<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<sheet name="Caravan">
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_DECLINE_QUEST1">
    <en>Ah... I understand, stranger. I presume too much of one who is not a flea.&lt;page&gt;I’ve heard the settlement below us is setting up a wishwall. Perhaps I’ll send Grishkin down to hang up our wish...&lt;page&gt;</en>
    <zh>唉……我明白。对外族提这种要求太过分了。&lt;page&gt;听说下面营地建了祈愿墙，我让格里什琴去挂上我们的愿望吧……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_HUNTER_EMPTY">
    <en>Bug not flea, my learnings, all have been scratched to your maps. Can give no more.&lt;page&gt;Leave now! Seek and save lost fleas, for a caravan full and whole!</en>
    <zh>外族虫，位置都标在你图上了。没其他的了。&lt;page&gt;快去吧！找到那些迷途跳蚤，凑满旅团！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_INFO_HUNTER">
    <en>Have you met her yet? Our burly new companion, Vog! Fresh returned from a long time spent tracking.&lt;hpage&gt;We have met, Fleamaster. It gladdens me that so strong a flea exists as her.&lt;hpage&gt;Yours was a caravan sorely lacking for protection, and I am too bound by my own tasks to provide it for you.&lt;page&gt;Why, we would never impose so! And now, no matter! Her scent may be strong, and her taste for brew bottomless, but her skill is sharp.&lt;page&gt;If predators draw close, her talents will provide much confidence to our caravan.</en>
    <zh>见过我们的新成员沃葛了吗？她的追踪术很是了得！&lt;hpage&gt;见过了。有这般强力的跳蚤存在，我也轻松一些。&lt;hpage&gt;毕竟你们旅团缺少护卫，而我又有要务在身。&lt;page&gt;怎么敢劳烦您！放心吧，虽然沃葛经常臭烘烘的，又嗜酒，但本事过硬。&lt;page&gt;如果有掠食者靠近，她的本领能安大伙的心。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_HUNTER_MEET_NOMAP_ACT3">
    <en>You remain, bug not flea? Would you seek service of me, ehh? Mine is knowledge much, the places of the lost little ones, heard and smelt across the caves.&lt;page&gt;You could help find! And bring! For all to come together now that times turn dark...&lt;page&gt;But no map you hold! If learnings are wanted, a map must be owned. Until then, we have no trade to make.</en>
    <zh>你还在啊，外族虫？要我帮忙吗？我知道那些迷途小辈的踪迹，各处洞穴都有。&lt;page&gt;你来寻找！把它们带来！最好齐聚于此，全体跳蚤……趁黑暗未临......&lt;page&gt;但你没有地图！想要情报，先准备地图。在此之前无可奉告。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_MEMBER_SHORT_REPEAT_FLEATOPIA_ACT3">
    <en>Our travels have end, and now soon the world will also have end! At such bitter of times, brew with friends is most sweet.</en>
    <zh>旅途结束，世界也要完蛋了！这种苦涩的时候，跟朋友一起喝药酿最甜。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CARAVAN_LECH_INTRO">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;Greetings again, sir flea. I see you were able to unite safely with this caravan.&lt;page&gt;Oh yes! All thanks to you! Dear, sweet you! Heh heh!&lt;page&gt;The Fleamaster, that old bore, tells me to call you Miss Hornet. But such a prickly name ill befits such a delicate beauty! Shall I call you something prettier, like ‘Nectarsweet’, my dear?&lt;hpage&gt;You shall not. Address me by my name or not at all.&lt;page&gt;Gradak! Of course. Of course! Heh heh. And now, I shall let you in on my little secret. My carriage doubles as a soothing spa, you see. It’s most ingenious.&lt;page&gt;The water inside is piping hot, and purer than a psalm! Heh heh! I’d gladly let you soak inside, for a modest fee!</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;又见面了，跳蚤先生。看来你顺利加入旅团了。&lt;page&gt;是啊！全托你的福！亲爱的小甜心！嘿嘿！&lt;page&gt;跳蚤首领那老古板让我称呼你为大黄蜂小姐。但这带刺的名字配不上娇花！叫你"蜜糖甜心"如何？&lt;hpage&gt;当然不行。要么称呼我的本名，要么闭嘴。&lt;page&gt;咳！是是是！嘿嘿，透露个小秘密——其实我的车厢兼作温泉疗愈所！&lt;page&gt;水温滚烫，而且比圣诗还纯净！付点小钱就能泡个痛快！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FG_BOUNCE_INTRO_FIRST">
    <en>Dear one, how shameful for the world to end while poor Kratt still has so much living left in him!&lt;page&gt;But how sweet of you to join me here! Will you play the Flea Bounce game, that I may appreciate the beauty of your agile form while I await my doom?&lt;page&gt;To play is simple. Leap up and keep bouncing on the fleas who fly past for as long as you are able!</en>
    <zh>亲爱的，可惜末日来得太早，可怜的克拉特还没活够呢！&lt;page&gt;但有甜心你在就好！要玩这跳蚤蹦蹦的游戏吗？我想欣赏你美丽灵巧的身姿呢！&lt;page&gt;规则很简单，跳起来踩飞过的跳蚤，持续越久越好！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_MEMBER_TALL_REPEAT_GREYMOOR">
    <en>Strange beasts prowl these grey lands. I hear them roar and shriek outside camp. Is best to stay inside and make quiet.</en>
    <zh>这片灰地时常能听见怪物吼叫，最好待在营地里别出声。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FG_DODGE_CHOICE">
    <en>Compete in Flea Dodge?</en>
    <zh>游玩跳蚤溜溜？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_MEMBER_SHORT_MEET_FLEATOPIA">
    <en>At longest last, have our flea roamings ended! Every sandy grain and stinky squelchy maggot was worth to endure, to claim such a home!&lt;page&gt;Is time for rest and celebrate, and none have earned such more than you, Miss Hornet! Raise your flask and drink most heartily with us!</en>
    <zh>终于不用流浪了！这一路上吃沙喝风忍蛆虫都值了！&lt;page&gt;是时候庆祝了！大黄蜂小姐，和我们一起举杯吧！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_GREYMOOR_REPEAT">
    <en>We will camp here in these grey lands until more fleas find their way to the caravan. Please lend your aid to any of our fellows you find lost out on the roads!</en>
    <zh>我们会在这灰地扎营，直到更多同胞归队。请继续帮助寻找迷途的跳蚤！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_ACCEPT_QUEST_OUTRO">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;I am travelling these lands for my own reasons, Fleamaster. However, if I happen upon any fleas on my travels, I will aid them as best I can.&lt;page&gt;Oh, oh, I could ask for nothing more! They must all be hiding or stuck in dangerous places, but if you rouse them they are sure to find their way here to us.&lt;page&gt;May the kingdom bless your travels and keep you safe, stranger! You are welcome to rest here with us whenever the roads bring you back!</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;我的旅途有自己的目的，但若路遇跳蚤，会尽力相助。&lt;page&gt;那就足够了！他们肯定是困在各处险地，只要脱困就会自己寻路归来。&lt;page&gt;愿王国庇佑您旅途平安！也随时欢迎您回来歇息！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_GREYMOOR_MEET_TRAVELED">
    <en>The journey here was long, but we didn’t lose a single flea! I’m told it’s good luck to bring a guest along when travelling, so we must have you to thank!&lt;page&gt;I trust the trip was agreeable for you. A pleasure perhaps? Nestled in with our dear little ones...&lt;hpage&gt;They certainly make for energetic travel companions. I’ve not often had opportunity to socialise with such spirited sorts.&lt;page&gt;Splendid! And now, you must go and see Grishkin, sitting there by the bubbling cauldron. After long travel, we drink to revive our spirits!</en>
    <zh>这趟旅途虽长，但没丢一只跳蚤！听说带贵客同行能带来好运，肯定是您的功劳！&lt;page&gt;旅途可还舒适？和小家伙们挤在一起挺开心吧？&lt;hpage&gt;他们确实精力旺盛，我很少和这么活泼的旅伴打交道。&lt;page&gt;那就好！现在去找格里什琴吧，她在冒泡的大锅旁。长途劳顿后该喝点提神！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_MEMBER_SHORT_BREW_FULL">
    <en>Miss Hornet, your bottle is full of Flea Brew. You know what such means! You must have drink! Har har!&lt;page&gt;When you have finish drinking, return and we will fill flask again! I’m is always brewing!</en>
    <zh>大黄蜂小姐，你身上的药酿还满着呢，得先喝光！&lt;page&gt;喝完了就回来找我！我这儿药酿管够！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_MEMBER_SHORT_REPEAT">
    <en>My fellows give much worry for the other fleas, but I’m not give at all. They will find their way to us, and if not, who keep count of them anyway? Har har!</en>
    <zh>大伙总爱担心那些迷途的同胞，我才不愁！该来的自会找来，没来谁又数得清？哈哈！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_JUDGE_REWARD">
    <en>Ahh, and before the road steals you away from us again, allow me to offer you a humble gift!&lt;page&gt;One of the little ones found a pale artefact while digging about in the sands. A spiny, cold sort of thing.&lt;page&gt;I see no use in it for we fleas, so of course we are all too pleased, eager even, to bestow it upon our dear friend!</en>
    <zh>趁您还没走，请收下这份薄礼！&lt;page&gt;有个小家伙在沙地里挖到件苍白古物，冷冰冰带尖刺。&lt;page&gt;对我们没用，正好赠予挚友！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_DELIVERY_FLEATOPIA_POST">
    <en>For your hard efforts and eternal friendship, please accept these meagre rosaries as reward.&lt;page&gt;Think of we fleas when you find chance to trade them!</en>
    <zh>为了酬谢您的辛劳，请收下这些念珠。&lt;page&gt;旅途上别忘了我们跳蚤，朋友！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CARAVAN_LECH_TALK_ACT3">
    <en>Dear one, my lone light amongst the darkness! Will you bathe in Kratt’s spa-carriage and let the warm waters wash away your worries?</en>
    <zh>亲爱的！黑暗中的明灯！可愿光临克拉特的温泉车厢，让暖流洗去烦忧？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CARAVAN_LECH_SPA_ACCEPT_2">
    <en>Please, my dear, step inside! I will stand guard here while you bathe... Right on this very spot!</en>
    <zh>亲爱的，请进吧！我就在这为你站岗……寸步不离！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_MEMBER_TALL_MEET_GREYMOOR">
    <en>Dodeshna. Want for shelter from the thick, grey air? Is heavy, and wet. I’m worry for the little flea’s health in this land.&lt;page&gt;And they make play in the filthy water. I say them stop, but they just laugh and splash on me. They are lack respect!&lt;hpage&gt;Most bugs instinctively obey those with strength and will. Speak with authority, or your commands may go unheeded.&lt;page&gt;Ugh... really, is Fleamaster’s job to teach the fleas such. I will just have rest here until is time to move on.</en>
    <zh>多德什纳。要来避一避吗？这的空气又闷又湿，小跳蚤们要生病了。&lt;page&gt;他们还玩脏水，说了也不听，反而溅我一身！没大没小！&lt;hpage&gt;虫类大多听从强者，你得用权威口吻。&lt;page&gt;唉……这本是首领该做的。我还是好好休息等旅团出发吧。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FG_DODGE_DECLINE">
    <en>Away then, bug. Await challenger, shall I.</en>
    <zh>那就走吧。我会等下一个挑战者。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FG_BOUNCE_COMPLETED">
    <en>Vikna! Our little game has ended. But I trust, after a short rest, you will play with us again?</en>
    <zh>维克纳！游戏结束。不过你应该还没尽全力吧，休息会儿再战？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FESTIVAL_BOARD_TITLE_JUGGLE">
    <en>Juggle</en>
    <zh>跳蚤耍耍</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_ACCEPT_QUEST1">
    <en>Ahh! Do I understand you rightly, stranger? You will help gather the lonely fleas to our caravan? Truly?</en>
    <zh>啊！我没听错吧？您愿意帮忙召集流落各处的跳蚤？当真？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_MEET_FLEATOPIA">
    <en>Miss Hornet! Our saviour! How dearly we had hoped you would visit.&lt;page&gt;And just look! This beautiful spot you’ve gifted us, safe apart from the dark and death of the lands beside. A place for fleas to grow smart and strong.&lt;page&gt;Here we shall see our travels end, for in Pharloom there could be no finer place to settle.&lt;hpage&gt;I am glad the location suits, Fleamaster. It is a calming thing to know these many fleas may survive. Most bugs of Pharloom seem destined for far bleaker fates.&lt;page&gt;Indeed! A hopeful future awaits! And only because of yourself and your efforts. To commemorate our arrival, it would be my pleasure to perform a small service for you.&lt;page&gt;
I have been learning to sew, and the little fleas have been gathering materials for me. I thought I could add an extra pocket to your tool pouch, to make your travels just a little easier.&lt;page&gt;
A trifling favour, much less than you deserve, but still I hope it meets to your satisfaction!</en>
    <zh>大黄蜂小姐！跳蚤的救星！我们等候您很久了！&lt;page&gt;看看这块宝地！远离外面的危险，跳蚤们肯定能在这茁壮成长！&lt;page&gt;这里就是我们旅团的终点站了，纺络再找不到比这更好的归宿了！&lt;hpage&gt;合你们的心意就好。能有这么多跳蚤幸存，我也感到高兴。其他虫类大多没那么幸运。&lt;page&gt;没错！未来充满希望，这全仰赖您的帮助。为纪念乔迁之喜，请收下这份纪念品。&lt;page&gt;我最近学了缝纫，小家伙们也帮我收集材料。想给你的工具袋加个口袋，让旅途轻松些。&lt;page&gt;区区薄礼不足挂齿，希望您别失望！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_GAMES_INTRO_REFUSE">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;I know not what you plan, Fleamaster, and at this time I cannot participate.&lt;page&gt;Ahhhh. Ahhhhhhh! Wretches, wretches, all of us! How can we begin without you, dear friend?</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;我不知您作何打算，跳蚤首领，但此刻我无法参与庆典。&lt;page&gt;啊啊啊！可惜啊，这太令我们难过了！没有您这位挚友，庆典如何开始？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FESTIVAL_OUTRO_SCENE">
    <en>Gathered here we are, to honour the grand champion of this very final of all festivals!&lt;page&gt;Now, Miss Hornet! Strike the great effigy with all your might!</en>
    <zh>我们相聚于此，为这末日庆典的总冠军加冕！&lt;page&gt;大黄蜂小姐，现在请全力击打巨像！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_MEMBER_SHORT_REPEAT_FLEATOPIA">
    <en>The little fleas like this place most of all. They are as much happy as I ever hear them!</en>
    <zh>小家伙们非常喜欢这地方！我从没听他们这么欢腾过！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_ALLRESCUED_INTRO_FULL_EARLY">
    <en>Oh, dear friend, Miss Hornet, look at our marvellous troupe! Their numbers full. Their spirits bright. All thanks to your heroic efforts!</en>
    <zh>大黄蜂小姐快看，我们壮盛的队伍！跳蚤们无一遗漏，个个精神饱满，全仰赖您的英勇相助！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FG_BOUNCE_CHOICE">
    <en>Compete in Flea Bounce?</en>
    <zh>游玩跳蚤蹦蹦？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_MEET_JUDGE_TRAVELED">
    <en>Another journey complete! And a new, high spot for our rest, upon the doorstep of that mighty Citadel, no less!&lt;hpage&gt;It is fortunate that all of your companions survived the trek, Fleamaster. The howling rise beside, and the tangled wood before it, have both claimed the lives of countless bugs.&lt;page&gt;Indeed! A perilous ascent! Maybe it was your company that brought us luck, Miss Hornet? It surely put us fleas at ease to have you and your weapon riding close.</en>
    <zh>又一趟旅程结束了！这次竟然停在了圣堡门廊这样的高处！&lt;hpage&gt;你们能平安抵达这里实属万幸。旁边的峭壁和前边的丛林都葬送过无数旅行者。&lt;page&gt;确实凶险！或许是您带来的好运？有您持械护卫，大伙安心不少。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_ALLRESCUED_INTRO_ALT">
    <en>Oh, and look, Miss Hornet, look at how many lost fleas have come! It seems even the last few stragglers are now with us.</en>
    <zh>噢对了，大黄蜂小姐快看！如此多的跳蚤同胞，连最后几个掉队的都回来了！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_MEET_1">
    <en>Ah! Aha! A native of these fiery lowlands approaches! Have no fear, my friend, we fleas are but humble travellers!&lt;hpage&gt;Well met, sir, though like you I am not of these lands. I am merely journeying through.&lt;page&gt;Oh. Oho! A kindred spirit! It’s good luck for wanderers to meet on an unfamiliar path.</en>
    <zh>啊哈！是这片灼热低地的原住民！别怕朋友，我们跳蚤都是卑微的旅者！&lt;hpage&gt;幸会，不过我和你一样只是途经此地。&lt;page&gt;噢！原来也是流浪旅者！听说路遇同道是好兆头呢！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CARAVAN_LECH_TALK">
    <en>Dodeshna, dear one, dodeshna! Heh heh! Have you returned to use Kratt’s luxurious spa-carriage? I’ve kept it roastily warm for you...</en>
    <zh>多德什纳亲爱的！要来泡克拉特的豪华车厢温泉吗？泉水一直为你温着呢！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FG_JUGGLE_COMPLETED_HIGHSCORE">
    <en>Vikna! The game is now ended, and the Flea Juggle champion has set an even higher score! Tremble in awe, dear fleas, at the might of our dear Miss Hornet!</en>
    <zh>维克纳！游戏结束，耍耍记录刷新！颤抖吧跳蚤们，见证大黄蜂小姐的实力！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_INCOMPLETE_QUEST1">
    <en>There are many lost and lonely fleas still scattered across this kingdom. If only some more of them joined us, the caravan could continue its journey.&lt;page&gt;You’ll find the little dears in all sorts of strange places, for they love to peek and pry and play, but if you rouse them they are sure to find their way here!</en>
    <zh>还有太多同胞流落四方。如果能多召集些，旅团就能继续前行。&lt;page&gt;那些小家伙总爱躲在古怪角落玩耍，但被发现就会自己寻路回来！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_MEMBER_TALL_FLEATOPIA_REPEAT_ACT3">
    <en>Those great rumbles from beneath, they have sound similar to giant beast. Such beast is much sorrowful though, I am think.&lt;page&gt;Fleas and monsters alike have their troubles...</en>
    <zh>下面传来的轰隆声，像巨兽哀嚎。或许长得越大，悲伤也就越大吧。&lt;page&gt;跳蚤和怪物各有各的苦……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="HORNET_FLEA_LAKE_FOUND">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;The Fleamaster and his caravan sought for caves offering space and safety. This calm lake and shore may prove suitable.</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;跳蚤旅团在寻找宽敞又安全的驻地，这片湖岸看着很合适。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_JUDGE_READYTOLEAVE">
    <en>Oh, Miss Hornet! Wonder at how large our caravan has grown! So bold and boisterous! This gilded chamber can barely contain us all!&lt;page&gt;The many fleas are itching to journey once more, to find a space to stretch their wings. But from here, as their leader, I am hesitant to order us so swiftly away.&lt;page&gt;These heights hold too much danger to set forth without a safe goal held clear in mind.&lt;page&gt;What of you, Miss Hornet? Your tasks carry you throughout this kingdom. Have you ever encountered a place appropriate?</en>
    <zh>大黄蜂小姐！看旅团现在多热闹！这金色大厅都快装不下了！&lt;page&gt;大伙急着再次启程找个宽敞的地方，但身为领袖，我不敢贸然行动。&lt;page&gt;高地危机四伏，没有明确目标不能冒险。&lt;page&gt;您有什么看法？您走遍了纺络，可曾遇见过合适的去处？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_REPEAT_GENERIC">
    <en>We will camp here a time before moving onward. These moments of safety and calm must be treasured, rare as they are.</en>
    <zh>我们会在这里暂驻。安宁时光难得，要好好珍惜。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_ALLRESCUED_INTRO">
    <en>Oh, my dear friend, Miss Hornet, look at how many of the lost fleas have come! It seems even the last few stragglers are now with us.</en>
    <zh>大黄蜂小姐快看！如此多的跳蚤同胞，连最后几个掉队的都回来了！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_MEET_2">
    <en>And now that we have met, know that I am Fleamaster Mooshka, leader of this caravan!&lt;page&gt;Our own journey has barely begun, but you are most welcome to tarry here a while, stranger. Where ways are dark and winding, good bugs must stay close together!</en>
    <zh>既然相遇，容我介绍——我是跳蚤首领穆什卡，旅团领袖！&lt;page&gt;我们刚启程不久，但欢迎您在此歇息。现在外面混乱得很，好虫子们应抱团取暖！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_MEMBER_SHORT_MEET_JUDGE">
    <en>The bellowing sandy land was full of much danger. We was almost lost poor Varga to hungry worms as we travel up!&lt;page&gt;Sadly, he is finding way here after all. Har! Is only jest. Grishkin and Varga is great friends, just like all fleas is being.</en>
    <zh>这片沙地凶险得很！来的路上瓦尔加差点就进了蠕虫的肚子！&lt;page&gt;可惜最后他找到路回来了！哈哈开玩笑，格里什琴和瓦尔加关系好着呢！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BREW_REFILL_PROMPT">
    <en>Refill Flea Brew?</en>
    <zh>装满跳蚤秘酿？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_HUNTER_ALL_FLEAS_FOUND">
    <en>You have brought them all, bug not flea. My work is done! No more searching needed. Ours is a caravan full!&lt;page&gt;Now my duty must change. To watch. To protect. This new task I am looking much to liking.</en>
    <zh>你把他们全找齐了，外族虫。我也不用再四处搜寻了！旅团满员！&lt;page&gt;现在改当护卫，这新差事合我胃口。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_MEMBER_TALL_RETURN">
    <en>Is warm here, you agree? Is very... what is say, cosy?&lt;page&gt;The Fleamaster though, is always want to move on. We will be drag away somewhere much worse soon, I think.</en>
    <zh>这儿暖和，对吧？很……温馨？&lt;page&gt;但首领总想挪窝，我猜迟早会搬去更糟的地方。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CARAVAN_LECH_SPA_DECLINE">
    <en>Oh... what a shame. Heh heh! I think you’d find the waters inside delectably soothing, if you’d only reconsider!</en>
    <zh>噢……真遗憾。这泉水能舒服到骨头里哦！要不再考虑考虑？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_DELIVERY_FLEATOPIA">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;Fleamaster, I bring a delivery, supplies from the couriers of Bellhart to aid your settlement.&lt;page&gt;Such dedication you continue to show us, Miss Hornet!&lt;page&gt;While we may seem safe out here at range from danger, we cannot go far to forage, and the many fleas need much nurture!&lt;page&gt;Food and provisions, such as you bring, are crucial in these desperate times.</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;我从钟心镇带了补给来。&lt;page&gt;大黄蜂小姐，您总是这么关照我们！&lt;page&gt;这里看似安全，但难以远行觅食，这么多张嘴要喂呢！&lt;page&gt;你带来的食物和物资真是雪中送炭！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FG_DODGE_INTRO_REPEAT">
    <en>This trial is Flea Dodge. Stay upon platforms, avoid attacks. Longer stay gives bigger score.</en>
    <zh>这试炼是跳蚤溜溜。站住平台，躲开攻击。坚持越久分越高。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_MEMBER_SHORT_MEET">
    <en>Dodeshna, dodeshna! I am saying, welcome to our caravan, stranger!&lt;page&gt;You are a very funny, very strange flea, isn’t it? No fur at all, and your wings fall off!&lt;page&gt;Har, har har har! Is just jest, of course. Us fleas famous for giving jokes!</en>
    <zh>多德什纳，多德什纳！我的意思是，欢迎来到旅团！&lt;page&gt;你真是个滑稽的跳蚤，没长毛还掉翅膀！哈哈！&lt;page&gt;开个玩笑啦！我们跳蚤最爱逗乐子！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_MEMBER_SHORT_RETURN">
    <en>Some beasts here, I see them eat through the bony ground. Is very smart! Bone is everywhere much abundant! If only I had such stomach, har har!</en>
    <zh>这有些野兽会啃地上的骨头，真聪明！这到处都是骨头，我要有这胃口多好！哈哈！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_MEMBER_SHORT_REPEAT_FESTIVAL">
    <en>Drink to full, Miss Hornet! Why waste? Be merry with us fleas before it all ends!</en>
    <zh>喝个痛快，大黄蜂小姐！浪费？都要完蛋了，只管开心就好了！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FG_DODGE_COMPLETED_HIGHSCORE">
    <en>Vikna. The trial has ended, and you have bested your old score. Rishkiz, champion!</en>
    <zh>维克纳，试炼结束。你超越了自己，里什基兹，祝贺你，冠军！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_OFFER_QUEST1_REPEAT">
    <en>Normally I would never burden a visitor with the caravan’s worries. But! Isn’t it the custom of this kingdom to share your deepest wishes with strangers?&lt;page&gt;Well, my wish is for the poor lost fleas of these lands to find their way to our caravan! Stranger, could you not help us?</en>
    <zh>本不该让客人操心旅团的琐事，但据说倾诉愿望是纺络的风俗？&lt;page&gt;我的愿望就是迷途跳蚤能回归旅团！能请您帮助我吗？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_JUDGE_CANLEAVE">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;Fleamaster, if your troupe is still prepared to travel, I have discovered a cave beyond the Citadel, at the edge of some ancient aqueducts. That place may well suit your needs for safety.&lt;hpage&gt;The trek would be long, but once reached, you will find a sandy shore, free of predators, beside a wide clear lake. It is as peaceful a place as I’ve seen throughout these fraught lands.&lt;page&gt;That’s it! It must be! Our destination has at last been set. Our journey can continue!&lt;page&gt;True friend of fleas you are, Miss Hornet. That place shall welcome us, no doubt. Will you be joining for this new journey?</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;要是旅团已经准备妥当，我发现圣堡外的古渠尽头有处洞穴或许适合你们。&lt;hpage&gt;路途虽远，但抵达后有沙滩湖泊，没有掠食者。是我在这里见过最安宁的地方。&lt;page&gt;就是那里了！终于找到目标了，旅团可以启程了！&lt;page&gt;真不愧是跳蚤挚友！那地方肯定很适合我们。愿意与我们一起同行吗？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CARAVAN_LECH_SPA_INTIMIDATED_ACT3">
    <en>My treasured guest... what need have I of rosaries, now that all is ending? Please, use my spa-carriage, free of charge! Dear Kratt is only too happy to provide!</en>
    <zh>尊贵的客人……如今万物都将终结，我还要念珠何用？请随意使用温泉车厢吧，分文不取！亲爱的克拉特乐意为您效劳！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_REPEAT_FLEATOPIA">
    <en>So many lost fleas have made it here... Truly, I’d never dared to hope we could gather such a grand company!&lt;page&gt;But still there may be more out there in this wide world... What a wonder it would be if they too found their way to our fresh paradise!</en>
    <zh>这么多迷途同胞都回来了……真是做梦都不敢想！&lt;page&gt;但或许还有其他流落者……要是他们也能找到这新乐园该多好！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CARAVAN_LECH_WOUNDED_TALK">
    <en>Auugghhh... the pain! Such fury, over a mistake! Poor little Kratt did not mean to steal a look!&lt;page&gt;This old carriage needs constant care. I was only doing repairs! I had no intent to intrude! And I barely saw a thing!&lt;hpage&gt;Lie no more to me, flea, and be grateful you still live. Know that if you peer again, you will die.&lt;page&gt;Of course! Kratt would never! Let’s consider the matter forgotten, and you shall forever be my treasured guest!</en>
    <zh>啊嗷！好痛！发这么大火干嘛！克拉特不是故意偷看的！&lt;page&gt;车厢需要养护，我只是在修补！这是无心之过，而且我基本什么也没看见！&lt;hpage&gt;不必编故事了，这次没死算你走运。下次再偷看，你必死无疑。&lt;page&gt;不敢不敢！这事就这么翻篇吧！您永远是贵宾！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_MEMBER_SHORT_MEET_BREW">
    <en>Dodeshna! Miss Hornet, is it? Welcome to our new camp! The travelling is done, and so we drink! &lt;page&gt;Is no better way to revive spirit than to drink the famous Flea Brew! I’m have just finished a batch, bubbling and warm!&lt;page&gt;You are friend, finder of lost, little fleas, hmm? Here, take bottle of Flea Brew with you! Will keep you warm while you travel.&lt;page&gt;I am always brewing here, so have no fear to drink plenty, and return whenever you are wanting more!</en>
    <zh>多德什纳！是大黄蜂小姐吗？欢迎来新营地！旅途结束，该喝点啦！&lt;page&gt;来点提神的跳蚤秘酿！我刚熬好一锅，热乎着呢！&lt;page&gt;是你帮忙找回流落在外的同胞对吧？那这瓶药酿送你！路上暖暖身子。&lt;page&gt;我整天都在熬制药酿，喝完了随时来取！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPLE_HUNTER_MEET_COMPLETE_ACT3">
    <en>You remain, bug not flea? If service is you here seeking, none is left for me to provide. All fleas are here, collected close.&lt;page&gt;Much better it is now for fleas to be together, ready to face whatever end will come.</en>
    <zh>你还在啊，外族虫？如果是要找我帮忙，那我帮不了什么了，跳蚤们都回来了。&lt;page&gt;现在大家都聚在一起，只剩等待最后的终局了。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_HUNTER_MEET_NOMAP">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;Fair greetings again, large flea. Of your many companions, I had little worry you would survive to find this caravan.&lt;hpage&gt;Would you tell me now of the task that saw you so apart from your fellows, and so fearsome in form?&lt;page&gt;Grrr....Mine is to track, by trail and smell and senses sharp. Find our friend fleas, our young most of most, to bring them together and grow them strong.&lt;hpage&gt;If you have sensed the locations of other lost fleas, would you share them with me? I may be able to send them safe to the caravan.&lt;page&gt;The locations! For price they could be shared, but you hold no map to mark! If learnings are wanted, a map must be owned. Until then, we have no trade to make.</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;又见面了，大个子。就知道你能活着找到这里。&lt;hpage&gt;能告诉我你为何离群索居，还练就这副体魄么？&lt;page&gt;吼……我负责追踪，靠着足迹气味，找回幼崽养壮族群。&lt;hpage&gt;若是探知迷途跳蚤下落，就告诉我，或许能送他们归队。&lt;page&gt;位置，拿念珠换！但你连地图都没有！想要交易，先弄张地图来！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FG_DODGE_INTRO_FIRST">
    <en>Bug. World is ending. Nothing left but to test ourselves.&lt;page&gt;This trial is Flea Dodge. Stay upon the platforms. Avoid attacks. Longer stay gives bigger score.&lt;page&gt;To score most is to become champion. This is only thing left to strive for.</en>
    <zh>虫子，世界就要毁灭，除了试炼也没别的事可做。&lt;page&gt;这试炼是跳蚤溜溜。站住平台，躲开攻击。坚持越久分越高。&lt;page&gt;分最高的就是冠军，而夺冠是最后的意义。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FG_DODGE_INTRO_CHAMP">
    <en>Bug, you are champion of Flea Dodge, but trial is still open to you. Can you defeat your own score?</en>
    <zh>虫子，跳蚤溜溜的冠军归你了。但挑战还将继续，你能突破自己的成绩吗？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_HUNTER_ACT3_MEET">
    <en>So bug not flea, you return. World is ruined. Final end comes soon, says Fleamaster.&lt;hpage&gt;This land is gravely wounded, but death need not follow. It is now my task to free this kingdom from its dark fall.&lt;page&gt;Grrr... such words are just fancy. Nothing left now, except to protect what little we have.</en>
    <zh>外族虫，你回来了。首领说，世界要完蛋了。&lt;hpage&gt;纺络遭受重创，但未必没有转机。我会帮王国摆脱黑暗。&lt;page&gt;吼……漂亮话谁都会说，现在我们也只能死守这点家当了。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FG_JUGGLE_INTRO_REPEAT">
    <en>Come, you revellers! Try the Flea Juggle game! Keep striking fleas upwards. Keep them airborne for as long as possible!</en>
    <zh>来啊狂欢者！玩跳蚤耍耍！把跳蚤打飞，滞空越久越好！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_JUDGE_CANLEAVE_FIRST">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;I have seen a place, Fleamaster, a cave beyond the Citadel, at the edge of some ancient ducts. That place may well suit your needs for safety.&lt;hpage&gt;The trek would be long, but once reached, you will find a sandy shore, free of predators, beside a wide clear lake. It is as peaceful a place as I’ve seen throughout these fraught lands.&lt;page&gt;That’s it! It must be! Our destination has been set. Our journey can continue!&lt;page&gt;True friend of fleas you are, Miss Hornet. That place shall welcome us, no doubt. Will you be joining the caravan on this journey?</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;我见过一处地方，在圣堡外的古渠尽头，或许符合你们的需求。&lt;hpage&gt;路途虽远，但抵达后有沙滩湖泊，没有掠食者。是我在这里见过最安宁的地方。&lt;page&gt;就是那里了！目标已定，旅团可以启程了！&lt;page&gt;真不愧是跳蚤挚友！那地方肯定很适合我们。愿意与我们一起同行吗？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_HUNTER_ALL_FLEAS_FOUND_ACT3">
    <en>All are here now, bug not flea. For your seeking, ours is a caravan full.&lt;page&gt;Much better it is now for fleas to be together, ready to face whatever end will come.</en>
    <zh>跳蚤全齐了，外族虫。托你的福，旅团满员了。&lt;page&gt;世界就要完蛋了，抱团总比落单好。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CARAVAN_LECH_SAVED">
    <en>Ooh, heh heh heh! What a turn, for dear Kratt to be strung up in such a dank little cave!&lt;hpage&gt;Cursed threads stretch throughout this land, set to ensnare the unwary. You seem no worse for it now, at least.&lt;hpage&gt;That metal carriage... It is yours, I assume?&lt;page&gt;Ooh, yes, yes! I’m setting out to join the nearest flea caravan, aren’t I? Safety in numbers, yes? I’ve had more than enough of venturing alone.&lt;page&gt;And you... I trust I will see you there? My carriage hides a special secret I’d gladly share with you when next we meet! Heh heh!</en>
    <zh>嘿嘿！没想到克拉特会在这阴暗的洞窟里翻船！&lt;hpage&gt;丝咒遍地，一不留神被缠住。你看起来倒是不担心？&lt;hpage&gt;那金属车厢……是你的吧？&lt;page&gt;对对！我正要投奔跳蚤旅团呢！独行太危险了！&lt;page&gt;你……也会去旅团吧？那我们旅团再见，车厢里有惊喜等着你哟！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_COMPLETE_WISHWALL_QUEST1_FULL">
    <en>And now, with our caravan bursting, we’ve rested here long enough. We fleas must head higher!&lt;page&gt;Oh, but stranger, how remiss of me! First, please, what shall we call you?&lt;hpage&gt;You may call me Hornet, Fleamaster. Know that I, like you, am glad to see your fellow fleas safe with your caravan. These are dangerous lands to travel alone.&lt;page&gt;Oh, vavenda! That is to say, incredible! What a beautiful thing it is! All of us together.&lt;page&gt;Dear friend... Miss Hornet. Our caravan prepares to depart toward the wide moor high above. Would you travel with us, as our honoured guest?</en>
    <zh>如今旅团拥挤不堪，我们也休整已久。跳蚤们必须向更高处进发！&lt;page&gt;哎呀，我真是失礼！还没请教您的姓名？&lt;hpage&gt;叫我大黄蜂即可。很高兴见你和同胞平安相聚，在这种地方独行确实太过凶险。&lt;page&gt;哈哈！能与同胞团聚，还结交了新朋友，真是太好了！&lt;page&gt;亲爱的朋友……大黄蜂小姐。旅团即将前往上方辽阔沼地，您愿意作为贵宾与我们同行吗？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_HUNTER_PURCHASED">
    <en>I have marked your map, bug. See the learnings of fleas lost across the lands.&lt;page&gt;If you are as brave as told by fellow fleas, seek them. Save them. For a caravan whole.</en>
    <zh>外族虫，地图标好了。上面有流落同胞的位置。&lt;page&gt;如果你真如传言般勇敢，就去救他们吧。凑满我们的旅团。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_REPEAT_FLEATOPIA_ALLRESCUED">
    <en>You are welcome here always, Miss Hornet, true friend of fleas!&lt;page&gt;Stay as long as you care. Rest and restore. We many fleas do so enjoy your company.</en>
    <zh>随时欢迎您回来，跳蚤的挚友！&lt;page&gt;想留多久都可以。好好休息，我们都喜欢与您相伴。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_JUDGE_READYTOLEAVE_NO_LAKE_REPEAT">
    <en>Dear friend of fleas, please! If ever you come upon a cave both wide and free, return with haste and tell us.&lt;page&gt;The fleas are oh so eager to journey, and I’m eager to see them to a destination safe!</en>
    <zh>跳蚤之友啊！如果发现宽敞安全的洞穴，请速来告知！&lt;page&gt;大伙迫不及待地要启程，我也盼着带他们去安全的归宿！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_ALLRESCUED_ACT3">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;That is well, Fleamaster. My travels through this land have been far and deep, and yet at almost every reach I met the friendly, inquisitive presence of your kind.&lt;hpage&gt;You fleas have an uncommon desire for adventure which I find admirable, even if it is seldom matched by capability.&lt;hpage&gt;Though I am long accustomed to travelling alone, following your journey, and sharing some part in its progress has been a warm thing.&lt;page&gt;And so happy have you made we fleas! Even as the darkness comes to claim us, we would be honoured to bestow one final gift, a treasure from fleakind’s glorious past.&lt;page&gt;May it mark you in Pharloom’s final moment as a friend to us all.</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;那就好，我走遍纺络，处处都能遇见你们好奇的同胞。&lt;hpage&gt;你们对冒险的热忱令我钦佩，虽然常常力有不逮。&lt;hpage&gt;我素来喜好独行，但与你们相遇确是暖心之事。见你们团聚也很是欣慰。&lt;page&gt;哈哈！我们跳蚤也欢喜得很！因此在这黑暗将至的时刻，请让我为您送上最后的赠礼，这是跳蚤一族昔日的珍宝。&lt;page&gt;愿它永远守护在您身边，铭记您为我族挚友。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_MEMBER_SHORT_REPEAT_JUDGE">
    <en>You are have luck, Miss Hornet, to lack the fur of we fleas. All the blowy sand of that place is getting very stuck inside!</en>
    <zh>你真幸运，大黄蜂小姐。不像我们长着毛，这破地方的沙子全钻进了毛里！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_MEMBER_TALL_REPEAT">
    <en>The beasts here are... much frightful, hm? Scary?&lt;page&gt;But if give them space, they leave alone. You respect beast, beast respect you.</en>
    <zh>这里的野兽……挺吓人？&lt;page&gt;保持距离就没事。你对它们敬而远之，它们也一样。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FG_DODGE_INTRO_GAMESCOMPLETE">
    <en>Grand Champion... bug called Hornet. Will you once again challenge the Flea Dodge trial?</en>
    <zh>名为大黄蜂的虫……总冠军。你要再次挑战跳蚤溜溜吗？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FG_BOUNCE_INTRO_GAMESCOMPLETE">
    <en>Fierce one, my dear Grand Champion! Will you dance and fly with us above the water?</en>
    <zh>小辣椒，亲爱的总冠军！和我们一起在水面上共舞吧！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_DELIVERY_FESTIVAL">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;Fleamaster, I bring a delivery, supplies from the couriers of Bellhart to aid your settlement.&lt;page&gt;Ahh, such a kindly gesture adds much warmth to our celebration!&lt;page&gt;These poor little fleas will never grow to roam the world as we have, so let us give them what happiness we can before the end.</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;跳蚤首领，我带来了钟心镇的支援物资。&lt;page&gt;啊，这份善意让庆典更添暖意！&lt;page&gt;这些可怜的小跳蚤注定无法像我们一样游历世界，就让我们在终结前尽力给予他们欢愉吧。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CARAVAN_LECH_INTRO_MARROW">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;Greetings again, sir flea. I see you were able to unite safely with this caravan.&lt;page&gt;Oh yes! Heh heh. All thanks to you! Dear, sweet you! Pray tell, what does one call such a delicate beauty? Surely yours is a name most sweet and soothing. Are you Fairgrace? Or Nectarsweet?&lt;hpage&gt;I am Hornet, sir. Address me by that name or not at all.&lt;page&gt;Gradak! Of course. Of course. My dear, Hornet! I shall let you in on my little secret. My carriage doubles as a soothing spa, you see. It’s most ingenious.&lt;page&gt;The water inside is piping hot, and purer than a psalm! Heh heh! I’d gladly let you soak inside, for a modest fee!</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;又见面了，跳蚤先生。看来你顺利加入旅团了。&lt;page&gt;是啊！嘿嘿，全托你的福！敢问美女芳名？定是甜美如"香露仙子"？&lt;hpage&gt;我名为大黄蜂，要么称我本名，要么闭嘴。&lt;page&gt;咳！是是是！亲爱的大黄蜂小姐！嘿嘿，透露个小秘密——其实我的车厢兼作温泉疗愈所！&lt;page&gt;水温滚烫，而且比圣诗还纯净！付点小钱就能泡个痛快！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FG_DODGE_ACCEPT">
    <en>Mamashka. The trial begins. Flea Dodge!</en>
    <zh>玛玛什卡。跳蚤溜溜，试炼开始！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_GAMES_INTRO_ALREADYACCEPTED">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;I saw your plea posted at Bellhart, sir flea, and accept your request.</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;我在钟心镇看到了你的祈愿，跳蚤先生，我接受。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_GAMES_INTRO_TALK_1">
    <en>The dirge I sing is for the end of our old lives...&lt;page&gt;Here at the end of times, our paradise crumbles beneath us. Flea and friend alike, all will soon be consumed...</en>
    <zh>我唱这首哀歌，祭奠旧日终结……&lt;page&gt;末日将至，乐园崩塌。跳蚤与挚友，终将湮灭……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_FOUND_FLEAS">
    <en>Ahh, look! The poor fleas are starting to make their way to us! What a precious thing!&lt;page&gt;We have much to thank you for already! And I hope we will have even more to be thankful for very soon! Please, keep seeking out our lost fellows!</en>
    <zh>快看！迷途的同胞开始回归了！多么珍贵的情谊！&lt;page&gt;我们对您感激不尽！还请您继续帮忙寻找失散的同胞！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_HUNTER_WILD_MEET_NOCARAVAN">
    <en>Grrr.. bug, not flea. Why you must bother me? This spot is mine, fair fought and earned.&lt;hpage&gt;I won’t stay long, madam. Nor would I contest your right to this cave. I only ask what task causes you to perch alone atop these dank ducts?&lt;page&gt;Task? Mine is a work most important, but not for talking of here, where danger waits close. Soon, I depart to seek fleas, my fellows, and join them.&lt;page&gt;Now... Grrr. You leave me! I go soon to seek other fleas. A flea alone is good, but fleas together is best! Till then, rest I need! Off, bug!</en>
    <zh>吼……外族虫，干嘛烦我？这地盘是我打下来的！&lt;hpage&gt;我无意久留，跳蚤，也不打算抢你山洞。就是好奇你独自在这做什么？&lt;hpage&gt;做什么？当然是重要的事，但没空多说，附近有危险。我马上就要离开，去找我的同胞。&lt;page&gt;唔……你走吧！跳蚤还是聚在一起更合适，我待会就去找他们！现在要先休息！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_GAMES_INTRO_REOFFER">
    <en>Dear friend... Miss Hornet! Forgive us, but we beg one more favour from you. Will you accompany us in our final act...?</en>
    <zh>亲爱的朋友……大黄蜂女士！请原谅，但我们恳求您最后再帮一次忙。您可愿陪我们完成旅途的终幕……？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_GAMES_INTRO_ACCEPT_2">
    <en>It is time for the Festival of the Flea! One last, grand celebration before the black quakes pull us all down into the darkness!&lt;page&gt;Rouse yourself fleas, one last time! Let the games begin!</en>
    <zh>跳蚤庆典就要开始了！在黑暗将我们拖入深渊前，最后一场盛大狂欢！&lt;page&gt;跳蚤们，最后一次振作起来！游戏开始！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_JUDGE_LEAVE">
    <en>Ahhh! Alas. Then we shall pray your own path remains safe.&lt;page&gt;And now, our new home is calling. We venture again!&lt;hpage&gt;Good travels, Fleamaster. May your journey ahead be safe and smooth.</en>
    <zh>啊哈哈，唉，那就祝您前路平安。&lt;page&gt;好了，新家在召唤，我们又要启程了！&lt;hpage&gt;一路顺风，跳蚤首领。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_COMPLETE_QUEST_SKIP_FULL">
    <en>But stranger! While you’re with us, you must hear of the miracle that has occurred!&lt;page&gt;See all these fleas gathered to our troupe? It seems so many! An impossible number, yet here they are, safely joined together. Our most cherished wishes answered!&lt;hpage&gt;If you were seeking fleas to join your caravan, I have found and freed many throughout my travels.&lt;page&gt;Oh! Can it be? Then you here are our saviour, our dear fleafriend! For all have made their way right, straight to us!&lt;page&gt;And now, with our caravan full to bursting, we’ve rested long enough. We fleas must head higher!&lt;page&gt;Oh, but saviour, how remiss of me! First, please tell, what shall we call you?&lt;hpage&gt;You may call me Hornet, Fleamaster. Know that I, like you, am glad to see your fellow fleas safe with your caravan. These are dangerous lands to travel alone.&lt;page&gt;Oh, vavenda! That is to say, incredible! What a beautiful thing it is! All of us together.&lt;page&gt;Dear friend... Miss Hornet. Our caravan prepares to depart toward the wide moor high above. Would you travel with us, as our honoured guest?</en>
    <zh>这位朋友！既然与我们同行，您可要听听旅团发生的奇迹！&lt;page&gt;看见归队的跳蚤们了吗？数量超乎想象！原以为这不可能，但它们已然齐聚于此。我们的祈愿实现了！&lt;hpage&gt;如果你是在寻找跳蚤，我在旅途中解救了许多。&lt;page&gt;噢！难道是您？那您便是我们的救星了，亲爱的跳蚤挚友！所有伙伴都因您重聚于此！&lt;page&gt;如今商队拥挤不堪，休整也已足够久。跳蚤们必须向更高处进发！&lt;page&gt;噢，救星阁下，原谅我失礼了！请问该如何称呼您？&lt;hpage&gt;叫我大黄蜂即可。很高兴你能和同胞平安相聚，在这种地方独行确实太过凶险。&lt;page&gt;哈哈！能与同胞团聚，还结交了新朋友，真是太好了！&lt;page&gt;亲爱的朋友……大黄蜂小姐。旅团即将前往上方辽阔沼地，您愿意作为贵宾与我们同行吗？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CARAVAN_LECH_SPA_INTIMIDATED">
    <en>Welcome back, my fierce one. Dodeshna! Heh heh! I’m sure your travels have wearied you.&lt;page&gt;Oh no, I wouldn’t dare take rosaries from such a treasured guest! Please, use my spa-carriage, free of charge! Dear Kratt is only too happy to provide!</en>
    <zh>欢迎回来小辣椒！嘿嘿，旅途累了吧？&lt;page&gt;哦不，我哪敢收您钱！随便泡！克拉特乐意为您效劳！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FESTIVAL_OUTRO_PRE">
    <en>Miss Hornet! You have proven yourself the champion at each of our flea games!&lt;page&gt;I am confident now that the grand champion of our festival has emerged. It is none other than yourself, of course!&lt;page&gt;And thusly, must our final ceremony begin. Fleas, prepare yourselves!</en>
    <zh>大黄蜂小姐，您包揽了所有跳蚤游戏的冠军！&lt;page&gt;我宣布，您是当之无愧的庆典总冠军！&lt;page&gt;最终仪式现在开始！跳蚤们，做好准备！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_MEMBER_SHORT_MEET_FESTIVAL">
    <en>Good friend of fleas is you, Miss Hornet. Now must join and drink much. Be merry before all ends. Brew is made, enough for all!&lt;page&gt;No charge for you if needing more. Why waste when future is final?</en>
    <zh>大黄蜂小姐，我们跳蚤的挚友，快来喝！末日临头该及时行乐！药酿管够！&lt;page&gt;尽管喝吧！都要完蛋了还留着干嘛？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_INFO_LECH">
    <en>A strange flea has joined our troupe. All are welcome, but something about this one sets my fur to raise.&lt;page&gt;His carriage offers a steaming service, but the charge in rosaries is stiff, especially for us fleas who carry few.&lt;page&gt;For the companionship we provide, and the safety of our numbers, surely some discount is deserved?</en>
    <zh>有个怪跳蚤入伙了。虽然我们来者不拒，但这家伙让我寒毛直竖。&lt;page&gt;他提供蒸疗服务，但要价高昂，我们跳蚤哪有这么多念珠？&lt;page&gt;看在我们提供庇护的份上，总该打个折吧？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FG_BOUNCE_COMPLETED_HIGHSCORE">
    <en>Vikna! Dear one, you outdo yourself! To beat your previous high score is a marvel indeed!</en>
    <zh>维克纳！亲爱的，你又破了自己的记录！太神奇了！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_HUNTER_WILD_REPEAT">
    <en>You still here, bug not flea? Is rest I need before I leave for caravan. Not chat. You feel trouble-type. Make my shell tense.&lt;hpage&gt;I shall take my leave, madam. Stay strong on your own journey. May we meet again at the caravan, amongst your fellows.</en>
    <zh>你怎么还在？我休息够了就去找旅团。别啰嗦，感觉你身上麻烦事不少，让我甲壳发紧。&lt;hpage&gt;那就告辞了，女士。祝你路上顺利，我们旅团再见。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FG_JUGGLE_DECLINE">
    <en>Ah, of course. Perhaps you will be trying one of the other games?</en>
    <zh>啊，好的，想玩其他游戏吗？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_HUNTER_REPEAT_NOMAP">
    <en>Grrr... bug not flea. Still wishing for knowings of my work? But you hold no map to mark! Until a map is owned, we have no trade to make.</en>
    <zh>吼……外族虫，还惦记我的情报？但你连地图都没有！先弄到地图再来。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CARAVAN_LECH_SPA_ACCEPT">
    <en>Thank you. Thank you! I’ll treasure these sweet-smelling rosaries dearly! Now, don’t be shy. Step inside!</en>
    <zh>多谢惠顾！这些香香的念珠我会珍藏的！别害羞，快请进！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FG_BOUNCE_COMPLETED_CHAMP">
    <en>Vikna! My dear one, my dancer, the game has ended and you have proven yourself the champion!&lt;page&gt;None can best your score. You have shamed us all with your fearsome grace! But you will keep playing for me, yes?&lt;page&gt;The end of the world need not be a lonely thing... eheh heh...</en>
    <zh>维克纳！游戏结束，我的亲爱的舞王！你已加冕冠军！&lt;page&gt;无法超越的优雅身姿！但你还会继续玩吧？&lt;page&gt;末日狂欢可不该独自度过，嘿嘿……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_QUEST1_TRAVEL_ACCEPT">
    <en>Excellent, excellent! Let us make preparations and be off without delay! Rouse yourself fleas, for the caravan roams once more!</en>
    <zh>太好了！即刻整装出发！跳蚤们动起来，旅团要再度启程啦！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FG_BOUNCE_INTRO_REPEAT">
    <en>My dear, will you play Flea Bounce for me once more? Leap up and bounce on the fleas who fly past for as long as you are able!</en>
    <zh>亲爱的，再玩一次蹦蹦游戏嘛！只需跳起来踩飞过的跳蚤，持续越久越好！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_MEMBER_SHORT_SETH">
    <en>Say you dodeshna to the new flea sitting there? Is quiet one, but is very good at games!&lt;page&gt;Have no worry for him, Grishkin will look after. Will fill him with brew and meet him to all the other fleas.</en>
    <zh>看见新来的安静跳蚤没？他玩游戏可厉害了！&lt;page&gt;别担心，格里什琴会照顾他的。先灌他药酿再介绍给大家！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_REPEAT_JUDGE">
    <en>Here we shall remain, for a time, Miss Hornet, and pray that more lost fleas find their way to us.&lt;hpage&gt;What others I encounter, I shall send your way, Fleamaster.</en>
    <zh>我们会暂驻此地，祈祷更多迷途同胞能够找来。&lt;hpage&gt;如果在路上遇到跳蚤，我会让他们来找你。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FESTIVAL_POT_TAKE_BREW">
    <en>Take Flea Brew?</en>
    <zh>拿取跳蚤秘酿？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FESTIVAL_BOARD_TITLE_BOUNCE">
    <en>Bounce</en>
    <zh>跳蚤蹦蹦</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_ALLRESCUED">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;That is well, Fleamaster. My travels through this land have been far and deep, and yet at almost every reach I met the friendly, inquisitive presence of your kind.&lt;hpage&gt;You fleas have an uncommon desire for adventure, which I find admirable, even if it is seldom matched by capability.&lt;hpage&gt;Though I am long accustomed to travelling alone, following your journey, and sharing some part in its progress has been a warm thing.&lt;page&gt;Ahh, and so happy too have you made we fleas!&lt;page&gt;I would be honoured to bestow one final gift unto you, Miss Hornet, a treasure from fleakind’s glorious past. May it mark you forever as a friend to us all.</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;那就好，我走遍纺络，处处都能遇见你们好奇的同胞。&lt;hpage&gt;你们对冒险的热忱令我钦佩，虽然常常力有不逮。&lt;hpage&gt;我向来独来独往，但与你们相遇也令我感到暖心。&lt;page&gt;哈哈！我们跳蚤也高兴得很！&lt;page&gt;请允许我献上最后的赠礼，这是跳蚤一族昔日的珍宝。愿它永远守护在您身边，铭记您为我族挚友。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CARAVAN_LECH_SPA_ACCEPT_INTIMIDATED">
    <en>The spa is yours, dear guest! And always open for one so considerate and kindly as yourself... eheh heh...</en>
    <zh>请享受温泉吧，亲爱的顾客！这里随时向您这样贴心又善良的客人开放，嘿嘿嘿……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CARAVAN_LECH_SAVED_REPEAT">
    <en>With luck, my dear, we will meet again when I have joined the flea caravan.&lt;page&gt;My carriage hides a special secret I’d gladly to share with you when next we meet!</en>
    <zh>运气好的话，我们在旅团再见。&lt;page&gt;我的车厢里给你留了一份惊喜呢，下次见面再为你揭晓！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_GAMES_INTRO_ACCEPT_1">
    <en>The pact is made then. Fellows! Steel yourself! It is time, it is time!</en>
    <zh>那么契约达成！伙计们！打起精神！时候到了，时候到了！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_MEMBER_TALL_FLEATOPIA_REPEAT">
    <en>This long lake... Space is much more big here. Finally I have some quiet from the little fleas.</en>
    <zh>这片湖……真宽敞。终于能躲开小跳蚤们清净会儿了。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_QUEST1_TRAVEL_DECLINE">
    <en>Ahh, that is a shame, but I understand. I’m sure our roads will cross each other soon enough.&lt;page&gt;And now, we must be off! Rouse yourself, fleas. The caravan roams once more!</en>
    <zh>唉，虽然遗憾，但能理解。相信我们很快会重逢的。&lt;page&gt;现在，我们该出发了！跳蚤们动起来，旅团要再度启程啦！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FG_JUGGLE_INTRO_GAMESCOMPLETE">
    <en>The grand ceremony has ended, but still we play! Will you honour us with a display of Flea Juggle, Miss Grand Champion Hornet?</en>
    <zh>庆典虽已落幕，但游戏不止！冠军大人愿意赏脸继续玩跳蚤耍耍吗？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_GREYMOOR_TRAVEL">
    <en>Wonderful! Wonderful! The fleas will be overjoyed to share this next journey with our favoured companion! Let us away!</en>
    <zh>太好了！跳蚤们肯定会因为有贵客同行而欢欣雀跃！我们这就出发！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FG_BOUNCE_ACCEPT">
    <en>Mamashka! Let our beautiful game begin! Flea Bounce!</en>
    <zh>玛玛什卡！蹦蹦游戏开始！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_JUDGE_READYTOLEAVE_NO_LAKE">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;Unfortunately not, Fleamaster. I have visited many of this kingdom’s caves, and none would offer the safety and space you require.&lt;hpage&gt;If ever I come upon such a place, I will let you know.</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;很遗憾，并没有。我去过的洞窟都不符合你们的需求。&lt;hpage&gt;但若将来遇到，肯定前来告诉你们。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FESTIVAL_BOARD_SPIRIT_NAME">
    <en>Flealia</en>
    <zh>芙罗拉</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FG_JUGGLE_INTRO_FIRST">
    <en>How do you like our festival, Miss Hornet? While the world crumbles around us, we will laugh and dance and frolick!&lt;page&gt;Make merry with us, and play some of the games of old!&lt;hpage&gt;My time is slim, Fleamaster. If I am to join your games, know it will be only to hone my skills for the greater trial I must soon face below.&lt;page&gt;Of course! Of course! Joy or learnings! Any reason is fine by us, Miss Hornet!&lt;page&gt;And look here, we have Flea Juggle, where the challenge is to strike fleas upwards and keep them airborne for as long as possible.&lt;page&gt;To have our treasured guest challenge this humble game would be an honour for us, truly!</en>
    <zh>大黄蜂小姐觉得我们的庆典如何？就算外面世界崩塌，我们照样欢欣起舞！&lt;page&gt;开心点，来陪我们玩玩老游戏吧！&lt;hpage&gt;我时间紧迫。参加游戏只是为了磨练技艺，应对接下来的恶战。&lt;page&gt;都行都行！不管是玩乐或修行都可以！&lt;page&gt;看这里，这是跳蚤耍耍——把跳蚤打上天，滞空越久越好！&lt;page&gt;贵客肯赏脸挑战，我们荣幸之至！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CARAVAN_LECH_WOUNDED_REPEAT">
    <en>A mistake, treasured guest! Never again! Ohhh. Never again!</en>
    <zh>一场误会啊贵客！绝不再犯！我保证！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_HUNTER_MEET">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;Fair greetings again, large flea. Amongst all of your troupe, I had little doubt you would survive to reach this caravan.&lt;hpage&gt;Would you tell me now of the task that saw you so apart from your fellows, and so fearsome in form?&lt;page&gt;Grrr....Bug not flea! Mine is to track, by trail and smell and senses sharp. Find our friend fleas, our young most of most, to bring them together and grow them strong.&lt;hpage&gt;If you have sensed the locations of other lost fleas, share them with me. I may be able to send them safe to the caravan.&lt;page&gt;My learnings? Not free for you, bug not flea. Rosaries! Give those and I shall say of what I have sensed. Work like mine... much long, and hard. For that, I deserve some riches held.</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;又见面了，大个子。你能平安到达这里倒是不令我意外。&lt;hpage&gt;能告诉我你为何离群索居，还练就这副体魄么？&lt;page&gt;吼……我负责追踪，靠着足迹气味，找回幼崽养壮族群。&lt;hpage&gt;若是探知迷途跳蚤下落，就告诉我，或许能送他们归队。&lt;page&gt;我的发现？外族虫，不白给，拿念珠来！我这行当又苦又累，理应拿点报酬。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_REPEAT_FLEATOPIA_ACT3">
    <en>So many lost fleas have made it here... Truly, I’d never dared to hope we could gather such a grand company.&lt;page&gt;But, oh! The world has grown so dangerous, and there may be more lost fleas out there. I do so hope they can find their way to us!</en>
    <zh>这么多迷途同胞都回来了……真是做梦都不敢想！&lt;page&gt;如今外面更凶险了，可能还有其他流落的同胞。真希望他们能找到我们！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_REPEAT_FLEATOPIA_ALLRESCUED_ACT3">
    <en>We fleas are all gathered, but now the world has loudly marked its ending! As great as our numbers grew, it seems our caravan will be the last.&lt;page&gt;There is only one thing left to do... but the preparations require time. If your travels wind their way back to us, dear friend, you yourself are welcome to participate...</en>
    <zh>跳蚤们虽已团聚，但世界即将毁灭！恐怕我们是最后的旅团了…….&lt;page&gt;只剩最后一事可做……但需时间准备。亲爱的朋友，如果再来，欢迎参与……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_FLEATOPIA_HUNTER_HINT">
    <en>Miss Hornet, I must tell, we’ve seen evidence nearby of a hunter of our tribe, a flea that seeks fleas!&lt;page&gt;As pungent and gruff as their sort often are, they’re still useful to have around a caravan.&lt;page&gt;A flea of their rare skill, settled among us, could offer defence and more.&lt;page&gt;If you’re still to be helping grow our town, search them out, up atop the muck choked ducts.</en>
    <zh>大黄蜂小姐！附近有我们族群的猎手出没的迹象，那是位专逮跳蚤的跳蚤！&lt;page&gt;虽然那家伙臭烘烘的又粗鲁，但对旅团很有用。&lt;page&gt;这样的好手要是能入伙，既能当护卫又有大用。&lt;page&gt;如果您还愿意帮忙壮大我们的旅团，就去腐殖渠上面找找吧！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FESTIVAL_POT_INSPECT">
    <en>A cauldron full of Flea Brew.</en>
    <zh>一大锅跳蚤秘酿。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPLE_HUNTER_MEET_COMPLETE">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;Fair greetings again, large flea. Of your many companions, I had little worry you would survive safe to find this caravan.&lt;hpage&gt;Would you tell me now of the task that saw you so apart from your fellows, and so fearsome in form?&lt;page&gt;Grrr....Mine was to track, by trail and smell and senses sharp. Find our friend fleas, our young most of most, to bring them together so strong they could grow.&lt;page&gt;A task once important, mine! But not now. All fleas are here, safe. A rare many! Time for toasts, and brew to fill our bellies!</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;又见面了，大个子。就知道你能活着找到这里。&lt;hpage&gt;能告诉我你为何离群索居，还练就这副体魄么？&lt;page&gt;吼……我以前负责追踪，靠着足迹气味，找回幼崽养壮族群。&lt;page&gt;这差事曾经很重要，但不需要了！现在大伙都齐了！该喝酒庆祝！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_GREYMOOR_CANLEAVE">
    <en>Look here! All these lively fleas flocked to our caravan. Thanks to you and your hunting, our numbers grow grand. Mayhap, in time, we could grow to match even those caravans of our fabled past?&lt;hpage&gt;To see so many safe is a welcome sight, Fleamaster. Their playful cheer suggests you are a fine steward for the swelling troupe.&lt;page&gt;Such kind words, Miss Hornet! How lucky we are to have found a friend so fair!&lt;page&gt;But now, we must away! These moors have been our host long enough. It is time to climb and hoist towards drier caves!&lt;page&gt;Good friend to fleas, would you join us on this next journey? </en>
    <zh>看！这么多活蹦乱跳的同胞加入！多亏您帮忙，队伍越来越壮大。或许能重现当年先祖们的盛况？&lt;hpage&gt;看见这么多跳蚤平安无事，我也很欣慰。他们的欢声笑语也证明了你是个称职的领队。&lt;page&gt;大黄蜂小姐过奖了！能结交您这样的朋友才是旅团的幸运！&lt;page&gt;但现在该启程了！沼地虽好，但不应久留，该向更干燥的洞窟进发了！&lt;page&gt;跳蚤之友，愿意与我们一起出发吗？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FG_DODGE_COMPLETED_CHAMP">
    <en>Vikna. The trial has ended.&lt;page&gt;Bug not flea... impressive was your performance. Your score exceeds even my own.&lt;page&gt;To see skill so much, moments before everything ends, gives me unexpected joy.&lt;page&gt;Rishkiz... I congratulate you, champion.</en>
    <zh>维克纳，试炼结束。&lt;page&gt;虫子，你超越了我，没想到外族也有这种身手。&lt;page&gt;末日临近还能见识这般技艺，着实是意料之外的惊喜。&lt;page&gt;里什基兹……祝贺你，冠军。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FESTIVAL_BOARD_TITLE_DODGE">
    <en>Dodge</en>
    <zh>跳蚤溜溜</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_GREYMOOR_MEET">
    <en>Ahh, Miss Hornet! Greetings, and well met, once again!&lt;page&gt;The journey here was long, but we didn’t lose a single flea! And now fate has brought us back together again... what a marvel!&lt;hpage&gt;It is good to see you safe, Fleamaster. The journey to this moor from the caverns below is long and dangerous.&lt;page&gt;Dangerous, certainly, but we fleas are born to roam!&lt;page&gt;And now, you must go and see Grishkin, sitting there by the bubbling cauldron. After long travel, we drink to revive our spirits!</en>
    <zh>啊！大黄蜂小姐！又见面真是太好了！&lt;page&gt;长途跋涉到这但没丢一只跳蚤！命运也让我们重逢……真是奇迹！&lt;hpage&gt;旅团平安就好，从下方洞窟到这沼地，路上肯定充满危险。&lt;page&gt;确实有不少危险，但跳蚤天生爱流浪！&lt;page&gt;现在，您去找格里什琴吧，她在冒泡的大锅旁。长途劳顿后该喝点提神！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_HUNTER_WILD_MEET">
    <en>Grrr.. bug not flea. Why you must bother me? This spot is mine, fair fought and earned.&lt;hpage&gt;I won’t stay long, madam. Nor would I contest your right to this cave.&lt;hpage&gt;I have encountered several of your fellow fleas, united in a caravan. Perhaps you would consider joining with them?&lt;hpage&gt;Yours seems a hardy hide, and I fear alone they lack the strength to survive long in this land.&lt;page&gt;Caravan? Grrr. Felt it in my fur... Time for change. If caravan is close, then my task, these lands, may near be complete.&lt;page&gt;Now... Grrr. Much talk I gave. You leave me! Meet again at caravan, amongst good fellows. There I share my learnings of fleas and Pharloom. Till then, rest I need! Off, bug!</en>
    <zh>吼……外族虫，干嘛烦我？这地盘是我打下来的！&lt;hpage&gt;我无意久留，跳蚤。也不打算抢你山洞。&lt;hpage&gt;我在一个旅团见过你的同胞。为何不加入他们？&lt;hpage&gt;你看着有些本事，他们也缺少护卫。&lt;page&gt;旅团？吼……感觉到了……是时候了。旅团出发，我在这的活也要结束了。&lt;page&gt;唔……不废话了。你走吧！在旅团再见，到时告诉你跳蚤位置的情报。现在我要休息！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_GAMES_INTRO_TALK_2">
    <en>Ohhhh! What other choice do we poor wretches have?! Cruel fate leaves us with only one last task...&lt;page&gt;Dear friend... Miss Hornet! Forgive us, but we beg one more favour from you. Will you accompany us in our final act...?</en>
    <zh>唉！我们这些可怜虫别无选择！残酷的命运只留下这一最后任务……&lt;page&gt;亲爱的朋友……大黄蜂女士！请原谅，但我们恳求您最后再帮一次忙。您可愿陪我们完成旅途的终幕……？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FG_JUGGLE_COMPLETED_CHAMP">
    <en>Vikna! The game is ended, and we have a new Flea Juggle champion! Incredible!&lt;page&gt;Miss Hornet, with your skill, I’m certain you could best all three of our games and become the grandest champion of them all!</en>
    <zh>维克纳！游戏结束！新的耍耍冠军诞生了！太强了！&lt;page&gt;以大黄蜂小姐的本事绝对能包揽我们三种游戏的冠军！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CARAVAN_LECH_SAVED_ACT3">
    <en>My, what a sweet face now emerges from the darkness! Poor Kratt has been hiding here from those blackened beasts for too long, all alone!&lt;hpage&gt;The beasts and bugs ensnared by the black thread are dangerous indeed. You have done right to hide yourself from them, sir.&lt;hpage&gt;That metal carriage... It is yours, I assume?&lt;page&gt;Ooh, yes, yes! I’m setting out to join the nearest flea caravan, aren’t I? Safety in numbers, yes? I’ve had more than enough of venturing alone.&lt;page&gt;And you... I trust I will see you there? My carriage hides a special secret I’d gladly share with you when next we meet! Heh heh!</en>
    <zh>哇，没想到黑暗中竟出现这样一张美丽的脸！可怜的克拉特独自在这躲避黑丝好久了。&lt;hpage&gt;受丝咒侵蚀的虫兽确实危险，你躲起来是对的。&lt;hpage&gt;那金属车厢……是你的吧？&lt;page&gt;对对！我正要投奔跳蚤旅团呢！独行太危险了！&lt;page&gt;你……也会去旅团吧？那我们旅团再见，车厢里有惊喜等着你哟！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_COMPLETE_QUEST1">
    <en>There are still many fleas for us to be united with though, and we’ve rested long enough. The caravan must head higher!&lt;page&gt;Oh, but stranger, how remiss of me! I introduced myself earlier without ever asking for your own name. Forgive me! Please, what shall we call you?&lt;hpage&gt;You may call me Hornet, Fleamaster. Know that I, like you, am glad to see your fellow fleas safe with your caravan. These are dangerous lands to travel alone.&lt;hpage&gt;I still have a long journey ahead of me. If I come across any more fleas, I will assist where I am able.&lt;page&gt;Oh, vavenda! That is to say, incredible! What a beautiful thing for me to hear!&lt;page&gt;Dear friend... Miss Hornet. Our caravan must be away now, toward the wide moor high above. Would you travel with us, as our honoured guest?</en>
    <zh>虽然还有许多同胞未归，但我们休整太久了。旅团该向高处进发了！&lt;page&gt;哎呀我真是失礼！之前只顾自报家门，还没请教您的姓名？&lt;hpage&gt;叫我大黄蜂即可。很高兴见你和同胞平安相聚，在这种地方独行确实太过凶险。&lt;hpage&gt;我的旅途尚未结束，如果再遇见跳蚤，会尽力帮助他们的。&lt;page&gt;哎呀！这可太好了！&lt;page&gt;亲爱的朋友……大黄蜂小姐。旅团即将前往上方辽阔沼地，您愿意作为贵宾与我们同行吗？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_MEMBER_TALL_FLEATOPIA">
    <en>So many awful places have us fleas travelled. Many times I almost die. But here is seems safe enough.&lt;page&gt;You will have rest too? Is space enough for us all now... friend.</en>
    <zh>旅团闯过了多少险地，好几回我都差点死了。但这里似乎很安全。&lt;page&gt;你也留下休息吧，朋友？现在地方够大。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_MEET_JUDGE">
    <en>Welcome again, Miss Hornet! See how high our caravan has climbed, resting right on the doorstep of that mighty Citadel!&lt;hpage&gt;It is fortunate that all of your companions survived the trek, Fleamaster. The howling rise beside, and the tangled wood before it, have both claimed the lives of countless bugs.&lt;page&gt;Indeed! A perilous ascent! We have seen the many husks in passing. A mighty luck must shine on us, to journey with such success.</en>
    <zh>欢迎您，大黄蜂小姐！看我们攀得多高啊，就在圣堡大门旁！&lt;hpage&gt;你们能平安抵达这里实属万幸。旁边的峭壁和前边的丛林都葬送过无数旅行者。&lt;page&gt;确实凶险！沿途见到了无数空壳。我们定是受命运庇佑。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_COMPLETE_QUEST1_INTRO">
    <en>Look, look! So many fleas have joined the caravan! What a miracle! We can not thank you enough for honouring our humble wish!</en>
    <zh>看呐！这么多跳蚤加入了旅团！真是奇迹！真不知该如何感激您实现愿望！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_HUNTER_MEET_ACT3">
    <en>You remain, bug not flea? Would you seek service of me, ehh? Mine is knowledge much, the places of the lost little ones, heard and smelt across the caves.&lt;page&gt;You help find! And bring! Best we come together, we fleas all... now that times turn dark...</en>
    <zh>你还在啊，外族虫？要我帮忙吗？我知道那些迷途小辈的踪迹，各处洞穴都有。&lt;page&gt;你来寻找！把它们带来！最好齐聚于此，全体跳蚤……趁黑暗未临......</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FG_BOUNCE_DECLINE">
    <en>As you wish, sweet one. Shall we just rest here together on the shore of eternity instead?</en>
    <zh>如你所愿，甜心。要不就和我在这岸边静静地守望末日？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CARAVAN_LECH_SPA_PROMPT">
    <en>Enter spa?</en>
    <zh>进入温泉？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FG_JUGGLE_ACCEPT">
    <en>Mamashka! I am saying, let the game begin! Flea Juggle!</en>
    <zh>玛玛什卡！我是说，游戏开始！跳蚤耍耍！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_MEET_FLEATOPIA_TRAVELED">
    <en>What a beautiful spot you’ve gifted us, Miss Hornet! Safe apart from the dark and death of the lands beside. A place for fleas to grow smart and strong.&lt;page&gt;Here we shall see our travels end, for in Pharloom there could be no finer place to settle.&lt;hpage&gt;I am glad the location suits, Fleamaster. It is a calming thing to know these many fleas may survive. Most bugs of Pharloom seem destined for far bleaker fates.&lt;page&gt;Indeed! A hopeful future awaits! And only because of yourself and your efforts. To commemorate our arrival, it would be my pleasure to perform a small service for you.&lt;page&gt;I have been learning to sew, and the little fleas have been gathering materials for me. I thought I could add an extra pocket to your tool pouch, to make your travels just a little easier.&lt;page&gt;A trifling favour, much less than you deserve, but still I hope it meets to your satisfaction!</en>
    <zh>大黄蜂小姐选的地方太好了！远离外面的危险，跳蚤们肯定能在这茁壮成长！&lt;page&gt;这里就是我们旅团的终点站了，纺络再找不到比这更好的归宿了！&lt;hpage&gt;合你们的心意就好。能有这么多跳蚤幸存，我也感到高兴。其他虫类大多没那么幸运。&lt;page&gt;没错！未来充满希望，这全仰赖您的帮助。为纪念乔迁之喜，请收下这份纪念品。&lt;page&gt;我最近学了缝纫，小家伙们也帮我收集材料。想给你的工具袋加个口袋，让旅途轻松些。&lt;page&gt;区区薄礼不足挂齿，希望您别失望！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FG_BOUNCE_INTRO_CHAMP">
    <en>My dear Flea Bounce champion, will you play with us again? Let us dance and fly above the waters until the world itself falls away!</en>
    <zh>亲爱的蹦蹦冠军，要再玩一次吗？在水面上飞舞直至世界崩塌吧！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CARAVAN_LECH_ACT3_MEET">
    <en>Sweet one! What a delight to see you emerge from the horrible darkness now enveloping the world!&lt;page&gt;Poor Kratt feared he would have only his mangy fellow fleas for company at the end of everything. How kind of you to spend your last moments here with me!</en>
    <zh>甜心！没想到世界末日还能和你见面，真高兴！&lt;page&gt;可怜的克拉特本以为最后只能和脏跳蚤们作伴，多谢你在这最后时刻陪着我！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FESTIVAL_BOARD_HORNET_NAME">
    <en>Hornet</en>
    <zh>大黄蜂</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_ACCEPTED_WISHWALL_QUEST1_FULL">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;Fleamaster, I took your request from the wishwall in the pilgrim camp. You are seeking fleas to join your caravan? I have found and freed many throughout my travels.&lt;page&gt;Oh yes, indeed! And look here, they all have made their way to us! So many gathered, it seems a miracle. Our wishes granted before even your promise was known!</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;跳蚤首领，我在朝圣营地祈愿墙接下你的委托。你在召集跳蚤加入旅团？我在旅途中已经解救了许多跳蚤。&lt;page&gt;没错！看啊，它们全都归队了！我们的祈愿尚未传达，就已然实现，真是个奇迹！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FG_JUGGLE_COMPLETED">
    <en>Vikna! The game is now ended, but you can play again, as much you wish... until the end of the world comes for us all!</en>
    <zh>维克纳！我是说，游戏结束，但随时可以重玩……直到世界末日！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_OFFER_QUEST1">
    <en>Stranger, will you hear my worry? The time has come for us fleas to find each other and travel together, as has happened through generations before.&lt;page&gt;The many fleas of this kingdom should be flocking to our caravan, but times have become dangerous. You feel it too, yes? Our poor cousins, out there, in hiding!&lt;page&gt;Would you, could you, help us find these poor, lost fleas? We daren’t continue our journey until some of the poor dears have found their way here to us!</en>
    <zh>旅者，愿意跟我聊聊么？我们跳蚤的祖辈曾相聚同行，现在我想是时候召集同胞了。&lt;page&gt;本该有无数同胞来投奔旅团，可如今危机四伏，您也感受到了吧？可怜的同胞们还在外躲藏！&lt;page&gt;您……愿意帮忙寻找迷途的跳蚤们吗？同胞没有到齐我们不敢上路啊！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_TRAVEL_PROMPT">
    <en>Travel with the Flea Caravan?</en>
    <zh>与跳蚤旅团同行？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_GREYMOOR_LEAVE">
    <en>Alas, Miss Hornet! Until our paths cross again, our dearest wishes go with you.&lt;hpage&gt;Safe travels to you and your troupe, Fleamaster. </en>
    <zh>那好吧，大黄蜂小姐！愿好运常伴您左右，下次再见！&lt;hpage&gt;也祝你们一路平安。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FESTIVAL_OUTRO_POST">
    <en>And so the great ceremony has reached its climax and its grand champion has emerged!&lt;page&gt;Thank you for spending your last moments with us here, Miss Hornet.&lt;page&gt;Though the world will soon end, and our paradise will crumble, the memories of friendship we all shared shall surely echo through the oncoming void for all eternity!&lt;hpage&gt;Fleamaster, your sentiment is kind, but this world will not end.&lt;page&gt;Oh? How good of you to speak words of hope for our benefit, but we have accepted our fate. Come, let us forget the past and revel together!&lt;hpage&gt;It is not merely hope that I offer you, sir, but a promise. This kingdom’s suffering has a singular cause, and by my own claw will it be cleansed.&lt;hpage&gt;Perhaps not every flea will survive what is coming... but the world will not die, and your settlement may still see chance to prosper.&lt;page&gt;Ahh? You speak... with such conviction. But I cannot bring myself to hope such, I am sorry.&lt;page&gt;Come what may, we fleas will be here until the end. And the games will continue, of course! Celebrate with us for as long as you wish, dear friend.</en>
    <zh>加冕仪式结束，庆典高潮已过，总冠军诞生！&lt;page&gt;大黄蜂小姐，感谢您与我们共度最后的时光。&lt;page&gt;纵使世界即将毁灭，乐园即将倒塌，我们的友谊也会永存于虚空之间！&lt;hpage&gt;谢谢你，跳蚤首领。但世界不会终结的。&lt;page&gt;感谢您在这最后关头还给我们希望，但我们认命了。还是及时行乐吧！&lt;hpage&gt;我给的并非虚无缥缈的希望，而是承诺。纺络的苦难都有源头，而我一定会亲手将其终结。&lt;hpage&gt;或许不是所有跳蚤都能幸存……但只要世界不毁灭，旅团终将再次启程。&lt;page&gt;啊哈哈，您这话……信念坚定。但我已不敢奢望。&lt;page&gt;无论如何，跳蚤们会坚持到最后。游戏永不停止！您想在这里玩多久都行，朋友！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FG_JUGGLE_COMPLETED_CHAMP_TO_OUTRO">
    <en>Vikna! The game is ended, and we have a new Flea Juggle champion! Incredible!&lt;page&gt;You have proven yourself the champion at each of our flea games!&lt;page&gt;I am confident now that the grand champion of our festival has emerged. It is none other than yourself, of course!&lt;page&gt;And thusly, must our final ceremony begin. Fleas, prepare yourselves!</en>
    <zh>维克纳！游戏结束，新的耍耍冠军诞生！太强了！&lt;page&gt;您已称霸所有跳蚤游戏！&lt;page&gt;是当之无愧的庆典总冠军！&lt;page&gt;最终仪式现在开始！跳蚤们，做好准备！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_HUNTER_CANCELED">
    <en>You not want my learnings, bug not flea? Rare it is we share such things with ones outside our own. </en>
    <zh>不想要我情报？我们可很少愿意和外族分享这些。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FG_JUGGLE_CHOICE">
    <en>Compete in Flea Juggle?</en>
    <zh>游玩跳蚤耍耍？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FG_JUGGLE_INTRO_CHAMP">
    <en>Miss Hornet, you are the greatest of us all in the Flea Juggle! But will you challenge yourself to ever higher achievements?</en>
    <zh>大黄蜂小姐是耍耍之王！要挑战更高记录吗？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_MEMBER_TALL_MEET">
    <en>Dodeshna, stranger. You are looking a little... tired, is it? Unhealthy?&lt;page&gt;You can rest with us here, if wish. Is nice and dark, and warmth from below brings good health.&lt;page&gt;Still, you should make care not to stay much long. You are not flea, after all.</en>
    <zh>多德什纳，旅者。你看着……有点累？&lt;page&gt;想休息可以留下。这儿又暗又暖，很适合休养。&lt;page&gt;但别待太久，毕竟你终究不是跳蚤。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_HUNTER_WILD_REPEAT_NOCARAVAN">
    <en>You still here, bug? Is rest I need before I travel. Not chat. You is trouble-type. Make my shell tense.&lt;hpage&gt;I shall take my leave, madam. Stay strong on your own journey. May we meet again in more hospitable surrounds.</en>
    <zh>你怎么还在？我休息够了就走。别啰嗦，感觉你身上麻烦事不少，让我甲壳发紧。&lt;hpage&gt;那就告辞了，女士。祝你路上顺利，我们下次再见。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_GREYMOOR_CANLEAVE_FULL">
    <en>Look, Miss Hornet! See the many lively fleas that form our caravan. Thanks to you and your hunting, so many are here! And all are eager again to travel!&lt;page&gt;We had once wished to match the numbers of our fabled past, yet now, we may even have exceeded them!&lt;hpage&gt;It is a welcome sight, Fleamaster, and the playful cheer about the caravan suggests you are a fine steward to the troupe.&lt;page&gt;Such kind words, Miss Hornet! How lucky we are to have found a friend so fair!&lt;page&gt;But now, we must away! These moors have been our host long enough. It is time to climb and hoist towards drier caves!&lt;page&gt;Good friend to fleas, would you join us on this next journey? </en>
    <zh>请看，大黄蜂小姐！这么多活蹦乱跳的同胞加入！多亏您帮忙，队伍越来越壮大。大家都盼着再度启程！&lt;page&gt;我们曾奢望恢复传说中的旅团规模，而现在或许已经超越了传说！&lt;hpage&gt;看见这么多跳蚤平安无事，我也很欣慰。他们的欢声笑语也证明了你是个称职的领队。&lt;page&gt;大黄蜂小姐过奖了！能结交您这样的朋友才是旅团的幸运！&lt;page&gt;但现在该启程了！沼地虽好，但不应久留，该向更干燥的洞窟进发了！&lt;page&gt;跳蚤之友，愿意与我们一起出发吗？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_JUDGE_TRAVEL">
    <en>Marvellous! We fleas shall be overjoyed to have your company on the road.&lt;page&gt;Now! Our new home is calling. We must travel!</en>
    <zh>太好了！跳蚤们肯定会为与你同行而欢呼！&lt;page&gt;现在！该向着新家进发了！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_MEMBER_SHORT_REPEAT_GREYMOOR">
    <en>I’m wonder at this land... Something heavy hangs above, like shadow. I’m hope the little fleas have not much danger here...</en>
    <zh>这地方不对劲……总觉得天上有黑影压着。但愿小家伙们别出事……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_ACCEPTED_WISHWALL_QUEST1">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;Fleamaster, I took your request from the wishwall in the pilgrim camp. You are seeking fleas to join your caravan?&lt;page&gt;Oh, yes! The time has come for us fleas to find each other and travel together, as has happened through generations before.&lt;page&gt;The many fleas of this kingdom should be flocking to our caravan, but times have become dangerous. You feel it too, yes? Our poor cousins, out there, in hiding!&lt;page&gt;But... do I understand you rightly, stranger? You will help find the poor, lost fleas? Truly?</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;跳蚤首领，我在朝圣营地看到了你的祈愿。你要召集跳蚤加入旅团？&lt;page&gt;正是！跳蚤们该像祖辈那样聚首同行了。&lt;page&gt;本该有无数同胞来投奔旅团，可如今危机四伏，您也感受到了吧？可怜的同胞们还在外躲藏！&lt;page&gt;但……您真的愿帮忙寻找我们迷途的同胞？当真？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TROUPE_LEADER_GREYMOOR_HAUNTEDBELLHART">
    <en>That great vein of bells there... some of the fleas wanted to shelter inside, but I was not so sure. The whole creaking mass seems unstable! It makes me tremble!&lt;hpage&gt;You were wise not to head inside, Fleamaster. A silken curse has taken hold of the settlement within. Advise your fellows to avoid that place.&lt;page&gt;A curse, you say?! W-well then! Our thanks are owed again. I shall let all fleas know they must not venture closer.</en>
    <zh>那串巨钟……有些跳蚤想躲进去，但我总觉得不牢靠！看着就发颤！&lt;hpage&gt;不在里面扎营是明智之举。那里已被丝咒侵蚀，告诫同胞远离为妙。&lt;page&gt;丝咒？！那……那可要多谢提醒！我这就通知大伙别靠近。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FG_DODGE_COMPLETED">
    <en>Vikna. The trial has ended. Your score can be seen on the board beside me. </en>
    <zh>维克纳，试炼结束。成绩在我身旁的榜上。</zh>
  </entry>
</sheet>