<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<sheet name="Crawl">
  <entry key="BLUE_SCIENTIST_OFFER">
    <en>Oho? You linger here still? Perhaps, like myself, you have been bewitched by the Plasmium’s beautiful glow?&lt;page&gt;Then join me, you must! A new assistant is needed. Together we shall unlock the secrets of this wondrous substance!</en>
    <zh>哦哟？你还没走呢？难道你也迷上生质液的蓝光了？&lt;page&gt;那就加入我吧！正好缺新助手，我们一起揭开这宝贝的秘密！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BLUE_SCIENTIST_REFILL_ACCEPT">
    <en>There, you are replete with wonderful Plasmium once more! You can begin injecting it at once. Now, off with you!</en>
    <zh>拿好，神奇生质液又重新装满了！你又可以注射了，快出发吧！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BS_SIT_QUEST1_REOFFER">
    <en>Assistant... You will help, yes? The buds have ripened... The Plasmium harvest can begin...</en>
    <zh>助手……你会帮忙的对吧？花苞熟了……该收集生质液了……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BS_SIT_QUEST2_REFUSE">
    <en>Leave your fear behind... Cast it off like an old shell. Give me what I need...</en>
    <zh>抛开恐惧……像蜕壳一样扔掉。把东西给我……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BS_SIT_QUEST1_REPEAT">
    <en>Bring the Pure Plasmium. It must be tested... ingested.&lt;page&gt;Ready the Needle Phial to full charge... Strike deep the ripened buds. Return that precious liquid life to me... Assistant.</en>
    <zh>带纯净生质液来……必须测试……吸收……&lt;page&gt;把储液针管蓄满力……扎进成熟花苞……把生质液带回来……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BLUE_SCIENTIST_ACCEPT">
    <en>Excellent! With two bugs at the task, the rate of discovery shall greatly increase!&lt;page&gt;Now! Before he up and vanished, my previous assistant seeded the warrens below with Plasmium buds.&lt;page&gt;The buds should be ripening as we speak, and the nectar within must be extracted before they reach maturity.&lt;page&gt;With the right tool in claw, collecting the nectar is an easy process. I’ll even lend you my own Needle Phial for the job.&lt;page&gt;Once you locate a bud, simply charge the Phial until readied, then release its needle into a bud’s core. Do it right, and it’ll suck out the nectar in one clean pop!&lt;page&gt;Return them to me when you’ve retrieved the necessary samples. With the right nectar, and the right testing, Plasmium can reveal even more of its wondrous properties!</en>
    <zh>太好了！效率翻倍！&lt;page&gt;我那前任助手在下面虫道种了生质液花苞。&lt;page&gt;现在应该快成熟了，得在成熟前提取生质液。&lt;page&gt;用储液针管采集，很简单的，我把我用的借给你。&lt;page&gt;找到花苞后蓄满力，把针头扎进核心，嗖的一下就能抽出来！&lt;page&gt;把带样本回来。有了它们做实验，生质液会更神奇！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BS_SIT_QUEST2_CANCOMPLETE">
    <en>Assistant, that odour... aahhh... you have the Plasmified Blood...</en>
    <zh>助手……这气味……你拿到生质血了……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BLUE_SCIENTIST_REPEAT">
    <en>Keep using the Plasmium Phial, and enjoy all the wonderful effects it has on your body. Once your Plasmium reserve runs dry, visit me again.&lt;page&gt;I’ll charge a few rosaries for refills, but you can be confident that every bead goes towards our vital studies!</en>
    <zh>尽管用，好好感受生质液的神奇。用完再来找我。&lt;page&gt;如果要重新装满生质液，我得收点念珠当经费，都是为科研做贡献！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BS_SIT_REFILL_REFUSE">
    <en>Do you fear the Plasmium, even now? Ahhh... Assistant... open your mind to the possibilities...</en>
    <zh>现在还怕生质液？啊……助手……敞开心扉接受可能……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BS_SIT_REPEAT">
    <en>Assistant... What we might become... together.</en>
    <zh>助手……我们一起……成为……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BS_SIT_QUEST1_ACCEPT">
    <en>Ahhhh. Yes... Assistant. So loyal... Take the Needle Phial... find the buds below. They are ripe...&lt;page&gt;Charge the Phial to full strength... Pierce them deep... Extract that Pure Plasmium.&lt;page&gt;This shell shall become what you need it to be... Plasmium can cure all.</en>
    <zh>啊……对……助手……真忠诚……拿着储液针管……去下面找熟透的花苞……&lt;page&gt;蓄满力……扎透核心……提取纯净生质液……&lt;page&gt;这副躯壳将完成蜕变……生质液会治愈一切……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BLUE_SCIENTIST_QUEST_REPEAT">
    <en>Assistant! You’re still dallying about here? I’ve an eager need for pure Plasmium, fresh from the bud.&lt;page&gt;Just one fully charged stab of my Needle Phial straight into a ripe bud! You’ll suck the Plasmium right up!&lt;page&gt;Now, pop down into those worm warrens and extract it for me! What could possibly be more important?</en>
    <zh>助手！怎么还在这磨蹭？我要花苞里的新鲜生质液！&lt;page&gt;用储液针管扎成熟花苞，把生质液抽出来就行！&lt;page&gt;好了，快去虫道干活！还有什么比这更重要的？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BLUE_SCIENTIST_OFFER_ZANGO">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;I am curious about the equipment you have here, and the blue liquid contained within. What study consumes you?&lt;page&gt;Ahh yes! So this miraculous substance intrigues you too! A wonder beyond wonders, miracle made material!&lt;page&gt;Plasmium! A naturally occurring elixir with no equal! It heals wounds and strengthens shells! I suspect it can even defy death itself!&lt;hpage&gt;Plasmium, you call it? I have encountered its like before, or else a substance of remarkable similarity...&lt;page&gt;Highly unlikely! The grey and barren soil of the mainland could never produce something as singular as this, and that is undisputable fact!&lt;page&gt;Plasmium was discovered by my master at the farthest edge of Pharloom, hidden deep in salt-stricken waters. I brought it to these caves under her direction, to study how it flourishes in a foreign place.&lt;page&gt;Perhaps, like myself, you have been bewitched by the Plasmium’s beautiful glow? Would you assent then, to assisting me in my studies?</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;我对这些仪器和蓝色液体有点好奇，你在研究什么？&lt;page&gt;啊哈！你也对这神奇物质感兴趣！这是奇迹中的奇迹，实体化的魔法！&lt;page&gt;生质液！无与伦比的天然灵药！疗伤健体，说不定还能起死回生！&lt;hpage&gt;生质液？我好像见过类似的……&lt;page&gt;不可能！纺络那贫瘠的灰土地产不出这种宝贝，这是铁的事实！&lt;page&gt;最初是我的导师在王国边陲的咸水深处发现了它。我奉命带到这山洞研究异地培育。&lt;page&gt;难道你也迷上生质液的蓝光了？要不要当我的研究助手？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BLUE_SCIENTIST_REOFFER">
    <en>Plasmium is a marvel of nature! And a new assistant is sorely needed. Together, let us unlock its secrets!</en>
    <zh>生质液是自然奇迹！正好缺新助手，我们一起揭开它的秘密吧！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BLUE_SCIENTIST_MEET_ZANGO">
    <en>Oho? A new face! Not here to bother, I hope? I’ve critical studies underway in these twisting tunnels and can afford no distractions!&lt;page&gt;You haven’t met Zango, my assistant, by chance? An indolent sort? Short, slovenly, rather unreliable-seeming?&lt;hpage&gt;In a dark cave below here, I encountered a shell not dissimilar from your own. I suspect your assistant may have met an unfortunate end.&lt;page&gt;Ah ha! That careless buffoon. No surprises then. That lump never shone with the talent for true discovery.&lt;page&gt;Now! To my work I must return! With my assistant so rudely dying on me, I’ve tasks enough for two bugs.&lt;page&gt;Unless you have further interest in my precious Plasmium, kindly leave me in peace!</en>
    <zh>哦哟？新面孔！不是来捣乱的吧？我在这些弯弯绕绕的洞里搞重大研究，可经不起分心！&lt;page&gt;有见过我助手赞戈吗？懒骨头一个，矮个子邋遢样，看着就不靠谱？&lt;hpage&gt;我在下方一黑暗洞窟里见到过和你挺像的尸壳，看来你的助手可能遭遇了不幸。&lt;page&gt;哈！那个冒失鬼。一点也不意外，废物本来就没科研天赋。&lt;page&gt;好了！我得赶紧开始研究了！现在死了助手，我得干双份活。&lt;page&gt;除非你对生质液感兴趣，否则别打扰我！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BLUE_SCIENTIST_REFILL_REFUSE">
    <en>Oh? Those who hesitate learn nothing, you know! The wondrous bright glow of Plasmium makes all things clear!</en>
    <zh>哦？犹豫可学不到新知识！生质液的美丽蓝光会照亮一切！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="LIFEBLOOD_GLAND_MSG">
    <en>Plasmium Gland</en>
    <zh>生质液腺</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BS_SIT_QUEST2_OFFER">
    <en>Assistant... to learn more of Plasmium’s wonders... I know what we must do... &lt;page&gt;The bugs below... who have imbibed the substance... and evolved... their bodies are full with Plasmified Blood...&lt;page&gt;You must use the Needle Phial and extract this precious nectar... only by scrutinising it... can we attain higher knowledge...</en>
    <zh>助手……想更了解生质液……我知道该怎么办了……&lt;page&gt;下面那些……吸收生质液进化的生物……体内有生质血……&lt;page&gt;用储液针管提取……分析后……我们就能获得高阶知识……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BS_SIT_QUEST1_COMPLETE_1">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;I have retrieved the Pure Plasmium, as requested. Know that, in your current state, I feel some reservation passing it to you.&lt;hpage&gt;This path your research takes... The final result may not be pleasant.&lt;page&gt;Pure Plasmium? No... Assistant... You must not doubt... It is precious. Perfect. It was needed... You have done well. As always...</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;你要的纯净生质液。但要交给这样状态的你，我有点犹豫。&lt;hpage&gt;你的研究方向……结局可能不太妙。&lt;page&gt;纯净生质液？不……助手……别怀疑……这是珍宝……完美……必须的……干得好……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BS_SIT_QUEST2_OFFER_PRE">
    <en>These lands have taken the Plasmium well... the soil has drunk it deep, and the creatures bloom so beautifully... have you seen them?&lt;hpage&gt;The effect of your Plasmium on the beasts here is all too evident. Great change has been inflicted upon them.&lt;hpage&gt;There is an echo also of other infections I have witnessed. I wonder at the meaning of it all... or if I am perhaps imagining similarities where there are none.&lt;page&gt;Assistant, ahhh... you grow more inquisitive... We both seek deeper insight...&lt;page&gt;Could we... peer deeper inside somehow...? Let us think on it...</en>
    <zh>这片土地吸收了生质液……深入土壤，深入生物，花苞绽放……看见了吗？&lt;hpage&gt;你的生质液让野兽变异，影响太明显了。&lt;hpage&gt;这让我想起以前见过的其他感染，不知是巧合还是……&lt;page&gt;助手啊……你也变好奇了……想深入探索……&lt;page&gt;或许……我们该更进一步研究？……让我想想……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BS_SIT_QUEST1_REFUSE">
    <en>Ahhhh... Assistant... greed was ever your greatest failing. Do not guard your discoveries so jealously...</en>
    <zh>啊……助手……贪婪是你的弱点……别独占成果……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BS_SIT_REPEAT_DONE">
    <en>For you... dear assistant... drink deep my liquid life...</en>
    <zh>喝吧……亲爱的助手……饮下我的生命精华……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BLUE_SCIENTIST_QUEST_COMPLETE_2">
    <en>Since you have proven yourself a capable assistant, take this delightful implement of my own invention, a Plasmium Phial.&lt;page&gt;With it, you can inject precious Plasmium straight into your body. Almost painlessly!&lt;hpage&gt;Your tool certainly looks sharp enough to pierce my shell, sir, but why should I want to do so?&lt;page&gt;Because filling your body with Plasmium is so beneficial! It protects you from harm! And it feels so exquisitely good!&lt;page&gt;My assistant and I have been injecting Plasmium into the local flora and fauna since we arrived. No ill effects have been observed, and so we can conclude that the process is utterly, completely safe.&lt;page&gt;Keep using the Plasmium Phial, and enjoy all the wonderful effects it has on your body. If you ever run out of Plasmium, visit me again.&lt;page&gt;I’ll charge a few rosaries for refills, but you can be confident that every bead goes towards our vital studies!</en>
    <zh>既然你够格当助手，送你个好东西——生质液瓶！&lt;page&gt;有了它，就能直接往甲壳里注射生质液，几乎不疼！&lt;hpage&gt;这工具确实足够扎穿我的外壳，但我为何要这么做？&lt;page&gt;因为注射生质液好处多多！不仅能防止受伤，而且感觉非常好！&lt;page&gt;我和助手给本地动植物都打过，没出现任何副作用，完全安全！&lt;page&gt;尽管用，好好感受生质液的神奇。用完再来找我。&lt;page&gt;如果要重新装满生质液，我得收点念珠当经费，都是为科研做贡献！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BLUE_SCIENTIST_QUEST_COMPLETE_1">
    <en>Ahh, and exactly the required amount! A satisfactory effort, assistant!&lt;page&gt;With this pure Plasmium extract, I may finally come to understand this wondrous substance.</en>
    <zh>啊，分量刚好足够！干得不错！&lt;page&gt;有这纯净生质液，终于能破解奥秘了！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BS_SIT_QUEST2_REPEAT">
    <en>Ready the Needle Phial... find the plasmified bugs below...&lt;page&gt;Charge the Phial to full strength... Pierce them deep... Extract the Plasmified Blood...</en>
    <zh>拿上储液针管……找到因生质液进化的生物……&lt;page&gt;蓄满力……扎入它们体内……提取生质血……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BS_SIT_QUEST1_OFFER">
    <en>Assistant... You will help, yes? The buds have ripened... The Plasmium harvest can begin...</en>
    <zh>助手……你会帮忙的对吧？花苞熟了……该收集生质液了……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BS_SIT_QUEST2_REOFFER">
    <en>The bugs below who have imbibed the substance and evolved... their bodies are filled with Plasmified Blood...&lt;page&gt;You must use the Needle Phial and extract this precious nectar... only by scrutinising it... can we attain higher knowledge...</en>
    <zh>那些……吸收生质液进化的生物……体内有生质血……&lt;page&gt;用储液针管提取……分析后……我们就能获得高阶知识……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BS_SIT_QUEST2_COMPLETE_1">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;Take it, sir, though what insight it will grant you I cannot say.&lt;page&gt;Have faith, dear assistant... After all this I understand... the greatest knowledge comes only from faith... faith in Plasmium.&lt;page&gt;This blood you have collected... sparkles... I see it! A glorious form... a glorious future, shimmering back at us...</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;拿去吧，虽然不知能研究出什么。&lt;page&gt;要有信念，好助手……我现在明白了……真理源自信念……对生质液的信念……&lt;page&gt;你收集的血……在发光……我看见了！辉煌形态……辉煌未来……等着我们……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BS_SIT_QUEST1_DECLINE">
    <en>You decline, Assistant? You cannot. The buds... The harvest. It must occur... For the source, and your saving...</en>
    <zh>你拒绝？花苞……必须收割……为了源头，也为了救你……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BS_SIT_QUEST2_DECLINE">
    <en>What fear arrests you...? This must be done... or we will never learn the deeper truth... Never become what is needed...</en>
    <zh>怕什么？……不这么做……永远不懂真相……永远无法进化……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BLUE_SCIENTIST_DECLINE">
    <en>You would refuse?! There is much work to be done, and it is all so achingly slow when I have no aid!</en>
    <zh>你要拒绝？！这么多活要干，没助手进度太慢了！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BS_SIT_QUEST2_ACCEPT">
    <en>Ahhhh. Yes... Assistant. So loyal... Take the Needle Phial... find the plasmified bugs below...&lt;page&gt;Charge the Phial to full strength... Pierce them deep... Extract their Plasmified Blood.&lt;page&gt;Once we have it... we can peer deeper... learn more... enlighten ourselves fully...</en>
    <zh>啊……好助手……拿上储液针管……找到因生质液进化的生物……&lt;page&gt;蓄满力……扎入它们体内……提取生质血。&lt;page&gt;有了它……我们能更深入……学习……完全开悟……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BS_SIT_MEET">
    <en>Ohhhhh... Assistant? Is that you?... You return at last, my friend?&lt;hpage&gt;Sir, you are in a disturbing state. This substance sprouts from within your shell. Time will see it consume you entirely. Would you seek aid?&lt;page&gt;No... No... Assistant... you are confused. A wonderful thing, we become. The Plasmium, our great research... We have progressed.&lt;page&gt;The research must continue. Soon... I shall become a source. </en>
    <zh>呃啊啊……助手？是你吗……终于回来了……&lt;hpage&gt;先生，你身体状态异常。某种物质在你壳内滋生，迟早会吞噬你。需要帮助吗？&lt;page&gt;不……不……助手……你错了。我们在进化……生质液……研究大突破……&lt;page&gt;研究必须继续……很快……我将成为源头……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BLUE_SCIENTIST_REFILL_OFFER">
    <en>Assistant! Have you come to refill your reserve of Plasmium?</en>
    <zh>助手！你是来补充生质液的？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="LIFEBLOOD_REFILL_PROMPT">
    <en>Refill Plasmium Reserve?</en>
    <zh>装满生质液？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BLUE_SCIENTIST_MEET">
    <en>Oho? A new face! Not here to bother, I hope? I’ve critical studies underway in these twisting tunnels and can afford no distractions!&lt;page&gt;You haven’t met Zango, my assistant, by chance? An indolent sort? Short, slovenly, rather unreliable-seeming?&lt;hpage&gt;I have not, sir. I am curious though, about the equipment you have here, and the blue liquid contained within. What study consumes you?&lt;page&gt;Ahh yes! So this miraculous substance intrigues you too! A wonder beyond wonders, miracle made material!&lt;page&gt;Plasmium! A naturally occurring elixir with no equal! It heals wounds and strengthens shells! I suspect it can even defy death itself!&lt;hpage&gt;Plasmium, you call it? I have encountered its like before, or else a substance of remarkable similarity...&lt;page&gt;Highly unlikely! The grey and barren soil of the mainland could never produce something as singular as this, and that is indisputable fact.&lt;page&gt;Plasmium was first discovered by my master at the farthest edge of Pharloom, hidden deep in salt-stricken waters. I brought it to these caves under her direction, to study how it flourishes in a foreign place.&lt;page&gt;Now! To my work I must return! Unless you have further interest in my precious Plasmium, or chance upon my truant assistant, kindly leave me in peace!</en>
    <zh>哦哟？新面孔！不是来捣乱的吧？我在这些弯弯绕绕的洞里搞重大研究，可经不起分心！&lt;page&gt;有见过我助手赞戈吗？懒骨头一个，矮个子邋遢样，看着就不靠谱？&lt;hpage&gt;没见过。不过我对这些仪器和蓝色液体有点好奇，你在研究什么？&lt;page&gt;啊哈！你也对这神奇物质感兴趣！这是奇迹中的奇迹，实体化的魔法！&lt;page&gt;生质液！无与伦比的天然灵药！疗伤健体，说不定还能起死回生！&lt;hpage&gt;生质液？我好像见过类似的……&lt;page&gt;不可能！纺络那贫瘠的灰土地产不出这种宝贝，这是铁的事实！&lt;page&gt;最初是我的导师在王国边陲的咸水深处发现了它。我奉命带到这山洞研究异地培育。&lt;page&gt;好了！我要继续工作了！除非你对生质液感兴趣，或者碰见我那翘班助手，否则别打扰我！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BS_SIT_REFILL_ACCEPT">
    <en>There... more. Let it seep deep into your shell... do not begrudge the pain...</en>
    <zh>灌满了……让液体渗入甲壳深处……别怕疼……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BS_SIT_QUEST1_CANCOMPLETE">
    <en>The Pure Plasmium... you have it. I can... smell it on you.</en>
    <zh>纯净生质液……你带来了。我闻到了……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BS_SIT_QUEST2_COMPLETE_2">
    <en>Through consumption of the blood... we shall at last attain enlightenment...&lt;page&gt;For your reward... take the gland from within my shell... my gift to you.&lt;page&gt;I have no more need of it... and it shall grant you... unending reserves of Plasmium...&lt;page&gt;Yes... Plasmium. Pure... beautiful... Plasmium...</en>
    <zh>吸收生质血……我们终将开悟……&lt;page&gt;给你的奖励是……拿走吧……我壳里的腺体……&lt;page&gt;我不需要了……它会给你……无限生质液……&lt;page&gt;没错……生质液……纯净……美丽……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BLUE_SCIENTIST_CANCOMPLETE">
    <en>Assistant! How goes your work? Have you extracted a sufficient amount of Plasmium for me?</en>
    <zh>助手！进展如何？提取到足够生质液了吗？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BLUE_SCIENTIST_ACCEPT_ZANGO">
    <en>Excellent! With two bugs at the task, the rate of discovery shall greatly increase!&lt;page&gt;Now! Before he went and died, my previous assistant seeded the warrens below with Plasmium buds.&lt;page&gt;The buds should be ripening as we speak, and the nectar within must be extracted before they reach maturity.&lt;page&gt;With the right tool in claw, collecting the nectar is an easy process. I’ll even lend you my own Needle Phial for the job.&lt;page&gt;Once you locate a bud, simply charge the Phial until readied, then release its needle into a bud’s core. Do it right, and it’ll suck out the nectar in one clean pop!&lt;page&gt;Return them to me when you’ve retrieved the necessary samples. With the right nectar, and the right testing, Plasmium can reveal even more of its wondrous properties!</en>
    <zh>太好了！效率翻倍！&lt;page&gt;我那死鬼助手在下面虫道种了生质液花苞。&lt;page&gt;现在应该快成熟了，得在成熟前提取生质液。&lt;page&gt;用储液针管采集，很简单的，我把我用的借给你。&lt;page&gt;找到花苞后蓄满力，把针头扎进核心，嗖的一下就能抽出来！&lt;page&gt;把带样本回来。有了它们做实验，生质液会更神奇！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BLUE_SCIENTIST_REFUSE">
    <en>Are you so enchanted by the Plasmium that you will not part with it? You are more like that dolt Zango than I first thought!&lt;page&gt;Its enlightenings are beyond your meagre mind! Give me the phial, assistant, or the deeper secrets of this substance will never be revealed!</en>
    <zh>舍不得交出来？你和赞戈那蠢货一个德行！&lt;page&gt;你这脑子参不透其中奥秘的！不交出生质液就永远别想知道秘密！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BS_SIT_REFILL_OFFER">
    <en>Aahhh... and you have been using your Plasmium... good. Let me replenish your reserve...</en>
    <zh>啊……你一直在注射生质液……很好。让我给你补满……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BS_SIT_QUEST1_COMPLETE_2">
    <en>Now. Share the discovery... Take this Plasmium Phial... Plunge it deep. Feel its vigour soak your shell...&lt;page&gt;If more is needed... If the Plasmium runs dry... return. Visit me again... That you may live, long... my loyal assistant.</en>
    <zh>现在，分享成果……拿着生质液瓶……扎进去……感受活力渗透……&lt;page&gt;用完再来找我……这样你才能……活得长久……我的好助手……</zh>
  </entry>
</sheet>