<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<sheet name="Dust">
  <entry key="TRADERS_QUEST_OFFER">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;The roaches outside, why are they kept in pens? They seem a dangerous creature to cage or tame.&lt;page=S&gt;Us moorbugs gotta eat, don’t we? They’re wild fast breeders, them Muckroaches. Hard shells and tough meat, if you can even crack ‘em open, but options ain’t plentiful so we ain’t choosy.&lt;page=S&gt;Ain’t so bad to eat, once you’re used to it. The guts is the best bit, but them’s a choice cut and we ain’t had it for ages now.&lt;page=L&gt;Har har, life is tough all right! Benj’n here’s wasting away before us, poor wretch!&lt;page=L&gt;Tugs at your emotions, eh missy? How ‘bout you put that poker to good use? Go poach some of them roaches and get us some tasty guts. There’d be fair trade waitin’ for you.</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;外头的蟑螂为何要圈养？此等凶兽关起来有什么好处？&lt;page=S&gt;我们这些沼地的虫子总得吃饭吧？淤秽蟑螂繁殖得贼快。虽然壳硬肉糙，破开都费劲，但我们也没得挑嘛。&lt;page=S&gt;吃惯了也倒还行。内脏最香，但这种精贵部位我们早八百年没尝过了。&lt;page=L&gt;哈！日子苦啊！瞧班金这体格，已经饿得瘦骨伶仃了！&lt;page=L&gt;是不是很可怜我们啊，小姐？要不用你那根烧火棍帮我们开开荤？去宰几只蟑螂，把内脏取来，我们会给你个公道价！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="GRUBFARMER_DELIVERY">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;Sir, I have brought a Queen’s Egg, at request of Bellhart’s couriers. It was a hazardous journey, but the creature inside has made it here alive.&lt;page&gt;Sssssss! How sss-ssublime! To think that my dear misss-stress would be the one to deliver the preciousss package! I had feared for the competence of those feeble couriersss...&lt;hpage&gt;It surprises me to know you correspond with them. I must wonder where else you go and who else you speak to after you scurry back up into the darkness...&lt;page&gt;Ssss. My whispersss-ss travel far, misstressss. You need not worry yourssself with my comingsss and goingss-ss. All I do... is in your sssss-service.&lt;page&gt;And now, pleasssse... give her to me... the little queen!</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;先生，我应钟心镇送货员之请，带来了一枚女王之卵。路途虽险，但卵内的生物尚且还活着。&lt;page&gt;咝——！何等殊荣！竟然由主人亲自护送这样宝贵的包裹！奴才我早就觉得这些送货员无能了……&lt;hpage&gt;你与他们有过联系？这倒是让我惊讶。不知道你遁入这片黑暗后，还与哪些虫往来过……&lt;page&gt;咝——奴才的低语声能传得很远，主人您无需担心我的行踪。奴才所为……皆为效忠于您。&lt;page&gt;现在，恳请您……将小女王……交给我！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TRADERS_TALK_GENERIC_2">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;The beasts outside and their masters alike are all ensnared by this land’s silken affliction. You are lucky bugs to have not succumbed.&lt;page=L&gt;The Haunting? Oh, we’s got that all worked out. Benj’n and me are a right pair of philosophers when we bend our minds to it.&lt;page=L&gt;It’s faith that gets you. It’s all caused by being too devout!&lt;page=S&gt;Yeah! Or maybe not bein’ devout enough!&lt;page=L&gt;Or maybe it’s safest not to think about it at all. Har har!</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;外头那些虫兽与其饲主都遭受丝咒侵蚀。二位未被沾染，实属侥幸。&lt;page=L&gt;丝咒？早研究透啦！班金和我可是哲学大师！&lt;page=L&gt;信仰过头的才会中招！全是虔诚惹的祸！&lt;page=S&gt;对！但如果不够虔诚，兴许也会中招！&lt;page=L&gt;要我说，最安全的办法就是别去瞎琢磨！哈！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="GRUBFARMER_GROWING_ACT3">
    <en>While you sss-stalk through the black-ravaged world, morsss-ssels will I grow. For the promiss-sse of what my misss-tress will become... I will toil, alwayssss...</en>
    <zh>只要主子您还在黑灾肆虐之地穿行，咝——奴才便会辛勤劳作，为主人进行培育。为主人脱胎换骨的承诺……咝——奴才至死方休！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TRADERS_TALK_GENERIC_1">
    <en>&lt;page=S&gt;It’s said the moors used to grow a bounty of fresh food, way back befores that Citadel set us about catchin’ their fallin’ thread.&lt;page=S&gt;Sounds right lovely, eh missy? Always eatin’, never troubled by no grumblin’ belly?&lt;page=L&gt;Har har! Yer like a hatchling, Benj’n! So given to fancies! &lt;page=L&gt;Now breedin’ roaches is what keeps us from starvin’. Dangerous work, and not the finest diet, but we ain’t complainin’.&lt;page=L&gt;Specially as more and more of them keepers are succumbing to the strange sickness. Only means more meat for us. Har!</en>
    <zh>&lt;page=S&gt;传说在圣堡逼我们捡拾掉落的丝线之前，沼地也曾盛产新鲜美食。&lt;page=S&gt;听着多美啊，小姐。一天到晚地吃，不用担心饿肚子。&lt;page=L&gt;哈！班金，你是刚破卵的吗？净做白日梦！&lt;page=L&gt;现在我们只能靠养蟑螂混口饭吃。这活危险，伙食差，但我们从不抱怨。&lt;page=L&gt;你看吧，越来越多的监管者都染上怪病。但往好处想，对我们来说，肉倒是更加管够了！哈！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TRADERS_TALK_REPEAT">
    <en>&lt;page=L&gt;We’re all fine here, miss. Content, like. P’raps it were time you made your way, eh?&lt;page=S&gt;Yeah, be on your way! And, erm, thanks for yer help there.</en>
    <zh>&lt;page=L&gt;我俩在这儿好得很，小姐。差不多该动身了吧？&lt;page=S&gt;对，赶紧走！另外，呃……多谢帮忙。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TRADERS_PINS_PROMPT">
    <en>Buy Steel Spines?</en>
    <zh>购买钢棘？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="GRUBFARMER_POPPED">
    <en>Sssss. Your hunger betrayssss-ss you, misstress. The morsel was not yet grown, but let it anger you not. I will grow you another... for I am your sss-ssslave.</en>
    <zh>咝——您看起来饥饿难耐了，主人。食物还未养成，请您息怒。奴才我继续努力……因为我永远是您的仆从。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="GRUBFARMER_MEET_3_ACT3">
    <en>Ssss! You have come to claim me, and I am yourssss. I am your humble sss-ssslave!&lt;hpage&gt;I’ve no interest in mastery over you, sir. If my cutting down of those black masses aided you, it was merely by chance. Farewell.&lt;page&gt;Farewell...? No... the sss-strong claim the weak, and the weak must sss-ssserve! I am yoursss, my mistress, and you muss-sst protect me!&lt;page&gt;Sss-ssee what I have built here! Prepared, for the coming of my mistressss. My powerful missssss-tress!&lt;page&gt;While you are away hunting, I will grow you... ssss-something good. But the work takesss time. Return to me sssss-soon, and you may have what I grow...</en>
    <zh>咝——！您来收服奴才了！奴才是您的，卑微的仆从！&lt;hpage&gt;我无意当你的主人。若清除那些黑暗之物帮助了你，仅是机缘巧合。告辞。&lt;page&gt;告辞……？不行不行……咝——强者当纳弱者，弱者理应侍奉！奴才归您了，主人您必须庇护我！&lt;page&gt;快瞧奴才为您建的巢穴！专为恭迎您的到来！我强大的主人！&lt;page&gt;您外出狩猎时，奴才将为您培育……一些好东西。但奴才我需要一些时间。等您回来，就能得到我培育的成果……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TRADERS_TALK_REFUSE_GIVE">
    <en>&lt;page=S&gt;Wh... why the delay? You keepin’ them guts for yourself? Here, Crull, she’s goin’ back on her promise!&lt;page=L&gt;Har. Promises is easily broken. But then, so’s a lot of other things. How ‘bout you reconsider yer greed there, missy?</en>
    <zh>&lt;page=S&gt;啧……怎么磨磨蹭蹭的？你想私吞内脏？克鲁尔，她反悔啦！&lt;page=L&gt;哈，承诺不就是易碎。虽然其他东西也挺易碎的。小姐，要不重新掂量下你这贪心值不值当？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TRADERS_PINS_DECLINE">
    <en>&lt;page=S&gt;Oi! You ain’t got the beads? Or you just not wantin’ to part with ‘em? &lt;page=L&gt;Hardly the time to be a miser, missy. You’re gonna be livin’ sick till you buy these spines from us.</en>
    <zh>&lt;page=S&gt;喂！你是身上没念珠，还是舍不得花？&lt;page=L&gt;小姐，现在可不是抠门的时候！不买这些钢棘，你就只能继续病着了！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="GRUBFARMER_MEET_3">
    <en>Ssss! You have come to claim me, and I am yourssss. I am your humble sss-ssslave!&lt;hpage&gt;I’ve no interest in mastery over you, sir. If my slaying of these creatures aided you, it was merely by chance. Farewell.&lt;page&gt;Farewell...? No... the sss-strong claim the weak, and the weak must sss-ssserve! I am yoursss, my mistress, and you muss-sst protect me!&lt;page&gt;Sss-ssee what I have built here! Prepared, for the coming of my mistressss. My powerful missssss-tress!&lt;page&gt;While you are away hunting, I will grow you... ssss-something good. But the work takesss time. Return to me sssss-soon, and you may have what I grow...</en>
    <zh>咝——！您来收服奴才了！奴才是您的，卑微的仆从！&lt;hpage&gt;我无意成为你的主人。若杀掉这些虫兽帮助了你，仅是机缘巧合。告辞。&lt;page&gt;告辞？不行不行……咝——强者接纳弱者，弱者应当侍奉！奴才归您，主人您必须保护我！&lt;page&gt;看奴才我建的巢穴！专为恭迎主人的到来！强大的主人！&lt;page&gt;您外出狩猎时，奴才将为您培育……一些好东西。但奴才我需要一些时间。等您回来，就能得到我培育的成果……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="PRINCE_CELL_INSPECT">
    <en>A cage with a simple lock.</en>
    <zh>带有简易锁具的囚笼。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="GRUBFARMER_MEET_1">
    <en>Sssss! I saw you. I sssss-saw what you did!</en>
    <zh>咝——！我看见了。奴才我看见您的手段了！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="GRUBFARM_MIMIC_REMEET_PRE">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;I would speak again. Show yourself.</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;我想再跟你谈谈。现身吧。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TRADERS_PINS_OFFER">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;Good bugs, I am here on request of the doctor Yarnaby. She requires spines forged of steel for a crucial operation.&lt;page=L&gt;Argh! Look at ‘er, Benj’n. She’s all sick like! Coiled up tight with somethin’ weird. I reckon that operation’s for her herself!&lt;page=S&gt;She’s a sad sight for sure Crull, but sick or not our scrap’s hard-found. If she’s wantin’, we’s gotta be gettin’ paid!&lt;page=L&gt;Ah! ‘Fraid the little one speaks true, missy. You might be ailin’, but we can’t be offerin’ charity. &lt;page=L&gt;We’re stockin’ the spines you need. You just gotta be ready to part with some beads!</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;二位，我受雅纳碧医生所托来到此处。她需要一些钢棘来完成一场重要的手术。&lt;page=L&gt;啊呀！班金快看，她病恹恹的！壳里缠着怪东西，手术是要给自己做的吧！&lt;page=S&gt;惨是惨，但咱的废料也是辛辛苦苦收集来的。想要就得掏钱！&lt;page=L&gt;唉！班金说得对，小姐。您虽然是病患，但我们不做慈善。&lt;page=L&gt;只要念珠够，钢棘有的是！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="GRUBFARMER_MEET_2">
    <en>Strong you are, misstress! Sss-ssmall, but so so deadly. And your ssscent! Well-aged!</en>
    <zh>咝——您真强悍，主人！身形虽小，杀伐果决。还有这味道——古老的气息！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="PRINCE_CELL_REPEAT">
    <en>Leave it, bug. I accept my place.&lt;hpage&gt;Very well, prisoner.</en>
    <zh>别管我了，小虫子。我已认命。&lt;hpage&gt;悉听尊便。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="GRUBFARMER_NEEDOLIN">
    <en>Sssss! Such sssss-sounds, plucked from the air and caught in your Silk! A marvel, my misss-stress...&lt;hpage&gt;It is a skill that any can learn. You could master this sound yourself, if you cared to.&lt;page&gt;No... a slave must grow morsels for his mistresssss. But the sssound... is so ssssss-soothing...</en>
    <zh>咝——！此等丝弦天籁，主人，这真是神迹……&lt;hpage&gt;这项技艺所有虫子皆可习得。你若愿意，也能精通。&lt;page&gt;不……仆从必须为主人培育食物。但这天籁之音……实在是令我感到抚慰……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="GRUBFARMER_DELIVERY_POST_SETUP">
    <en>It is done. Our nessst is larger, and the little queen beginssss her toil. &lt;page&gt;More morsss-ssels can I grow for you now! Are you pleasss-sed with me, my missstress-ss?&lt;hpage&gt;You are diligent at your work, and have raised no claw against me. If it remains so, I will have no reason to be displeased.&lt;page&gt;Ssss! Then my work will continue! For I am ever your devoted sss-ssslave!</en>
    <zh>大功告成。巢穴已扩建完毕，小女王已经开始她的劳作。&lt;page&gt;现在奴才我可以为您培育更多的食物了！您对我满意吗，我的主人？&lt;hpage&gt;你工作勤勉，也从未对我起过任何歹意。若能保持如此，我便没有不满的理由。&lt;page&gt;咝——！奴才一定继续勤恳工作！因为我永远是您忠诚的仆从！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="GRUBFARMER_OPENED1">
    <en>Ssss! Mistress, is the morsss-sssel I grew worthy? You must conss-sume... conssss-sume and become sss-stronger.&lt;page&gt;Thissss is how I will sss-sserve my misstress-ss. While you hunt, I will prepare morsssels. Alwaysss, preparing them for my mighty misssss-tresss...&lt;hpage&gt;Continue this work if it pleases you sir, but do not call me your mistress, for I am not.&lt;page&gt;Sss... but you are... missstress. You are ssss-strong and I am weak.... a sss-sslave. Alwayss-sss, your ssss-slave...</en>
    <zh>咝——！主人，奴才培育的食物可还合您心意？请享用……变得更强大。&lt;page&gt;这就是奴才我的侍奉之道。您外出狩猎时，奴才准备食物。永远为主人效劳……&lt;hpage&gt;先生，若你乐于此道便请继续，但请不要称我为主人。我并非你的主人。&lt;page&gt;咝——可您就是……我的主人。您强大，我弱小……我永远是您的仆从……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TRADERS_QUEST_COMPLETE">
    <en>&lt;page=S&gt;That smell! S’overwhelming! I ain’t never seen so many roach guts at once!&lt;page=L&gt;Benj’n, me old mate, get a grip on yerself. These guts still need cuttin’, and cleanin’, and stewin’. You got a lotta work ahead of you.&lt;page=S&gt;Fine by me, Crull, if it means such a feast! We’ll be eatin’ like they do up in the Citadel soon enough!&lt;page=L&gt;And what about you, missy? You be joinin’ us for this exquisite meal?&lt;hpage&gt;I’m afraid not, sirs. I must keep moving, and I fear the taste of such a delicacy is wasted on me.&lt;page=L&gt;I was hopin’ as much. Two can sing, but three’s too many, eh? Har har!&lt;page=L&gt;Still, maybe this tool is enough for you to ‘member us by? A pointed weapon of me own makin’, from when I used to wrangle the Muckroaches meself. I bet you’ll get some good use from it.</en>
    <zh>&lt;page=S&gt;这味儿！够冲！我这辈子没见过这么多蟑螂内脏！&lt;page=L&gt;班金老伙计，稳住！这些内脏还得切洗炖煮，你的活还多着呢。&lt;page=S&gt;包在我身上，克鲁尔！我们能吃上圣堡级别的宴席啦！&lt;page=L&gt;小姐您呢？要赏脸和我们共进大餐不？&lt;hpage&gt;恕不奉陪，我得继续前行了。而且此等美味给我享用，实属浪费。&lt;page=L&gt;正合我意！俩虫享用正好，仨就嫌多！哈！&lt;page=L&gt;但我希望这工具能让您记住我俩。这是当年我还在驯蟑螂时亲手制作的武器，希望您用得顺手。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="GRUBFARM_MIMIC_GIVE_POST">
    <en>Take. Ahhh, my reward. Give them.</en>
    <zh>我要拿走。啊……我的奖赏。给我。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="GRUBFARMER_DELIVERY_POST_DELIVERY">
    <en>With thissss... ssso caringly delivered by the misstresss... our nesssst can be expanded!</en>
    <zh>咝——这是……主人亲自护送过来的……我们的巢穴可以扩建了！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="PRINCE_CELL_TALK_ACT3">
    <en>Leave me be. This kingdom’s collapse has come. Better I stay here to accept it.&lt;page&gt;To die within a cage... A fitting finale for this shell, and a well deserved fate for these cursed lands.&lt;hpage&gt;As you wish, prisoner.</en>
    <zh>让我安安静静待在这里吧。这个王国即将倾塌，我应当待在这里，坦然接受一切。&lt;page&gt;在囚笼中死去……也算是我这副甲壳注定的命数了，这片诅咒之地亦是如此。&lt;hpage&gt;如你所愿。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="GRUBFARM_MIMIC_MEET">
    <en>I can sense you. Hidden.</en>
    <zh>我能感知到你，藏起来的那位。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TRADERS_PINS_REPEAT">
    <en>&lt;page=L&gt;Another trade fairly conducted, har. Those spines are sharp, and they’s hardly begun to rust. Better be gettin’ back to your doc to get yerself sorted out, eh?</en>
    <zh>&lt;page=L&gt;又一笔公道买卖，哈。这些钢棘锋利如初，基本还没开始生锈。快去找您那位医生治病去吧！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TRADERS_QUEST_ACTIVE_REPEAT">
    <en>&lt;page=L&gt;We’re still waitin’ on them roach guts you promised us, missy. Patiently, but not too patiently, you get me?&lt;page=S&gt;You can find the Muckroaches all ‘round these roads. Cut one down and reach inside its shell to pull out the tasty guts! Mmmmm!</en>
    <zh>&lt;page=L&gt;小姐，我俩还等着您许诺的蟑螂内脏呢。耐着性子等，但也不太耐烦了，懂我意思吗？&lt;page=S&gt;淤秽蟑螂到处都是，找一只来宰了，破开外壳，把内脏取来。唔——我都流口水了！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="GRUBFARM_MIMIC_GIVE_DENY">
    <en>Give them. Take wrong. Ssssomeone, ssssave me.</en>
    <zh>给我。拿错了。咝——救救我。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="GRUBFARM_MIMIC_MEET_PRE">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;I can sense you there, hidden in the darkness. Show yourself.</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;我能感知到你，隐匿于黑暗之中的那位。现身吧。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TRADERS_QUEST_REFUSE">
    <en>&lt;page=L&gt;Refuse us, do you, missy? No matter then. We’ll just get back to slowly starving, har har!</en>
    <zh>&lt;page=L&gt;小姐，你真要拒绝我们吗？无妨！继续慢慢饿死呗，哈！哈！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TRADERS_QUEST_CANCOMPLETE">
    <en>&lt;page=L&gt;Ooh, someone’s carrying a delectable scent! Come to deliver us what you promised, missy?</en>
    <zh>&lt;page=L&gt;噢，你身上有股好香的味道！小姐是来兑现承诺的吧？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="GRUBFARM_MIMIC_GRUB">
    <en>The morsselssssss. Give them. Take.</en>
    <zh>咝——食物……交出来。我要拿走。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TRADERS_PINS_REOFFER">
    <en>&lt;page=L&gt;Thinkin’ serious about the spines, missy? Surely your good health’s worth more than a few beads!</en>
    <zh>&lt;page=L&gt;要不再考虑考虑买钢棘的事？小姐，您的健康可比几颗念珠金贵！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="GRUBFARM_MIMIC_GIVE">
    <en>Yes, give it here!</en>
    <zh>是的，快给我！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TRADERS_QUEST_REOFFER">
    <en>&lt;page=L&gt;How ‘bout you put that poker to good use then, missy? Go poach some of them roaches and get us some tasty guts? There’d be fair trade waitin’ for yer!</en>
    <zh>&lt;page=L&gt;小姐，要不用你那根烧火棍帮我们开开荤？去宰几只蟑螂，把它们美味的内脏取来，我们会给你个公道价！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="GRUBFARMER_RETURN">
    <en>Misstress, you called for your ssss-slave? I obey... for you are ssss-sstronger. My gatheringsss can wait.</en>
    <zh>咝——主人，您在召唤奴才我吗？奴才遵命……因您比我更强大。采集之事可以暂缓。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TRADERS_QUEST_ACCEPT">
    <en>&lt;page=L&gt;Har. I reckon you don’t know how much trouble you’ve promised yourself just now, missy.&lt;page=L&gt;Ah well, best you get to it. Muckroaches are everywhere along these old roads. Just find a few and pluck their guts out. Easy as sin!</en>
    <zh>&lt;page=L&gt;哈！小姐，您可不知自个儿揽了个多大的麻烦。&lt;page=L&gt;算了，麻溜开工吧。淤秽蟑螂到处都是，找几只宰了，把它们内脏取来。简单得很！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="GRUBFARM_MIMIC_NOGRUB">
    <en>Not right. Nothing. Go.</en>
    <zh>不对。什么都没有。走开。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="PRINCE_CELL_TALK">
    <en>Leave me be, traveller. Better I accept this kingdom’s cruelty than rage helpless against it.&lt;page&gt;To waste in a cell, forgotten. ‘Tis no worse a fate than the Haunting that binds Pharloom’s many fragile minds.&lt;hpage&gt;As you wish, prisoner.</en>
    <zh>让我安安静静待在这里吧，旅行者。与其毫无意义地反抗这王国降下的残酷，不如选择接受它。&lt;page&gt;于囚笼钟腐朽，遗忘。总好过丝咒缠身，沦为纺络万千痴愚之一。&lt;hpage&gt;如你所愿。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="GRUBFARMER_TENDING">
    <en>Tending to the morss-ssels is a delicate tasssk, and requiresss much patience. Let me toil for you, missstresss, under your exquisite protection...</en>
    <zh>咝——培育食物需要精细耐心。请容奴才我在您的庇护下劳作……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="GRUBFARM_MIMIC_REMEET">
    <en>Show again. Speak yourself.</en>
    <zh>再次现身吧，我们聊聊。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="GRUBFARMER_GROWING">
    <en>A ss-sslave must feed his misstress-sss. Morsss-sels will I grow. While you hunt, I am working... alwaysss-sss...</en>
    <zh>咝——奴才应当伺候主人。奴才我会培育食物。您狩猎时，奴才劳作……永不停歇……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TRADERS_PINS_ACCEPT">
    <en>&lt;page=S&gt;S’a pleasure doin’ business, ma’am. It’s only the finest scrap we’re sellin’. Promise!&lt;page=S&gt;For your shell’s sake, we’ll be hopin’ all them spines can get the job done!</en>
    <zh>&lt;page=S&gt;交易愉快，小姐。我们卖的绝对都是上等废料！我敢打包票！&lt;page=S&gt;希望这些钢棘能助你甲壳康复！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="GRUBFARMER_MEET_ACT_3">
    <en>Ssss! My misstress hasss returned to me! Under her protection, I have no fear of the ssslithering black sssss-sstringss!&lt;page&gt;How the world trembles in their terrible grassssp! In such times, only the mighty sssurvive... and those who loyally ss-sserve them...&lt;hpage&gt;I cannot remain here to protect you sir, but know that my aim is to cut this land free of the black threads. In the meantime, you should concern yourself with your own safety.&lt;page&gt;Ssss. I hear more than your words, misssstress. I hear your true dessiresss, pulsing within you. To see them met, I will continue to toil for you... alwaysssss.&lt;page&gt;</en>
    <zh>咝——！主人归巢，奴才拜伏！有您的护佑，奴才何惧那肆虐的黑灾！&lt;page&gt;天地在这恐怖攫握中战栗不休！咝——唯有强大者得以生存……以及附庸强者的忠仆……&lt;hpage&gt;我无法久留此地庇护你，先生。我此行是为了斩断此间黑灾的锁锢。各自珍重吧。&lt;page&gt;咝——奴才听到的岂止主人的言语，更识得您胸膛激荡的夙愿——必当达成！奴才唯有殚精竭虑……至死不渝！&lt;page&gt;</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="TRADERS_MEET">
    <en>&lt;page=L&gt;Oi, why you come in here, all treadin’ muck? With that nasty-lookin’ poker by yer side? Eh?&lt;page=S&gt;Yeah, why you comin’ in here? We ain’t done nothin’ wrong. We ain’t all twisted like them roachkeepers!&lt;page=L&gt;She’s come to kill us, Benj’n! S’the blimmin’ end for us, old mate! Har har!&lt;hpage&gt;I mean you no harm, good bugs. I cut down only those who bar my path.&lt;page&gt;&lt;page=L&gt;That so? Well, them keepers outside ain’t inclined to let strangers pass by, so you’ll be makin’ good use of yer poker there, missy.</en>
    <zh>&lt;page=L&gt;嘿，满脚泥污闯进来作甚？还带着根脏兮兮的烧火棍？嗯？&lt;page=S&gt;就是，来这儿干啥？我们可没干坏事，不像外头那群蟑螂看守者那样疯癫！&lt;page=L&gt;她是来宰咱们的，班金！老伙计，咱们要完犊子啦！哈哈！&lt;hpage&gt;二位，我无意加害你们。针刃只斩挡路之虫。&lt;page&gt;&lt;page=L&gt;当真？外头的监管者可不爱放生面孔过路。小姐，你那烧火棍可要派上大用场咯！</zh>
  </entry>
</sheet>