<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<sheet name="Enclave">
  <entry key="PILGRIM_LARGE_SK_SAVED_ACT3_REPEAT">
    <en>That golden knight’s out there, sister, cutting down the lost, keeping us safe.&lt;page&gt;Reckon this place would’ve already been overrun if not for them’n their noble blades.</en>
    <zh>小姐，那位金甲骑士在外面斩杀着被诅咒者，保护我们的安全。&lt;page&gt;没有他那伟大的刺刃，这地方早就败落了。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CARETAKER_DELIVERY_POST">
    <en>Take some beads for your effort, miss bellringer, and know this sad lot’ll be survivin’ a little longer thanks to you.</en>
    <zh>敲钟者小姐，拿些念珠当作辛苦费吧。多亏你，这些可怜虫又能多苟活几天了。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CARETAKER_SNARE_COMPLETE_POST">
    <en>S’done! The parts are prepared. I’m headin’ up now to set the heavy thing.&lt;page&gt;Even with the trap laid, best be guessin’ her on top won’t go down so simple. She’ll sense what’s comin’.&lt;page&gt;That blade of yours is gonna have to do its work ‘fore this thing can snap.&lt;hpage&gt;I’d expected such, sir. And I am ready. Set your snare. I shall attend shortly.</en>
    <zh>搞定了！部件准备完毕。我这就上去布置。&lt;page&gt;就算陷阱就位，顶上那位也不会乖乖受死。她能预感到潜在的危机。&lt;page&gt;你得先用你的针刃削弱她，这玩意才能触发。&lt;hpage&gt;我早有预料，先生。我已准备就绪。布置陷阱吧，我随后就到。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CITY_MERCHANT_SHOP_REPEAT_ACT3">
    <en>Everything is falling apart, my dear one. Be sure to share your rosaries with me before it’s too late!</en>
    <zh>亲爱的，这里的一切都在分崩离析。趁现在还来得及，把你的念珠分我一些吧！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CITY_MERCHANT_TALK1">
    <en>Lots of stories being sung about you, dear one. Gathering supplies, saving lost bugs... all sorts of good deeds!&lt;page&gt;Very clever to craft such a reputation for yourself. If you keep it up, you’ll fast become a legend among these simple sorts.&lt;hpage&gt;I’ve no interest in becoming one, madam. In my long life, I’ve known enough legends, watched them rise and fall and fade away, many times.&lt;page&gt;Is that so, dear? How humble you are! You should know though, this old pilgrim has her sight keenly trained on you! Nothing gets by old Jubilana!</en>
    <zh>亲爱的，现在好多虫子都在传颂你的事迹呢。收集物资、拯救迷失的虫子……全是各种各样的善举！&lt;page&gt;你很聪明，给自己打造了这么好的名声。这样下去，你很快就会成为这些单纯的家伙们心中的传奇啦。&lt;hpage&gt;女士，我可没兴趣成为什么传奇。在漫长的一生中，我见识过足够多的传奇，无数次看着他们崛起、衰落、消逝。&lt;page&gt;这样啊？亲爱的，你可真谦逊！不过你要知道，我这个老朝圣者可一直密切关注着你呢！什么都逃不过老朱比拉娜的眼睛！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CARETAKER_MEET_2">
    <en>It was you, wasn’t it? Ringin’ that great clanging bell just now! Right when I’m tryin’ to get some sleep!</en>
    <zh>刚才敲钟的是你吧？叮呤咣啷的！我正要补觉呢！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="PILGRIM_LARGE_REPEAT">
    <en>Please don’t go too far, sister. Right here’s the only safety you’ll find within this whole cursed place.</en>
    <zh>小姐，千万别走远。在这片诅咒之地，这儿是唯一安全的地方。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CITY_MERCHANT_BRIDGE_REPEAT">
    <en>There must be a few more goodies to gather up here, and I don’t need you lingering around in the meantime. Blessings, and farewell!</en>
    <zh>我这会儿可没法跟你一块回去，路上可能还有好东西等着我捡漏呢。愿你蒙福，再见！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CARETAKER_LV1_MEET">
    <en>Well, well! See here what your brash behaviour has wrought, bellringer!&lt;page&gt;Just as I predicted, this once-peaceful sanctuary is now crawling with all sorts. We’ve the beginnings of a shabby little settlement, all huddled around this old shrine!&lt;hpage&gt;These poor bugs, all are victims of the Citadel and its insidious attraction. This place draws them up, into its maw, only to consume them, utterly.&lt;page&gt;Aye, inside and out, s’nothing but a grand, gilded lie. Well, at least these few stragglers can enjoy a moment’s safety. Poor fools...</en>
    <zh>瞧瞧你干的好事，敲钟者！&lt;page&gt;跟我料想的一样，这座本来平静的钟殿现在挤满了各色杂碎！一帮可怜虫围着那旧钟搭了个窝！&lt;hpage&gt;这些可怜虫都是圣堡的牺牲品，被它的谎话骗来，最终将被吞噬殆尽。&lt;page&gt;哼哼，这里就是个外表光鲜的巨大骗局。不过至少这群蠢货能享受片刻安宁……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CITY_MERCHANT_ITEM_SEAL_CHIT">
    <en>A precious order passed down by the holy conductors. Rare now to find these old texts, and rarer still to find a bug able to read ‘em.</en>
    <zh>神圣指挥官亲笔签发的珍稀敕令。如今，这种古卷已经很难找到了，而能读懂它们的虫子就更少见了。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CITY_MERCHANT_SAVED_1">
    <en>Ooh, what a turn-up! I’d feared t’was naught but meself left sane about these halls. Seems this old bug’s luck has not yet worn thin!&lt;hpage&gt;It was more than luck that saw me to you, madam. I promised the wish of bugs concerned for your safety.&lt;hpage&gt;I urge you to head their way now, beside the old bell, up and over.&lt;hpage&gt;A small settlement has formed there, and the bell, reawakened, seems to ward away the worst of the Citadel’s many dangers.&lt;page&gt;A settlement? In these long-haunted halls? Are you telling naughty little lies, dear one? Well, I suppose there’s not too much danger in going and seeing the truth for meself.</en>
    <zh>哎呀呀！还以为这鬼地方只剩我没发疯呢！看来我这只老婆子运气还没用完！&lt;hpage&gt;我能找到你可不只是运气使然，女士，我是受其他虫子所托来确保你的安全。请尽快前往上方那座古钟，同那些虫子会合。&lt;hpage&gt;那古钟周围形成了一个小型庇护所，重鸣的钟声似乎能驱散圣堡的大部分危险。&lt;page&gt;庇护所？在这闹鬼的圣堡？亲爱的，你在编故事吧？不过亲眼去看看也无妨~</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CITY_MERCHANT_SAVED_2">
    <en>Be away then, dear one, and leave me to gather up my trinkets and baubles.&lt;page&gt;If this settlement of yours truly has bugs settled safe, I’ll be able to make some lucrative trades. Blessings and farewell!</en>
    <zh>快走吧，亲爱的。别耽误我收拾我的宝贝货物。&lt;page&gt;要是你那庇护所真能安生做生意，老婆子我定能大赚一笔！愿你蒙福，再见！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CARETAKER_SNARE_OFFER">
    <en>It’s feelin’ almost time, eh, bellringer? You and her who waits up there. That fated meeting won’t hold forever... Ready to make your play, to oust one ruler and claim her place?&lt;hpage&gt;I’ll not deny some part of me desires that outcome... Dominance, it seems, is baked deep in my blood, as too, no doubt, for the one up top.&lt;hpage&gt;And yet, another part resists... A part, over time, I find myself siding with more...&lt;hpage&gt;That part wishes not to claim a monarch’s mantle, rather it would see my freedom regained, and this kingdom’s bugs unshackled from their pale chains.&lt;page&gt;...Remarkable idea you’re speakin’ there, bellringer, a world cut free. Not a wish I’ve had much cause to hope on, serious like... but I ain’t so surprised to hear you speak it.&lt;page&gt;For all your helpin’, I been seein’ it clearer. You’ve still got the monarch in you, alright, and the glare of a Weaver, but the ambition... that’s wild different from both.&lt;hpage&gt;If you have already guessed to my desire, sir, and share some part of it, would you offer me aid in the conflict to come?&lt;page&gt;Aye... Maybe, yes. I can barely bear to tell it... But there’s an idea, one rare discussed, for fear of her up there sensin’ the score.&lt;hpage&gt;You have conceived a method, I take it? A way to see a monarch... removed? And me left free from claiming her station?&lt;page&gt;...We have, me and what remains of my family. S’a trap, of a sort, beyond the skill of this Citadel, one to go further than just her binding. You’d be just the hunter to set it, if you’re dare enough to try...</en>
    <zh>时机快到了吧，敲钟者？你和顶上那位迟早要碰面……准备好推翻旧主，自己上位了吗？&lt;hpage&gt;一定程度上，我不否认自己渴求这样的结果……我的统治欲深植血脉，和顶上那位一样。&lt;hpage&gt;但另一部分的我在抗拒……而这一部分正变得愈发强烈……&lt;hpage&gt;不想戴上王冠，只盼重获自由，让这王国的虫民挣脱苍白的枷锁。&lt;page&gt;一个解脱束缚的世界……真是难以想象。我虽然不敢奢望，但从你嘴里说出来倒不意外。&lt;page&gt;看你四处救援，我也明白了。你确有君王的血统和织者的锋芒，但野心……和两者都截然不同。&lt;hpage&gt;先生，既然你已了解我的想法，可否在即将到来的纷乱中助我一臂之力？&lt;page&gt;啊……或许可以吧。我有一计……但这是一招险棋，鲜少被提及，唯恐被顶上那位察觉。&lt;hpage&gt;也就是说……你有能让我弑君并自由脱身的方法？&lt;page&gt;我们……我那残存的家族确实有个计划。那是一种陷阱，一种超越圣堡的陷阱。而你恰好能成为安放这个陷阱的猎手——如果你胆子够大的话……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CARETAKER_SWAMP_SOUL">
    <en>What’s that you got there, bellringer? Stole someone else’s soul for yourself?&lt;hpage&gt;You speak of the remnant I found in the muck-choked caves beside the Citadel? This is soul siphoned from a once powerful bug.&lt;hpage&gt;It’s only a thin mix now, but there is still some strength left. At peak, their talents must have been impressive.&lt;page&gt;Aye, they was that. I knew the bug, in ‘is prime, long time back. Braver’n most, and as little a fan of this Citadel as you yourself.&lt;page&gt;Went seekin’ alliance with those basic bugs of the swamps. Thought they’d both gain from the union... Scheming defiance, or some such stupidity!&lt;page&gt;Now he’s as dead as he was daft! Don’t go tryin’ ta make friends in Pharloom, bellringer. Nothin’ good comes of it.</en>
    <zh>敲钟者，你手里攥着什么？偷了谁的灵魂？&lt;hpage&gt;你是说我在圣堡旁边泥沼洞穴里找到的灵魂？这是从一只强大的甲虫身上剥离出来的。&lt;hpage&gt;虽然稀薄但尚存力量，全盛时期定非等闲之辈。&lt;page&gt;啊，没错！我认识那虫子，当年也算条好汉，而且跟你一样厌恶圣堡。&lt;page&gt;居然想联合沼泽平民搞叛乱！以为能互利共赢……真是蠢到家的反抗计划！&lt;page&gt;现在死得渣都不剩！所以说，在纺络交朋友准没好下场！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CARETAKER_BEAST">
    <en>Hmph. Bellringer, you might think me a dullard, but I understand this place and have well-good senses.&lt;page&gt;Brought here, weren’t you? From beyond the border of our lands?&lt;hpage&gt;You are correct. The one who waits atop this Citadel... Through their hospitality, I arrived in this kingdom. I seek now to return that welcome in kind.&lt;page&gt;Hmph. Beastly words, them. Finely spoken, but beastly all the same.&lt;page&gt;I just pray you don’t bring any more unneeded pain down on the heads of these gormless little pilgrims...</en>
    <zh>哼，敲钟者，别当我是蠢货。我对这地方算是知根知底，而且我的预感往往很灵验。&lt;page&gt;你是从纺络境外被“请”来的吧？&lt;hpage&gt;没错。圣堡顶端那位邀请我来到这个王国……盛情难却，现在轮到我回礼了。&lt;page&gt;冠冕堂皇的野兽做派！话说得再漂亮，骨子里还是透出兽性！&lt;page&gt;只希望你别再牵连这些呆头呆脑的朝圣者……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CARETAKER_SNARE_COMPLETE_PREPARE">
    <en>Found it all, did ya, bellringer? Then join me and let’s get to preppin’! I’ll be askin’ both your Silk and your claws ‘fore the construction.</en>
    <zh>找齐了是吧？那就快来搭把手！我需要你的灵丝和利爪参与构建。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="PILGRIM_SMALL_02">
    <en>The Citadel chose us, granted us a little more living. For what purpose though, who could say?</en>
    <zh>圣堡选择了我们，赏我们多活两天。谁知道是出于什么目的呢？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CARETAKER_SNARE_REPEAT">
    <en>If’n your wantin’ that trap made, you’d best get to collectin’. I’ll point you toward what’s needed, best as I can.</en>
    <zh>如果决定要把那个陷阱造出来，就快去收集所需的部分。我会告诉你需要做什么。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CARETAKER_MERCHANT">
    <en>Heard you did the savin’ for our dear merchant there? I’ve seen her about, sneaking and scrounging, even a’fore you was ringing that bell.&lt;page&gt;She’s a useful sort, but don’t let her age be foolin’, she’s still the sharpest mind for a deal.&lt;page&gt;Won’t be long till there’s nary a rosary about this shrine that ain’t found its way into her pockets.</en>
    <zh>听说你救了那个奸商？早在你敲钟之前，我就瞧见她在这儿鬼鬼祟祟扒拉破烂了。&lt;page&gt;别看她老，坑钱手段多着呢！&lt;page&gt;要不了多久，这附近的念珠全得进她腰包！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CARETAKER_SNARE_REOFFER">
    <en>Bellringer... Re-thinkin’ on that trap, are ya? It’s a mad method, for sure, but you’d be just the hunter to set it, if’n you’re dare enough to try...</en>
    <zh>敲钟者……有重新考虑过陷阱的事吗？这想法虽然疯狂，但对你来说最合适不过了……如果你胆子够大的话。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CARETAKER_SNARE_ACCEPT">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;Grant me your aid, sir. If your trap provides a path to freedom, both for myself and your land’s bugs, I may indeed choose to trigger it.&lt;hpage&gt;What work do you require of me now to see your service made?&lt;page&gt;It’s my family’s strength you’ll need be seeking, bellringer, us three ol’ bugs still alive, spread ‘cross this kingdom, and one poor cousin dead and drained in swamps choked rotten.&lt;page&gt;Each has power. Raw, savage stuff! For you, they’ll give it, if for their fascination at the act, or the thrill of defiance... or because they have no choice at all.</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;请助我一臂之力，先生。若你的陷阱真能为这片土地的虫子和我带来自由，我愿成为那个安放它的猎手。&lt;hpage&gt;现在需要我做些什么？&lt;page&gt;去召集我家族的力量——三个苟活的老家伙，他们分散王国各处。还有个可怜的表弟，他死在了腐臭的沼泽。&lt;page&gt;我的家人每个都带着野蛮原始的力量！他们会把力量交给你——或是出于对你这种勇气的欣赏，或是享受反抗带来的的亢奋……抑或是别无选择。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CITY_MERCHANT_ITEM_WARDKEY">
    <en>Real fine key this. No doubt it’ll open the way to somewhere special. Somewhere full of goodies, I’ll bet. Find the lock, and it’ll practically pay for itself!</en>
    <zh>上等货色！毫无疑问，它准能打开某个特殊地方的通路。我敢打赌，那地方肯定堆满了好东西。找到对应的锁，这钥匙就物超所值啦！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CARETAKER_DELIVERY">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;Caretaker, I bring supplies from the town of bells below the Citadel.&lt;page&gt;And badly needed they are, miss bellringer. Ain’t much finding or foraging happening with this mob, what with them choir types all stalkin’ about the chambers beside.</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;看守者先生，我从圣堡下方的钟心镇带了补给。&lt;page&gt;啊！真是雪中送炭！圣咏团在附近晃悠，这帮怂包根本不敢出去觅食。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CARETAKER_SNARE_REPEAT_BELLHERMIT">
    <en>Buried in the warren of bells, at Pharloom’s core, seek my sullen uncle. That one has power to spare.</en>
    <zh>去纺络的核心地带，在到处是钟的地方找我那阴沉的叔叔，他的力量多得没处使。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="PILGRIM_SMALL_01">
    <en>So you found this place too, sister? This Citadel’s grand promise has been strangled away by cursed thread, but at least the great bell here grants us some sanctuary.&lt;page&gt;We’re amongst the blessed few... granted just a little more living.</en>
    <zh>小姐，你也找到这个地方了啊？我们可真是走运。圣堡曾经的宏伟都因丝咒化为了泡影，但多亏了那座大钟，我们才能安全地待在这儿。&lt;page&gt;也许只是片刻安宁，但能多活一会儿……但在这病怏怏的鬼地方，多活片刻就是最好的福报了。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CITY_MERCHANT_REPEAT">
    <en>Off you go now, dear one. If it’s my trinkets you covet, you can trade me your rosaries up at the shrine. Blessings and farewell!</en>
    <zh>你该走了，亲爱的。如果你想要我的这些宝贝，就来钟殿用念珠跟我换！愿你蒙福，再见！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="PILGRIM_GENERIC_ACT3_REPEAT">
    <en>Ooohh... If we’re no longer pilgrims... What are we?</en>
    <zh>噢……我们如果不再是朝圣者了……那会成为什么呢？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CITY_MERCHANT_ITEM_TOOLMETAL">
    <en>Crafty types used to go all a’clamour for this metal. S’not much to look at, but I still remember its value.</en>
    <zh>当年被工匠们抢破头的金属材料。看着不起眼，但老婆子我记得它可金贵着呢。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CARETAKER_MEET_1">
    <en>Oi! You there!</en>
    <zh>喂！那边的！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CARETAKER_MEET_REPEAT">
    <en>This shrine, awakened... it calls out to ‘em, you see. “It’s safe here. Come on over!” ringing in the ears of every lost pilgrim and grubby so-and-so unlucky enough to have made it to this blasted Citadel with their wits intact.&lt;page&gt;Well, what’s done is done, and what’s rung is rung. Just make sure you come back here soon, you lout! I ain’t dealing with all the fresh intake myself!&lt;hpage&gt;If time permits, sir bug, I shall visit again. </en>
    <zh>只要这钟殿醒着，那些迷途的朝圣者和肮脏的食腐者就会收到召唤。&lt;page&gt;就像在那些家伙耳边低语“这里安全，快来！”，然后他们就会屁颠屁颠地涌向这座被诅咒的城堡。&lt;page&gt;事已至此，你最好尽快回来帮忙！我可不想独自应付这些新来的蠢货！&lt;hpage&gt;先生，若有空闲，我会再来。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CARETAKER_SNARE_DECLINE">
    <en>Guess I shouldn’t be surprised. It’s a fool act to try such a thing... Maybe even to think on it. Your kind ain’t designed to die.</en>
    <zh>果然还是有所顾虑吗？企图弑君本就是蠢行……或许连想都不该想。你们这一族的命数本就不包括死亡。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CARETAKER_SNARE_ACCEPT_SNARE">
    <en>For the last part, I’ll also be needin’ that rune setter you’re carryin’. Clever old Weaver tool, that thing, and the perfect base on which to stretch our power.&lt;page&gt;Once you’ve collected for yourself the other critical parts, I’ll ask you pass it over as well.</en>
    <zh>最后还需要你身上那个陷阱设置器。精巧的织者工具，正好可以用来作为我们陷阱的基底。&lt;page&gt;等你集齐了其他部分，就把这玩意也交给我。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CARETAKER_SNARE_REPEAT_SWAMP">
    <en>Find the husk of my cousin, claimed by the scorned bugs of the swamps. A careless fool to let himself be taken, and dead they might be, but some glimmer of his soul can still be sensed.</en>
    <zh>找到我表弟的躯壳，它被沼泽中满怀怨愤的虫子占据了。他粗心大意，才会被抓住并害死。但我仍能感受到他灵魂散发的的一丝微光。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CARETAKER_SNARE_COMPLETE_PRE">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;Sir, I have the items requested. Craft me your trap that we may see these lands free.</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;先生，所需物品已集齐。请为我制作陷阱，还此地自由。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CITY_MERCHANT_MEET_AFTERBRIDGE">
    <en>T’was a good deed you did up above, dear one, saving me from them screeching flocks. Not seen the like of it in a long, long time.&lt;page&gt;I’ve returned with all sorts of new goodies, too. Let’s see if anything I’ve scavenged will fit your fancy.</en>
    <zh>亲爱的，多亏你把我从那些可怕的家伙手上救了出来。我好久遭遇过那样的危险了。&lt;page&gt;我还带了各种各样新鲜的好东西回来。来看看我搜罗到的货物有没有合你心意的。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CARETAKER_WISHES_PROGRESS">
    <en>Don’t think I ain’t see’in it, bellringer! A whole lotta helpin’ you’ve been up to, both here and down below!&lt;page&gt;S’a strange mantle you’re takin’ for yourself, seeing all them bugs saved and wishes promised.&lt;hpage&gt;You find it strange, sir? I’ve found some solace in the service, and the rewards received have proved a boon on my journey.&lt;page&gt;Aye! But it ain’t your place now, is it? I see well what you are, Weaver’n more! It’s below your station! You ain’t no common sort meant for carin’ on us low folk.&lt;hpage&gt;I could say the same for you, who still chooses to remain cowled. You continue to pose as only a simple pilgrim. Don’t you think it’s past time you ceased the performance?&lt;page&gt;Leave off, Old One! Permit a bug their small disguise! It’s been a pleasant thing to play simple. And I weren’t calling for change, even if you seem insistent on bringing it!&lt;hpage&gt;Change was unavoidable, sir, whether I arrived or not. The monarch stirs. Its threads stretch far. My presence only accelerates the inevitable.&lt;page&gt;So what’re you hopin’ for, eh? Planning to usurp, to perch above us all as queen? Build up our hopes only to string us all in your own beastly web? Such is the way of Weavers and gods both...</en>
    <zh>敲钟者！别当我没看见！你在这里和下层当活菩萨呢！&lt;page&gt;披着救世主的皮，到处行侠仗义，很别扭吧？&lt;hpage&gt;先生觉得我别扭？帮助其他虫子让我获得了某种慰藉。当然，获得的报酬也能助我前行。&lt;page&gt;呵！可这不是你该干的！我看得出来，你有织者血统！屈尊来操心我们这些贱民的死活，太掉价！&lt;hpage&gt;那你扮成普通朝圣者，不也是在演戏？是时候摘掉伪装了吧？&lt;page&gt;该死！就不能让我活个清净吗？安安静静的普通日子不好过吗？非得去寻求变革！&lt;hpage&gt;变革不可避免，无论我来与否。圣堡之主已然有所行动，其丝线已遍及全境。我的到来不过是加速了这过程。&lt;page&gt;所以你到底图什么？想夺权篡位，成为新的女皇？先点燃我们的希望，然后再把我们困入网中？你们织者和神灵都这副德行……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CARETAKER_LV3_MEET">
    <en>You keep at all that helpin’, you’re gonna start inspiring it in others! Best you think serious about what effect you might be causin’, bellringer!&lt;page&gt;Too much hope could prove a dangerous thing, ‘specially for all these bugs starved so long of it.</en>
    <zh>敲钟者！你再这么当救世主，其他虫子都要学样了！你最好想清楚这样会引发什么后果！&lt;page&gt;让浑浑噩噩几辈子的虫子看到希望——这是非常危险的！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CITY_MERCHANT_SAVED_BRIDGE_2">
    <en>Now, why don’t you hurry back to the shrine and let them all know what a good job you’ve done?&lt;page&gt;There might be a few more goodies to gather up on my way back, and I don’t need you lingering around in the meantime. Blessings and farewell!</en>
    <zh>现在，快回去替我报平安吧！&lt;page&gt;我这会儿可没法跟你一块回去，路上可能还有好东西等着我捡漏呢。愿你蒙福，再见！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CITY_MERCHANT_ITEM_SIMPLEKEY">
    <en>Simply forged, and simply styled. Designed to open all sorts of different locks, if they be basic enough.</en>
    <zh>锻造工艺粗糙，样式也朴素。但能打开各种不同的锁——只要锁芯别太复杂。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="PILGRIM_STANDARD_MEET">
    <en>Sister, sister! Let me confide in you! As I ascended the Citadel’s chambers to reach this place, I swear I heard the laughter of a child!&lt;page&gt;Wasn’t much more than an echo, and I confess me fear’s been playing awful tricks on me... and yet that voice still keeps ringing in my head.&lt;page&gt;Surely though, no bug so young and lively could survive within those heartless halls?</en>
    <zh>小姐！你且听我说！在圣堡殿堂上来此地的路上，我分明听到了幼虫的嬉笑声！&lt;page&gt;肯定是回声作祟，要么就是我吓出幻觉了……但那笑声一直在我脑子里萦绕。&lt;page&gt;这鬼地方哪可能有活着的幼虫？你说对吧！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="PILGRIM_LARGE_SK_SAVED_ACT3_MEET">
    <en>Sister, you seen ‘em out there? Our new champion, that golden knight stalking the Citadel’s crumbling halls?&lt;page&gt;Tall, righteous bug. Not much for conversing. Still! I’d be long dead if not for their appearance.&lt;page&gt;And I ain’t the only one. Others have spoken of the knight’s timely deeds and rare bravery.&lt;page&gt;We’re desperate for any protection we can get, and that gleaming champion’s been offering their aid almost as much as you yourself.</en>
    <zh>嘿，小姐，瞧见没？那位在圣堡摇摇欲坠的大厅里巡逻的金甲骑士！&lt;page&gt;高大正直，威风凛凛，不太爱说话。不过！要不是他，我早没命了！&lt;page&gt;不光是我！好多朝圣者都说曾被他及时搭救。&lt;page&gt;现在大伙就指望你和那位英雄护着咱了。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CITY_MERCHANT_RUMMAGE_REPEAT">
    <en>If you’re going to keep skulkin’ around here while I work, you may as well buy something. Take a look dear one, don’t be shy!</en>
    <zh>如果你打算在我干活的时候一直偷偷摸摸地在这儿晃悠，那你还不如找我买点东西。来看看吧，亲爱的，别害羞！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CARETAKER_SNARE_ACCEPT_NO_SNARE">
    <en>And last, as the base, seek a weapon of Weavers past. Should still be one left, down there in their largest nest, a snare to set a rune’o searing Silk. Our own trap’ll be woven tight about it.</en>
    <zh>最后是陷阱的基底部分，去找到古织者的工具——陷阱设置器，它可以用来设下灼烧灵丝的符文。&lt;page&gt;应该还剩一个，就在织者最大的巢穴里。我们的陷阱将以它为核心进行制作。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CARETAKER_MEET_3">
    <en>Admit it! You done it! You shifty li’l bell-runger!&lt;hpage&gt;You have chosen a curious place to rest, sir. Do you perhaps know something of this shrine and its companions in the lands below?&lt;page&gt;Oh, so you ask funny questions as well as cutting bells free, eh? You certainly ain’t a pilgrim, but you’re clearly not of the Choir either. No! I know exactly what you are...&lt;page&gt;A bell-ringing lout! A weirdo! Don’t you realise what you’ve done, waking that shrine back up?&lt;page&gt;That bell has rung out far and wide! The wretched and the lost will have heard its call. They’ll be making their way here now.&lt;page&gt;Well, what’s done is done, and what’s rung is rung. Just make sure you come back here soon, you lout! You can help me deal with all the dirty little pilgrims and desperate scavengers who turn up.</en>
    <zh>承认吧！就是你干的！你这莽撞的敲钟者！&lt;hpage&gt;先生，你选了个有趣的地方歇脚。莫非知晓这处钟殿与下方各处钟殿的关联？&lt;page&gt;哈！又会问怪问题又会乱敲钟，既非朝圣者也不像圣咏团……我算看明白了——&lt;page&gt;你就是个扰我清梦的怪胎！知道唤醒这座钟殿会引来什么吗？&lt;page&gt;迷途的朝圣者和食腐者都会循钟声而来！&lt;page&gt;事已至此，你最好尽快回来帮忙对付那些脏兮兮的家伙！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CARETAKER_SNARE_COMPLETE_PRE_CANCEL">
    <en>Oi! What’s this? Suddenly havin’ second thoughts? For sure it’s a frightful thing to attempt, but you’ve already put in all the leg work!&lt;page&gt;She up top’ll already be sensin’ your goal, vague-like maybe, but there ain’t no worth to backin’ out now.</en>
    <zh>喂！这就反悔了？虽然这计划确实骇人，但你都已经走到这一步了！&lt;page&gt;顶上那位早就隐隐约约地感应到了你的企图，现在退缩太迟了！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CITY_MERCHANT_ITEM_SPOOLEXTEND">
    <en>Stretch a spool out nice and long with this fine-wrought tool. The perfect purchase if you’re planning to hoard a lot of Silk for yourself!</en>
    <zh>这件制作精良的工具能拓展你的灵丝轴容量。如果你打算为自己囤积大量灵丝，这件绝对是必买！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CARETAKER_WISHES_PROGRESS_REPEAT">
    <en>You keep at all that helpin’, you’re gonna start inspiring it in others! Best think serious about what effect you might be causin’, bellringer!&lt;page&gt;Too much hope could prove a dangerous thing, ‘specially for all these bugs starved so long of it.</en>
    <zh>你再这么当救世主，其他虫子都要学样了！最好想清楚这样会引发什么后果！&lt;page&gt;让浑浑噩噩几辈子的虫子看到希望，这是非常危险的！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="PILGRIM_GENERIC_ACT3_MEET">
    <en>Ooohh... What new horror now besets us?&lt;page&gt;Is this fresh punishment for our sins, or yet another test to prove our faith?&lt;hpage&gt;It is neither, good bug. In this disaster you bear no blame.&lt;hpage&gt;Hold close to your companions, and I will work swift to see this madness stilled.</en>
    <zh>噢……现在又是什么新的灾祸降临到我们头上了？&lt;page&gt;这是对我们罪孽的报应，还是又一次考验我们信仰的试炼？&lt;hpage&gt;都不是。在这场灾厄中，你并无任何过错。&lt;hpage&gt;别离开你的同伴，我会尽快让这场狂乱平息下来。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CARETAKER_SNARE_REPEAT_SNARE">
    <en>For the base, we’ll be needin’ a weapon of Weavers past. Search down low, aside the paths of bone, inside their largest nest. S’a snare device, one to set a rune’o searing Silk.</en>
    <zh>陷阱的基底部分需要用到一件古织者的工具——可以设下符文的陷阱设置器。往底层搜寻，就在满是骨头的道路旁，织者最大的巢穴里。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="PILGRIM_STANDARD_REPEAT">
    <en>I swear I heard it, sister... That laugh! It almost sounded like they were enjoying themself...</en>
    <zh>小姐，我真没幻听……那笑声……听着像是它们在嬉戏玩乐一样……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CITY_MERCHANT_ITEM_NEEDOLIN_TOOL">
    <en>Hold this while makin’ music and you’ll soon hear its function. Amplifies song, it does! Sends it out full and bright. Ideal if you’re ever planning on performing for a crowd.</en>
    <zh>演奏时握着这件宝贝，你就能很快体会到它的作用。它能放大乐声，让声音饱满又响亮。要是你打算登台表演，这东西再合适不过了</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CITY_MERCHANT_ITEM_ROSARYSTRING">
    <en>How about we get your loose beads all strung up safe? I’ll pinch a few for their braiding, but that’s surely worth it for the peace of mind.</en>
    <zh>我来帮你把零散的念珠穿起来，做成便携的链子怎么样？收点手工费不过分吧？图个心安嘛！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CITY_MERCHANT_RUMMAGE_GRAND_FORUM">
    <en>Ooh, I’m glad I wriggled my way over here! What a bounty’s been laid out by our benefactors, those generous Conductors! Giants amongst bugs they are, all-seeing and kind!&lt;page&gt;It’s beautiful here, and goodies are everywhere. Only enough for one though, deary, so don’t be greedy! You know I got here first. Blessings, and farewell! </en>
    <zh>啊哈！幸亏我一路摸到这儿来了！咱们的恩主——慷慨的指挥家们，可真是留下了丰厚的赏赐啊！他们全视全知，又心地善良！&lt;page&gt;这儿可真美，到处都是好东西。不过嘛，亲爱的，这些东西只够我拿哦，所以别贪心！你该懂得先来后到。愿你蒙福，再见！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="PILGRIM_LARGE_MEET">
    <en>You stay close, sister. Them halls beside are crawling with haunted husks.&lt;page&gt;Wandering will only bring death, pointed and painful!</en>
    <zh>小姐，你跟紧点。旁边的那些大厅里到处都是被丝咒附身的躯壳。&lt;page&gt;四处乱走只会带来痛苦的死亡。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CARETAKER_WARD">
    <en>Have you done it yet, bellringer? Wriggled deep? Discovered the depths of obsession that brought this place so low?&lt;hpage&gt;If you speak of this Citadel and its Silk, Caretaker, then yes, I now know the start of it. &lt;hpage&gt;In the ward down below, I saw it clear, the hollowed husks, and the many torturous implements... machines to instill a bug with thread, that would see their life extended.&lt;page&gt;Aye! That’s it, in part! But there’s more scale to it than all that. Just think of’em greedily shoving the Silk into their shells, the madness that overcame them, eternal life for mortal bugs! Then think on how long it’s all gone on...&lt;hpage&gt;...The children born of them, and all the pilgrims after... The Silk has seeded deep into this kingdom’s shells, generations deep...&lt;hpage&gt;No wonder Pharloom’s bugs proved such easy prey for that haunted thread. It had only to seek for itself to reach them.&lt;page&gt;Ho ho! Now you’re seein’ it, bellringer! These poor pilgrims, all born bound to the cruel system of our world, now stricken in its new cursed web.&lt;page&gt;You at least are free from it. And free to shake it all up... if’n that’s your choosing.</en>
    <zh>事情办成了吗，敲钟者？找出那些让圣堡堕落的疯狂执念没？&lt;hpage&gt;若是指圣堡的丝咒，是的，我已知晓其根源。&lt;hpage&gt;下层病房里尽是空壳，以及无数刑具般的器械……那些向甲壳灌注丝线延续生命的机器。&lt;page&gt;没错！但远不止如此！想想他们贪婪吞食灵丝的模样，凡虫妄图永生引发的癫狂！再想想这持续了多少世代……&lt;hpage&gt;……他们的子嗣，后来的朝圣者……灵丝早已深植于这个王国的甲壳内，代代相传……&lt;hpage&gt;难怪纺络的虫子会轻易沦为丝咒的猎物，那些邪丝只需稍加引诱就能侵蚀他们。&lt;page&gt;哈！现在你算看透了！这些可怜虫生来就被束缚在这个世界的残酷体制里，如今又陷进新的诅咒之网。&lt;page&gt;至少你是自由的，自由得足以颠覆这一切……若这是你的选择。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CITY_MERCHANT_SAVED_BRIDGE_1">
    <en>Well, well, if it isn’t my very own shadow, the clever little red-cloak! You still following me around, trying to pinch away some of the goodies I sniff out?&lt;hpage&gt;You mistake my intent, ma’am, somewhat ungenerously. The pilgrims of the settlement below were worried by your long absence. It was on their behalf that I tracked you, again.&lt;page&gt;Is that so? What a worrying bunch of busybodies they are! I’m still able to fend for meself!&lt;page&gt;Hmph... and yet, perhaps ‘tis a warm thing that I remain in their thoughts so. I hadn’t expected that. And I can’t deny that you too have done me a good turn once more.&lt;page&gt;That awful flock almost had me, truth be told, and I still have to wonder at your intentions, dear one... but bless you, all the same!</en>
    <zh>啧啧，这不是小红斗篷嘛！还在惦记着老婆子我找到的的宝贝？&lt;hpage&gt;女士，你误会了。是庇护所的虫子们担心你的安危，我才再次前来找你。&lt;page&gt;是这样吗？瞎操心！老婆子我纵横圣堡的时候他们都还是虫卵呢！&lt;page&gt;不过……被惦记的感觉倒也不坏。这次算我又欠你一份情。&lt;page&gt;说实话，那群可怕的家伙差点就抓住我了，而你……不管怎样，还是要感谢你！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CITY_MERCHANT_RUMMAGE_LIBRARY">
    <en>Looking for goodies of your own, dear one? You’d do well to avoid the dark vaults near here. They say the keepers inside were jealous hoarders even before the silken curse came down.&lt;hpage&gt;You have more familiarity with the Citadel than most, madam. How long have you spent here, surviving amongst the haunted corridors?&lt;page&gt;Oh, long enough. S’not such a bad lot, all told. The memories of my pilgrimage have all faded now, but a life spent in the Citadel’s golden halls was all I ever wished for.&lt;page&gt;And lo and behold, my humble wish was granted! Certainly, the place might be a bit past its prime, but it’d be churlish of me to complain now, wouldn’t it?</en>
    <zh>亲爱的，你也在找好东西吗？你最好避开这附近阴暗的书库。据说在丝咒降临之前，里面的管理员就已经是些抠门的守财奴了。&lt;hpage&gt;女士，你比大多数虫都更熟悉圣堡。这被诅咒的地方生存，肯定也不是件易事吧？你在这儿待了多久了？&lt;page&gt;唔，待了有够久了。总的来说，也不算太差。当初朝圣时的记忆如今已经模糊，但在这金色圣堡度过一生，这就是老婆子我的毕生所求。&lt;page&gt;你瞧啊，我这小小的愿望已经实现啦！当然，这地方或许已经过了鼎盛时期，但现在要是我还抱怨，那就太不识好歹了，不是吗？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CITY_MERCHANT_ITEM_SHELL_FRAGMENT">
    <en>Part of an ancient mask, or a fractured shard of someone’s visage? With the full thing, you’d be better able to protect your shell. </en>
    <zh>古老面甲的一部分？还是谁的面部残片？要是能凑齐整套，肯定能更好地保护你的甲壳。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CITY_MERCHANT_MEET_ACT3">
    <en>What a calamity has befallen our holy Citadel! I ain’t never seen anything like it in my long life.&lt;page&gt;Times like this, we must be sure to help each other. Dig deep, dear one, I’ll be needing a lot of rosaries to survive what’s comin’!</en>
    <zh>圣堡这次真是大难临头了！老婆子我活了这么久，这阵仗还是头回见！&lt;page&gt;这种时候，我们一定要相互帮助。帮帮忙，亲爱的，为了挺过即将到来的难关，我需要很多念珠！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CARETAKER_LV2_MEET">
    <en>All your work, and look! They keep arrivin’. It’s bugs aplenty up here now. Hapless, weak, but alive they are!&lt;hpage&gt;More scared than weak, they seem to me. It is heartening knowing these few have survived safe for your care.&lt;page&gt;That’s your work, bellringer! Not mine. Ringin’ and helpin’! Hope they recognise your efforts, ‘cause I ain’t providing much, and I ain’t one for fighting if that Choir and their pins ever come callin’.</en>
    <zh>全是你折腾的后果！现在这儿挤满虫子了！又蠢又弱，畏畏缩缩地苟活！&lt;hpage&gt;更像是吓坏了，才显得羸弱。还得多亏有你在这儿照顾他们。&lt;page&gt;喂！别跟我扯上关系！这都是你干的好事，敲钟者！我可不会帮忙打架——要是圣咏团找上门，你自己扛！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CARETAKER_REPEAT">
    <en>Here they limply lay, the castaways and the disillusioned and the used-up.&lt;page&gt;It’s a sorry settlement you’ve summoned, miss bellringer, and a blasted bother for me. Not sure we have anything to offer ‘em... Not even hope.</en>
    <zh>看看这些疲惫的虫子，不是漂泊一生，就是失去信念。&lt;page&gt;敲钟者小姐，你搞出来的这个避难所真是大麻烦，我还得伺候这帮难民……我们连丁点希望都给不起。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CITY_MERCHANT_SHOP_REPEAT">
    <en>Stop and share some of your rosaries before you go scurrying off again, dear one. I’m sure to have something that’s to your liking!</en>
    <zh>亲爱的，先别走，用你的念珠跟我做点小生意再离开也不迟呀。我这儿有各式各样的好货，绝对物超所值！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CITY_MERCHANT_ITEM_SPOOLPIECE">
    <en>Half a spider’s spool. You’d just have to find its match. Them ol’ Weavers built some fine things alright. They’re all long dead, but their craftwork still gleams bright. </en>
    <zh>织者的半个灵丝轴，你只需要找到与之匹配的另一半。古织者的手艺真不赖，虫死了这么多年，其造物还锃光瓦亮。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CITY_MERCHANT_ITEM_WALLCLING">
    <en>A gleaming find for you climbing types. With this in your claw, you’ll be able to stick to walls for as long as you like!</en>
    <zh>对于你们这些攀爬爱好者来说，这可是个不可多得的宝贝。握在爪子里就能无限黏附峭壁——想挂多久挂多久！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CARETAKER_SNARE_REPEAT_CHURCHKEEPER">
    <en>Down in the mosslands, still clinging to her failed chapel, my sister’ll part with her power, if asked kind enough.</en>
    <zh>去苔地找我那守着破教堂的姐姐，态度客气点，她或许会分给你力量。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CARETAKER_SNARE_ACCEPT_SWAMP_SOUL">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;Grant me your aid, sir. If your trap provides a path to freedom, both for myself and your land’s bugs, I may indeed choose to trigger it.&lt;hpage&gt;What work do you require of me now to see your service made?&lt;page&gt;It’s my family’s strength you’ll need be seeking, bellringer, us three ol’ bugs still alive, spread ‘cross this kingdom, and that sad soul you’re already carryin’ there, the last of my poor cousin, dead and drained in those rotten swamps.&lt;page&gt;Each of my family has power, raw, savage stuff. For you, they’ll give it, if for their fascination at the act, or the thrill of defiance... or because they have no choice at all.</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;请助我一臂之力，先生。若你的陷阱真能为这片土地的虫子和我带来自由，我愿成为那个安放它的猎手。&lt;hpage&gt;现在需要我做些什么？&lt;page&gt;去召集我家族成员的力量——三个苟活的老家伙，他们分散王国各处。还有一个正是你已找到的这悲惨灵魂的主人，他是我可怜的表弟，死在了腐臭的沼泽。&lt;page&gt;我的家人每个都带着野蛮原始的力量！他们会把力量交给你——或是出于对你这种勇气的欣赏，或是享受反抗带来的的亢奋……抑或是别无选择。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CARETAKER_LACE_DEFEATED">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;Sir, I have opened the way above these halls, and bested the white knight that stood as guardian.&lt;hpage&gt;Child of the monarch, she claimed herself at the end, and her shell suggested it true, a being born purely from Silk woven tight. &lt;hpage&gt;That such a feat is possible... I have seen life woven from Silk before, but tiny, transient... Never like this...&lt;page&gt;Aye, bellringer! You’ve slain a marvel indeed... Well, flawed marvel, at least.&lt;page&gt;One to keep far from she was, least for us mortal sorts. Look of a child and a mind to match, but her’s been up wanderin’ this Citadel longer’n most. Even in its long silence, way ‘fore you came and roused its ire. &lt;page&gt;Might’a seen herself this place’s protector, keepin’ it clean and quiet as she did. Course quiet meant most crossin’ her path found a painful end from her pin.&lt;page&gt;I’d be sayin’ thanks for the slaying, but with all the other husks now awoken and enraged, a bug’s chances ain’t grown by much.</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;先生，我已打通上层通路，击败了守卫的白骑士。&lt;hpage&gt;她自称君主子嗣，其甲壳构造显示此言非虚——纯粹由致密灵丝编织。&lt;hpage&gt;如此造物真是超乎寻常……灵丝编织的生命我倒也见过，但都渺小且残缺。和她相比，简直天差地别……&lt;page&gt;哈！敲钟者，看来你宰了个神迹一般的家伙……好吧，至少是个有瑕疵的神迹。&lt;page&gt;一直以来，对于我们来说，都是离她远点为妙。她长得孩童模样，心智也相仿，却已徘徊在圣堡多年——早在你到来并激怒她之前。&lt;page&gt;她自诩圣堡守护者，清扫所有“不洁者”。凡是靠近的都成了其针下亡魂。&lt;page&gt;本该谢谢你除掉她，但现在其他空壳都被唤醒并激怒了……咱们的处境可没变好。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CITY_MERCHANT_MEET">
    <en>Hello again, dear one. Looks like we both made it up here, safe as told. And what a shock to find you were speaking the truth about this place!&lt;page&gt;A settlement like this in the Citadel, nice and safe, cloistering so many bugs with minds intact! Never seen anything like it, nor even imagined such.&lt;page&gt;Makes trading away all of my nice bits and baubles much easier. After all, I want to take lots and lots of rosaries with me when my strength finally fails!</en>
    <zh>又见面啦，亲爱的。看来咱俩都如预想的那样平安到达这儿了。真没想到你说的这个地方居然是真的！&lt;page&gt;在这圣堡里有这么一处庇护所，既舒适又安全，还住着这么多心智健全的虫子！我从没见过这样的地方，连想都没想过会有。&lt;page&gt;在这儿做点小买卖可容易多啦！毕竟，等我老得不行的时候，我想带上好多好多念珠，风光下葬呢！</zh>
  </entry>
</sheet>