<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<sheet name="Forge">
  <entry key="BALLOW_CONTROL_KEY">
    <en>Ho, miss! How’s all this then? Lotta dials to be trackin’, but at least the controls seem in good order.&lt;page&gt;From here, I can guide your bell down, best as any bug.&lt;page&gt;&lt;hpage&gt;Then you’ve no prior experience with this type of transport?&lt;page&gt;No one does, miss! Them’s who used to dive’re all long dead, or cursed ta half life. An’ there ain’t no bug left alive’s been brave or stupid enough to try... ‘til now, at least.&lt;page&gt;I’ll work it best’s I can. Can’t do much more, I’m afraid. At least the forgings of these docks were built to last. Now we’s only gotta pray they hold for you.&lt;page&gt;Here’s the key that’ll see you inside its metal belly. Pop in there once you’re feelin’ good and ready. In the meantime, I’ll get to seeing things set up here.</en>
    <zh>嚯，小姐！这玩意儿够复杂的！仪表盘多得数不过来，好在操控装置还算正常。&lt;page&gt;我能在这儿引导潜钟下潜，保准比任何虫子都靠谱。&lt;page&gt;&lt;hpage&gt;这么说，你从没操作过这种器械？&lt;page&gt;谁都没这种经验，小姐！以前开潜钟的早死绝了，剩下的也半死不活。活着的虫里，就没有哪个又疯又蠢的敢用这玩意……直到现在。&lt;page&gt;我会尽力而为，但别的可不敢打包票。好在码头造的这家伙够结实，现在只能祈祷它下潜后不会出什么故障。&lt;page&gt;这是这个大铁肚子的钥匙。等你准备好了就钻进去。我这就去把装置整备妥当。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FORGE_DAUGHTER_ACT_3_WHITE_FLOWER_REPAIR_UNSEEN">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;Forge Daughter, I have acquired a power that will enable me to end this black madness. Soon I will act to stop the quakes and save this land.&lt;page&gt;Excellent, pointy bug. Your drive, and your vigour, both have proven surprisingly large for one so small.&lt;page&gt;Know we have heard from Ballow, who told of his repair efforts upon the diving bell below. By now, that task is likely completed.&lt;page&gt;If you are hoping to put his work to the test, then we shall wish again on your survival. And if our own service can aid your critical task, know we will continue to provide it gladly.</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;熔炉之女，我已获取终结这场黑灾所需的力量。终结动荡、拯救这片地区就在此一举。&lt;page&gt;啧，好家伙！小尖头虫，没想到你个头不大，魄力和干劲倒是真不小。&lt;page&gt;听巴洛说，他底下那口老破钟修得差不多了。这会儿多半已经完工。&lt;page&gt;想试试那家伙的成果？那咱还得再一次祝你好运。要是咱这熔炉里的功夫能帮上忙，甭客气，照旧伺候着！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="LADY_BUG_DEPLETED_A">
    <en>Erm, you may notice your prize there is a little light, my lady...&lt;page&gt;Awful truth is, you’ve cleaned us out. We’ve not a single measly rosary left between us. Turns out we were just no match for you!&lt;hpage&gt;It was a game fairly played, sir, though I’ve no wish to see you destitute. Would you like to make another kind of wager, perhaps?</en>
    <zh>呃，您可能会觉得这次的奖品有点寒酸，女士……&lt;page&gt;实话说，您把我们家底都赢光了。半颗念珠都不剩！我们根本不是您对手！&lt;hpage&gt;先生，游戏确实公平公正，但我也不想见你倾家荡产。要不要换个赌注？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BALLOW_DIVING_BELL_PT2">
    <en>Grfff... So it’s gotten that bad, aye? I guess... If that’s how it is, I’ll be your bug.&lt;page&gt;Meet me below, at the diving bell. We’ll see if I can get you ready for the drop.</en>
    <zh>&lt;page&gt;嘶……已经糟到这地步了？行吧……如果真是这样，那我帮你。&lt;page&gt;去潜钟底下碰头，我看能不能给你整备好。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="DIVING_BELL_POST_INSPECT">
    <en>Holler when you’re ready, miss. The upgrades are done. That bell’s as ready as it’ll ever be.</en>
    <zh>准备好了就喊我一声，小姐。升级已经完成，这只潜钟现在状态绝佳。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BALLOW_SAUNA_REPEAT">
    <en>Ahhh... Can you feel it yet? All your troubles dripping away...</en>
    <zh>啊哈……感觉到了吗？烦心事都在随着汗液滴落……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FORGE_DAUGHTER_CANCEL_NOMETAL">
    <en>The deposits around here, those long-burning rocks. They’re useful to the Citadel, in whatever their shadowy business, but useless if you require tools of us!&lt;page&gt;We need finer material. Rare metal. Pharloom would provide a bounty to the able explorer. Find us some, and we’ll build your violent aids.</en>
    <zh>储备在附近的长效燃烧石？圣堡那帮虫子拿去搞些见不得虫的勾当倒合适，对我们来说屁用没有！&lt;page&gt;去找些更好、更稀有的金属！只要你有本事，纺络遍地都是是宝贝。找着了，我们就有办法给你造那些家伙什。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="LADY_BUG_CHALLENGE_FINAL_END">
    <en>Ola, ola! Our lady has missed her mark, and so thusly ends our challenge!</en>
    <zh>哎哎！这位女士脱靶了，挑战结束！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BALLOW_DIVING_BELL_ABYSS_BLACK">
    <en>...iss...istake...erwhelm...retrie...a...ssible...</en>
    <zh>……错……错误……过载……无法……打捞……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="LADY_BUG_DECLINED">
    <en>My lady, I pray you reconsider! T’would be an honour to see those strong limbs of yours in action, truly!</en>
    <zh>女士，再考虑考虑吧！要是能见识到您矫健的风姿，定会是我们的荣幸！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="LADY_BUG_CHALLENGE_FINAL_POOR">
    <en>A respectable enough effort, truly. You didn’t earn enough rosaries to make a profit off us, but that should only spur you on to try again!</en>
    <zh>表现非常不错！虽然赚的念珠还不够回本，或许正好能激励您再试一次！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="DOCK_KEY_RECEPTICLE_INSPECT">
    <en>An old diving bell. Its door is shut tight by an ornate clamp.</en>
    <zh>一具古旧的潜钟，钟门被一只华丽的夹钳紧紧锁闭。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BALLOW_REPAIR_REPEAT">
    <en>The diving bell’ll be ready again soon, miss. Once this new shield-shell is fitted, it’ll surely withstand the drop!.. Surely!</en>
    <zh>潜钟很快就能再用，小姐。新护壳装好后绝对能扛住下坠！绝对！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BALLOW_DIVING_BELL_ABYSS_REPEAT">
    <en>...tract...annot...ap...en...epair...orry..iss...</en>
    <zh>……牵引……无法……修理……抱歉……小……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="LADY_BUG_ACCEPTED_3">
    <en>Ola, ola, time to play! Take these straight pins and strike the target when you see it!</en>
    <zh>哎哎，游戏要开始咯！拿好这些掷针，见靶就扎！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BALLOW_DIVING_BELL_TO_BENCH_REPAIRED">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;Sir, I require a moment. Please unlock the bell for me.&lt;page&gt;Aye. Can do, miss. Hail me again when you’re ready to travel.</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;巴洛先生，我还需要点时间。麻烦打开钟门。&lt;page&gt;没问题，小姐。等您准备妥当了，再喊我一声就行。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BALLOW_SAUNA_MEET">
    <en>Here to sweat away your sorrows, miss? The steam does wonders for a mind set sullen, or a shell gone stiff.&lt;hpage&gt;I’ve found these lowlands hot enough already, and mine is a shell more resilient than most.&lt;hpage&gt;To challenge that further seems a unique sort of madness.&lt;page&gt;Aye, well, this is Pharloom, miss! Madness is catching. I’d say this here’s the smallest form of it.</en>
    <zh>有烦心事吗，小姐？来蒸桑拿吧，蒸汽对郁结的心绪或僵硬的甲壳有奇效。&lt;hpage&gt;我倒觉得这里已经够热了，何况我这副甲壳比多数虫子都硬实。&lt;hpage&gt;热上加热，怕不是疯得别致。&lt;page&gt;哎，这儿可是纺络，小姐！疯病是会传染的。要我说，在这蒸桑拿算最轻的症状了。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="LADY_BUG_DEPLETED_REPEAT">
    <en>What an honour it was to play with you, my lady! I hope you’ll think of us whenever you feel those rosaries rattling around in your pockets.</en>
    <zh>与您同乐实乃荣幸！希望您摸着兜里的念珠时能想起我们。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="DIVING_BELL_TO_BENCH_INSPECT">
    <en>Cancel Descent?</en>
    <zh>取消下潜？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FORGE_DAUGHTER_ACT_3_START_FIRST_MEET_2">
    <en>There is no choice! Not for us. We cannot leave, not ever. We are a Forge Daughter, fixed to this forge and its service. Ours is a duty lifetime bound.</en>
    <zh>没得选！从来就没得选。咱是熔炉之女，生来就和这熔炉缔结了契约。使命在身，至死方休。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FORGE_DAUGHTER_DIVING_BELL_REPEAT">
    <en>If you’re planning passage below, Ballow’s the one to assist you. We must remain by the forge, always.</en>
    <zh>若想下潜，去找巴洛帮忙。咱得永远守着熔炉。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FORGE_DAUGHTER_ACT_3_START_FIRST_MEET_1">
    <en>Oh! Pointy bug, why do you bother us at our work? The world cracks and quakes to some grave new calamity, surely you should seek somewhere safer?&lt;hpage&gt;As far as I might flee, I suspect no such place exists, and in any case, I would not see this land’s bugs abandoned to their end.&lt;hpage&gt;What of you? Why do you choose to remain so diligent at your task, given the fell state of your lands?</en>
    <zh>哟！小尖头虫，干嘛打扰咱干活？外面又闹起什么灾祸，搞得地动山摇，你该找个安全地儿躲躲才对啊？&lt;hpage&gt;恐怕无论逃到哪里，都无处可避。更何况，我不愿抛下此地生灵，让它们无力地面对终结来临。&lt;hpage&gt;你们呢？既然明白此地危在旦夕，为何还要死守这熔炉？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FORGE_DAUGHTER_MEET_1">
    <en>Oh! Small pointy bug, why do you bother us at our work?&lt;hpage&gt;The sound of your craft called me to investigate. What is your duty here? Are you a smith of some kind?</en>
    <zh>嘿！小尖头虫，干嘛打扰我们干活？&lt;hpage&gt;你们的锻打声引我前来。你们在这儿做些什么？可是铁匠？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="LADY_BUG_ACCEPTED_1">
    <en>Ola, ola, time to play! Take these straight pins and strike the target when you see it!&lt;page&gt;If you can strike the target fifteen times, the prize is yours!</en>
    <zh>哎哎，游戏要开始咯！拿好这些掷针，见靶就扎！&lt;page&gt;击中靶子十五次，奖品就是您的！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FORGE_DAUGHTER_MEET_2">
    <en>A smith? Hardly so crude! We are Forge Daughter! How can a pointy bug not tell?&lt;page&gt;Ours is the ancient line and honoured role. These docks and lands around are fortunate to have our skills.&lt;hpage&gt;If you are as talented as you suggest, would you lend me your aid? I’ve lacked for my usual tools, and I suspect you could craft fine replacements.&lt;page&gt;Blades and traps, no doubt? We know your type!&lt;hpage&gt;Of sorts, but maybe strange to this land? Some would likely prove fine challenge for your craft.&lt;page&gt;Hmph! Then we’ll construct them. But! You’ll provide the materials, and compensation for our time.</en>
    <zh>铁匠？太掉价了！我们可是熔炉之女！你竟然不认识我们？我们祖传的手艺让整个深坞都沾光！&lt;hpage&gt;若你们的技艺真如你所夸耀那样好，可否帮我个忙？我的一些工具没有了，我想你们应该能打造合用的替代品。&lt;page&gt;要做刺针还是陷阱？你这种客人我见多了！&lt;hpage&gt;有些可能是你没见过的款式，对你们的工艺应该是不小的挑战。&lt;page&gt;哼！那咱就造出来给你看。但材料你得自备，工钱也得结清。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="LADY_BUG_ACCEPTED_2">
    <en>Ola, ola, time to play! Take these straight pins and strike the target when you see it!&lt;page&gt;If you can strike the target twenty-five times, the prize is yours!</en>
    <zh>哎哎，游戏要开始咯！拿好这些掷针，见靶就扎！&lt;page&gt;击中靶子二十五次，奖品就是您的！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="LADY_BUG_REST">
    <en>Well, perhaps that’s enough games for now, eh?&lt;page&gt;We’ll need to come up with a much trickier challenge to best you, my lady!</en>
    <zh>好吧，我想就先玩到这里为止？&lt;page&gt;我们得琢磨个更刁钻的挑战才能赢过您，女士！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FORGE_DAUGHTER_ACT_3_REPEAT">
    <en>This world may not have long, but we shall face its end still delivering our duty.</en>
    <zh>这世界或许时日无多，但咱就算直面末日也要把活干完。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FORGE_SHARD_POUCH_DESC">
    <en>To maintain one’s tools is a constant task. These shards should be kept close when you travel, that you can repair and replenish as the need arises.</en>
    <zh>保养工具需要持之以恒。旅程中应当随身携带这些碎片，以便随时进行修理和补充。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BALLOW_CONTROL_REPEAT">
    <en>Pop inside the diving bell once you’re feelin’ good and ready. In the meantime, I’ll get to seeing things set up here.</en>
    <zh>这是这个大铁肚子的钥匙。等你准备好了就钻进去。我这就去把装置整备妥当。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FORGE_ITEM_STING_SHARD_DESC">
    <en>A vicious stabbing trap? We can build it. Just know, it disturbs us, these devious implements you conceive to kill.</en>
    <zh>带尖刃的陷阱是吧？能造。但你得知道，我们可不喜欢鼓捣这些阴险的杀戮工具。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="LADY_BUG_OFFER">
    <en>Ola, ola! Welcome, my lady, so glad you found us here! I can see you’re blessed with strong limbs and keen sight.&lt;page&gt;Fond of frolics are you? Keen to test your aim? We’d be right honoured to play a little game with you. A little test of skill we’ve set up.&lt;hpage&gt;I’ve no need to test my skills, sir, nor do I have time for frivolities.&lt;page&gt;Oh, but we’d make it worth your while! A prize awaits you, if you can meet our challenge!&lt;hpage&gt;If you offer a prize, that changes matters. I can meet any challenge if the reward is sufficient. What are the rules of your game?&lt;page&gt;Exceedingly simple, my lady! I’ll provide the pins for throwing, and my associate will provide a target. Hit the target fifteen times and you’ll earn yourself a worthy prize!</en>
    <zh>哎哎！欢迎大驾光临！真高兴您找到这儿！一看您就是肢强目锐的虫。&lt;page&gt;喜欢玩游戏吗？要不要来试试准头？我们设计了个小游戏，可以考验您的技巧。&lt;hpage&gt;先生，我无需试炼技艺，更无空闲嬉闹。&lt;page&gt;别呀！奖品丰厚着呢！只要完成挑战，奖品就是您的！&lt;hpage&gt;既然有奖品，倒可以尝试。只要奖励足够丰厚，任何挑战都能接受。游戏规则是什么？&lt;page&gt;简单至极！我将为您提供掷针，我的伙计会提供靶子。击中靶子十五次，奖品就归您了！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="KNIGHT_LOCK_INSPECT">
    <en>A heavy door chained with a simple padlock.</en>
    <zh>一扇厚重的门扉，挂着一只简易挂锁。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="DOCK_KEY_RECEPTICLE_HINT">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;This bell could carry me below, but it will first require a key, and an operator to aid its descent.&lt;hpage&gt;I cannot complete this task alone. Someone upon these docks will have to assist me.</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;此钟可载我下沉，但需要钥匙开启，还需要操作员协助下潜。&lt;hpage&gt;我自己难以达成此事，需要得到码头上某位清醒者的帮助。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BALLOW_GENERIC_ACT3">
    <en>Oi! What’s with all these tremors? This smelt still need shovelling, and the shakes’re only making it harder.</en>
    <zh>啊喂！这震天动地的，到底是怎么回事？晃荡个没完，还让不让干活了？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FORGE_DAUGHTER_DIVING_BELL_TALK_FIRST_SHOP_ACT_3">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;Though tied by charge, would you provide me your service, Forge Daughter? I have need of tools that your skills could likely provide.&lt;page&gt;Blades and traps, no doubt? We know your type!&lt;hpage&gt;Of sorts, but maybe strange to this land? Some would likely prove fine challenge for your craft.&lt;page&gt;Hmph! Then we’ll construct them. But! You’ll provide the materials, and compensation for our time.</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;熔炉之女，你们虽有使命在身，但可否为我打造些工具？你们的手艺应该能胜任。&lt;page&gt;要做刺针还是陷阱？你这种客人我见多了！&lt;hpage&gt;差不多，有些可能是你们没见过的款式，对你们的工艺应该是不小的挑战。&lt;page&gt;哼！那咱就造出来给你看。但材料你得自备，工钱也得结清。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BALLOW_DIVING_BELL_TO_TRAVEL_UP">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;Sir, I need to return above. Please ready the bell for me.&lt;page&gt;Aye, miss. Sit on the bench, and let’s get you hauled up.</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;巴洛先生，我需要返回地面。请准备上浮。&lt;page&gt;好嘞，小姐。坐稳扶牢，这就把你拽上来。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="LADY_BUG_CHALLENGE_FINAL_WIN">
    <en>Quite a lot of targets struck, and quite a lot of rosaries earned! Our lady never fails to impress us!</en>
    <zh>击中了非常多目标，念珠赚得盆满钵满！女士，您总能让我们大开眼界！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="LADY_BUG_CHALLENGE_FAILED">
    <en>Ola, ola! Have to stop you there. That’s three times now you’ve missed your mark! I’m afraid that makes you the loser of our little game, with all due respect.&lt;page&gt;Fret not though, for we never tire of playing! Step over here, and we can start another game.</en>
    <zh>哎哎！得叫停啦。您已脱靶三次！恕我直言，这局算您输。&lt;page&gt;没关系，我们的游戏永远欢迎您！请移步这边来，我们再开一局。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="DIVING_BELL_TO_BENCH_INSPECT_ASCEND">
    <en>Cancel Ascent?</en>
    <zh>取消上浮？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FORGE_LAVA_CHARM_DESC">
    <en>This trinket is our own invention. It wards against the deadly lava and heat around these docks. The workers used to request them of us. Now they’ve lost the mind to care.</en>
    <zh>这宝贝可是我们的独家发明，可以用来抵御深坞致命的熔岩与高温。往日工虫们争相求购，如今它们却连心智都已涣散。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FORGE_DAUGHTER_CANCEL_HASMETAL">
    <en>Farewell, then. If you require our craft, this forge is always hot.</en>
    <zh>慢走不送，需要造东西的话随时过来。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BALLOW_CONTROL_POST_REPEAT">
    <en>The new shell-shield’s all bolted on tight, miss. If you’re planning another descent, head down, holler, and I’ll get you where you’re goin’.</en>
    <zh>我把新护壳加固得很严实，小姐。如果你打算再下潜一次，就下来喊一声，我会帮你启程。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FORGE_DAUGHTER_TALK_2">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;The behaviour of your fellow workers, I’ve seen similar... agitation upon the roads. These docks are not alone in the strangeness of their occupants.&lt;page&gt;’Tis odd behaviour to be sure, but not for Ballow and us to know. Ours is busy work, and we keep to ourselves.&lt;page&gt;Whatever the goings on of the world outside, no bother to us, as long as our craft can continue.</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;你同僚的这般行径，我在路上也见过类似的……狂躁。这码头的住民并非孤例。&lt;page&gt;这种行为确实奇怪，但我们和巴洛可懒得深究。我们只管埋头干活，少管闲事。&lt;page&gt;外头天塌地陷都与我们无关，只要这门锻造手艺能传下去就行。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FORGE_DAUGHTER_TALK_3">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;How did you come to serve these docks, Forge Daughter?&lt;page&gt;Sent from our Forgehome we were, at request of those holy bugs above.&lt;hpage&gt;The Citadel dwellers? The veiled bugs? They ordered you here?&lt;page&gt;Yes! An age ago that. Such is duty! We Forge Daughters live to hone the craft, and aid the line.&lt;page&gt;By the Citadel’s patronage, and our long duty upon these docks, our Forgehome would swell in holy esteem.</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;熔炉之女，你们为何来此码头效力？&lt;page&gt;是上头那些圣虫召我们来的，我们在熔炉乡收到了调令。&lt;hpage&gt;圣堡的住民？那些覆面虫？是他们下令调遣你们来这儿的？&lt;page&gt;正是！都是陈年旧事了。职责所在嘛！我们熔炉之女活着就为磨砺手艺，延续传承。&lt;page&gt;靠着圣堡的庇佑和在这些码头长年累月的苦工，熔炉乡的名望自会愈发神圣。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FORGE_DAUGHTER_TALK_1">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;I’d expected this workshop too would contain only combative types, but you seem composed, Forge Daughter.&lt;page&gt;You’ve met the workers? They’re all wound up! They still work at their tasks, in a simple way, but they’re useless for conversation. It’s only ourselves and young Ballow with any sense left.</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;我原以为这工坊里全是些好斗之徒，但你们倒是沉着清醒，熔炉之女。&lt;page&gt;见过那些工虫没？个个跟上了发条似的！它们没日没夜机械式地干活，但早就不会聊天了。如今只剩咱和那边的巴洛还保留着些清醒。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BALLOW_CONTROL_POST_MEET_NO_REPAIR_SEEN">
    <en>Miss! Errr... Ullo... I see you’ve survived... somehow... Thought that last plunge must’a been your end.&lt;hpage&gt;It was not. I survived the fall, and managed a treacherous return.&lt;hpage&gt;For the diving bell’s failure, the risks were clear to me. The fault lies not with you.&lt;page&gt;Aye! As you say! This bell’s old. And time has a way of breaking things even as fine forged as this.&lt;page&gt;And see below, for its failure I’ve been workin’ hard at improving the design! Your last journey ended up being a valuable test... ahem.&lt;hpage&gt;Good. That return path is long closed to me, and your bell is now needed again.&lt;page&gt;Again? We’ll if you’re game enough to try a second time... A shell-shield’s been fitted, and the bell’s like new. Better’n new!&lt;page&gt;If you’re planning another descent, head down, holler, and I’ll get you goin’.</en>
    <zh>小姐！呃……那个……你居然还活着……真行啊……我以为那趟下潜准要了你的命。&lt;hpage&gt;还好，坠落时侥幸生还，又爬过险路回来。&lt;hpage&gt;潜钟故障本在意料之中，错不在你。&lt;page&gt;没错！你说得对！这钟老掉牙了。再好的锻造也经不起岁月折腾。&lt;page&gt;你瞧，因为这次事故，我已经在改进设计了！权当这回是一次有价值的测试……咳。&lt;hpage&gt;很好。从湖底回来的路已经行不通了，若我再次下潜仍需用到此钟。&lt;page&gt;还来？你要真有胆量再试……护壳已经装好了。现在这只潜钟跟全新的一样！不，比新的还强！&lt;page&gt;如果你打算再下潜一次，就下来喊一声，我会帮你启程。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BALLOW_DIVING_BELL_TO_TRAVEL">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;Sir, I am ready. Please prepare the bell for departure.&lt;page&gt;S’time to take the plunge, aye, miss? Just sit on the bench, and I’ll see you strapped in tight.</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;巴洛先生，我已就绪。请准备下潜。&lt;page&gt;好嘞，小姐，跳水时间到了。在椅子上坐稳，我来给你捆严实咯。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="DOCK_KEY_RECEPTACLE_INSPECT_DEMO">
    <en>An old mechanism with a keyhole.</en>
    <zh>一个带钥匙孔的老旧机关。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BALLOW_CONTROL_POST_MEET">
    <en>It’s done, miss! I’ve fitted the shell-shield. Bell’s like new. Better’n new even!&lt;page&gt;If you’re planning another descent, head down, holler, and I’ll get you goin’.&lt;hpage&gt;Your work is appreciated, sir. Know that, with luck, the threat from below might soon be quelled, and your lands shall rest calm.&lt;page&gt;Well... Good! I’m only really wishin’ to return to the forge, and my regular duties... A little purpose, routine...&lt;page&gt;Frankly, miss, all this action’s more’n a bit overwhelming for bugs like me. I’ll be glad when it’s all over... Providing we survive, of course.</en>
    <zh>搞定啦小姐！护壳装好了。现在这只潜钟跟全新的一样！不，比新的还强！&lt;page&gt;如果你打算再下潜一次，就下来喊一声，我会帮你启程。&lt;hpage&gt;辛苦你了。若是运气好，下面的威胁很快便会平息，此地也能重回安宁。&lt;page&gt;那敢情好！我只盼着早日回熔炉干回老本行……有点奔头，按部就班……&lt;page&gt;说真的，小姐，这种大场面对我这种小虫子来说太刺激了。等这一切都结束后，我们……当然，前提是我们能活下来。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BALLOW_REPAIR_MEET">
    <en>Miss! Errr... Ullo... I see you’ve survived... somehow... Thought that drop must’a been your end.&lt;hpage&gt;It was not. I survived the fall, and managed a treacherous return.&lt;hpage&gt;For the diving bell’s failure, the risks were clear to me. The fault lies not with you.&lt;page&gt;Aye! As you say! This bell’s old. And time has a way of breaking things even as fine forged as this.&lt;page&gt;And you can see here, for its failure I’d already been workin’ at improving the design! Ended up being a useful test... ahem.&lt;hpage&gt;Good. That return path is now closed to me, and your bell may still be needed if I choose to descend again.&lt;page&gt;Again? Well, if you’re game enough to try a second time...Once this new shield-shell is fitted, it’ll surely withstand the drop!.. Surely!</en>
    <zh>小姐！呃……那个……你居然还活着……真行啊……我以为那趟下潜准要了你的命。&lt;hpage&gt;还好，坠落时侥幸生还，又爬过险路回来。&lt;hpage&gt;潜钟故障本在意料之中，错不在你。&lt;page&gt;没错！你说得对！这钟老掉牙了。再好的锻造也经不起岁月折腾。&lt;page&gt;你瞧，因为这次事故，我已经在改进设计了！权当这回是一次有价值的测试……咳。&lt;hpage&gt;很好。从湖底回来的路已经行不通了，若我再次下潜仍需用到此钟。&lt;page&gt;还来？你要真有胆量再试……等新护壳装好，保准能扛住下坠！绝对没问题！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FORGE_DAUGHTER_MEET_2_DEMO">
    <en>A smith? Hardly so crude! We are Forge Daughter! How can a pointy bug not tell?&lt;page&gt;Ours is the ancient line and honoured role. These docks and lands around are fortunate to have our skills.&lt;hpage&gt;If you are as talented as you suggest, would you lend me your aid? I’ve lacked for my usual tools, and I suspect you could craft fine replacements.&lt;page&gt;Blades and traps, no doubt? We know your type!&lt;hpage&gt;Of sorts, but maybe strange to this land? Some would likely prove fine challenge for your craft.&lt;page&gt;Hmph! Then soon, yes! I may accept. But not now! Now there is much work to be done, and we cannot afford to be bothered so.</en>
    <zh>铁匠？太掉价了！我们可是熔炉之女！你竟然不认识我们？我们祖传的手艺让整个深坞都沾光！&lt;hpage&gt;若你们的技艺真如你所夸耀那样好，可否帮我个忙？我的一些工具没有了，我想你们应该能打造合用的替代品。&lt;page&gt;要做刺针还是陷阱？你这种客人我见多了！&lt;hpage&gt;有些可能是你没见过的款式，对你们的工艺应该是不小的挑战。&lt;page&gt;哼！那行，你过阵子再来！咱会造出来给你看！这会儿活儿太多，咱忙不过来！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FORGE_DAUGHTER_DIVING_BELL_TALK_FIRST_MEET">
    <en>Oh! Small pointy bug, why do you bother this Forge Daughter at their work?&lt;hpage&gt;These black quakes that wrack your lands, I am seeking to see them quelled at their source, below the lakes of flame.&lt;page&gt;You would wish to descend so deep?... It is true these docks possess the means. Alas, we ourselves cannot help. Whether Pharoom’s health or fall, our charge ties us to this forge, always.&lt;page&gt;Ballow there’s the bug to ask, and if our fate is as dire as your action suggests, we are sure he is only needing of some quick convincing.</en>
    <zh>嘿！小尖头虫，干嘛打扰我们熔炉之女干活？&lt;hpage&gt;&lt;hpage&gt;如今黑灾震动大地，我想深入熔岩湖之底，将其从源头平息。&lt;page&gt; 小尖头虫，你想潜那么深？……码头那边倒是有法子能办到。&lt;page&gt;唉，可惜咱帮不上忙。不管纺络是死是活，咱都得守着这熔炉。&lt;page&gt; 去找码头那边的巴洛吧。若局势真如你所说那般危急，你随便吓唬两句他就会服软。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FORGE_DAUGHTER_REPEAT_DEMO">
    <en>Return later, pointy bug! Now there is much work to be done, and we cannot afford to be bothered so.</en>
    <zh>过阵子再来，小尖头虫！眼下正忙着呢，少添乱！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FORGE_DAUGHTER_ACT_3_WHITE_FLOWER">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;Forge Daughter, I have acquired a power that will enable me to end this black madness. Soon I will act to stop the quakes and save this land.&lt;page&gt;Excellent, pointy bug. Your drive, and your vigour, both have proven surprisingly large for one so small.&lt;page&gt;We shall remain here, still. If our service can aid your critical task, know we will continue to provide it gladly.</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;熔炉之女，我已获得终结黑灾的力量。很快便将行动，平息震动，拯救此地。&lt;page&gt;干得好，小尖头虫。你这小身板里的劲头倒是大得出奇。&lt;page&gt;咱还会守在这儿。若咱这手艺能助你成事，尽管开口便是。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FORGE_DAUGHTER_ACT_3_SHOP_ REPEAT">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;Stay safe, Forge Daughter. If I require your aid, I shall return.&lt;page&gt;Our wishes go with you, pointy bug. Calm the raging of our world, that our task can continue.</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;保重，熔炉之女。若是需要帮助，我自会再来。&lt;page&gt;祝你好运，小尖头虫。平息这外头的狂乱，咱才能继续安心干活。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="DOCK_DIVING_BELL_CONTROLS_HINT">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;These controls are complex. If I’m to descend within the bell below, I will first require an operator.&lt;hpage&gt;Someone upon these docks will have to assist me.</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;此操控装置颇为复杂。若想要乘潜钟下潜，需要有操作员协助。&lt;hpage&gt;需要得到码头上某位清醒者的帮助。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BALLOW_DIVING_BELL_TO_TRAVEL_DOWN">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;Sir, I wish to depart. Please ready the bell for travel.&lt;page&gt;Sure thing, miss. Sit on the bench, and I’ll send you down.</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;巴洛先生，我可以出发了。请整备好潜钟。&lt;page&gt;好嘞，小姐。在椅子上坐稳，我这就送您下潜。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="LADY_BUG_REOFFER">
    <en>Interested in our little game, my lady?&lt;page&gt;If you can hit the target fifteen times you’ll earn yourself a worthy prize!</en>
    <zh>对我们的小游戏感兴趣吗，女士？&lt;page&gt;击中靶子十五次，奖品就归您了！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FORGE_DAUGHTER_ACT_3_START">
    <en>Oh! Pointy bug, you return? Our world cracks and cries from some grave new calamity.&lt;page&gt;Nevertheless, we must remain, fixed to this forge and its service. Ours is a duty lifetime bound.</en>
    <zh>&lt;page&gt;嘿！小尖头虫，你回来了？外面又闹起什么灾祸，搞得哭天抢地的。&lt;page&gt;不过无所谓，咱还得守着熔炉干活。使命在身，至死方休。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BALLOW_GENERIC">
    <en>If you need something, talk to the boss. I’m busy.</en>
    <zh>有事找老板说去。我正忙着呢。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="DOCK_DIVING_BELL_CONTROLS">
    <en>A control panel with various levers and gauges.</en>
    <zh>布满操纵杆与仪表的控制台。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BALLOW_DIVING_BELL_PT1">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;Sir, I have need to head below the lakes of flame.&lt;hpage&gt;There is a diving bell at the base of this structure that seemed fit for the task. I require it opened, and an operator to send it deep.&lt;hpage&gt;As one of few upon these docks with mind still sound, that role must fall to you.&lt;page&gt;Can’t you see I’m busy, miss? Ain’t got time for naught else while the shovelling needs doing.&lt;hpage&gt;Choose to aid me, or all your efforts will soon be wasted. This kingdom crumbles. Its collapse is inevitable. If you wish for your work, and your life to continue, you must help me, now.</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;先生，我需要潜入熔岩湖之下。&lt;hpage&gt;此建筑底部有座潜钟可用。我需要把它打开，并有个操作员送我下沉。&lt;hpage&gt;如今码头清醒者寥寥无几，此事只能由你来办。&lt;page&gt;没看我正忙吗，小姐？眼下铲矿石的活还干不完呢。&lt;hpage&gt;这王国正在崩塌，覆灭无可避免。你不帮我，就等着一切辛劳付诸东流。若你还想活命，还想每天有活干，就立刻帮我。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BALLOW_DIVING_BELL_PT1_BELL_UNSEEN">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;Sir, I have need to head below the lakes of flame. Can you aid me in this task?&lt;hpage&gt;&lt;page&gt;Hmmm... Well if you head down below to the very base of the docks, there’s an old diving bell built for just what you’re askin’. &lt;page&gt;Thing is, you can ride it, but it takes an operator stood dockside to send it. I might be capable, but I ain’t got time for naught else while the shovelling still needs doing.&lt;hpage&gt;Choose to aid me, sir, or all your efforts will soon be wasted. This kingdom crumbles. If you wish for your work, and your life to continue, you must help me, now.</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;先生，先生，我需要潜入熔岩湖之下。能否请你助我一臂之力？&lt;hpage&gt;&lt;page&gt;唔……如果您是往深坞最底层去，那边倒是有口老潜钟专门干这活的。&lt;page&gt;可这玩意儿需要有另一只虫在地面操作才能下水。我虽然会弄，但眼下铲矿石的活儿堆成山，实在没闲工夫管别的啊。&lt;hpage&gt;这王国正在崩塌。你不帮我，就等着一切辛劳付诸东流。若你还想活命，还想每天有活干，就立刻帮我。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="LADY_BUG_OFFER_PROMPT">
    <en>Start Challenge?</en>
    <zh>开始挑战？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BALLOW_DIVING_BELL_TALK_PRE_POST_MEET">
    <en>Oi! Who’sat? Whoever’s down there, if you’re feelin’ mad enough to try and travel, best meet me up at the controls, and we can chat.</en>
    <zh>喂！谁在那儿？不管你是谁，如果想要下潜，最好来操控台找我聊聊。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FORGE_DAUGHTER_POST_ABYSS">
    <en>Well. Well. Still alive! You have proved yourself made of the hardiest stuff, pointy bug.&lt;page&gt;Ballow did tell, shamefully, of complications with your diving bell, and of your absence upon its retrieval.&lt;page&gt;He had feared you lost to the flame, but we ourself had slight guessed otherwise.&lt;hpage&gt;To return from below proved as difficult a climb as ever I have faced, and yet, in time near, I will need to descend again.&lt;page&gt;Then twice mad you are, bug! Or brave beyond measure. We shall wish on your continued survival, even if you seem intent on ending it.</en>
    <zh>啊哈！瞧瞧这是谁还生龙活虎的！小尖头虫，你可真是命硬。&lt;page&gt;巴洛支支吾吾地交代了潜钟的意外——打捞起来后，你已经不见了。&lt;page&gt;他以为你被火焰吞噬了，但咱倒隐约觉得不然。&lt;hpage&gt;从底下爬回来确实是个不小的挑战，但很快我又得再下去一趟了。&lt;page&gt;哈！？你这虫子，不是疯到顶了就是勇到没边了！尽管你像在自寻死路，咱还是祝你多活些时日。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="LADY_BUG_REOFFER_2">
    <en>The frolics haven’t ended, my lady! If you’d like to really test yourself, we should play again!&lt;page&gt;Hit the target twenty-five times and you’ll earn yourself a beautiful necklace of rosaries! What say you?</en>
    <zh>游戏还没完全结束，女士！想真正挑战自己一把吗？再来一局如何？&lt;page&gt;击中靶子二十五次，这条精美的念珠项链就是您的！意下如何？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FORGE_DAUGHTER_TALK_REPEAT">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;Keep well, Forge Daughter. I shall return if I require your aid.&lt;page&gt;Yes! Or no. Either is fine by us, as long as the craft continues.</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;保重，熔炉之女。若是需要帮助，我自会再来。&lt;page&gt;行！不来也行。只要手艺没断，咱都没意见。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="LADY_BUG_IN_CHALLENGE">
    <en>Hesitate not, my lady! Take aim and throw true!</en>
    <zh>别犹豫，女士！瞄准了就狠狠地扎过去！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FORGE_ITEM_TOOL_KIT_DESC_EXPAND">
    <en>If you add the implements from this set to your own, the quality of your crafting will increase. You will produce finer, sharper, and deadlier tools... if that is your wish.</en>
    <zh>若将此套器具与你的工具结合，你的制作水准将更上一层楼。你将打造出更精、更利、更致命的器械……只要你想。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FORGE_ITEM_TACKS_DESC">
    <en>Planning to lay a carpet of spikes? These would surely slow your prey. We’d never have considered using such common tools for combat.</en>
    <zh>用布满尖刺的毯子让敌人减速？如此普通的工具还能在战斗中应用，我们可从没想到过。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="LADY_BUG_DISQUALIFIED">
    <en>Ola, ola, ola! Perhaps I neglected to tell you not to cross past those markers? It’s a law of the game, and we all abide by laws here, don’t we?&lt;page&gt;Your actions have disqualified you, my lady, but we harbour no ill will! Step over here and we can begin a new round at once!</en>
    <zh>哎哎！我可能忘了告诉您别越过那个标记？游戏规矩总得遵守，对吧？&lt;page&gt;您犯规出局，但我们之间绝不会因此产生芥蒂！请移步这边来，我们马上新开一局。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="LADY_BUG_CHALLENGE_WIN_1">
    <en>Ola, ola! That’s it then. Our lady has struck the target fifteen times! A beautiful victory!&lt;page&gt;Hopefully you enjoyed yourself! A little levity is a balm in these troubled times, don’t you think?&lt;hpage&gt;I’d have thought such games best saved for times of peace, but perhaps there is truth in what you say.&lt;hpage&gt;And now that I have bested your challenge, you will produce the prize I have earned?&lt;page&gt;Oh... o-of course! I see you have a tool pouch of your own there. Full to bursting with baubles and trinkets, no doubt!&lt;page&gt;I’ll fit another pocket onto it, so you can carry even more tools and shards with you. A fair prize, wouldn’t you say?</en>
    <zh>哎哎！成了！这位女士成功击中靶子十五次，完美胜出！&lt;page&gt;玩得开心吧？在这病怏怏的世道里找点乐子也算是良药，您说是不是？&lt;hpage&gt;我原以为这类游戏该留在太平年月，但或许你说的也有道理。&lt;hpage&gt;现在我已完成挑战，是否该兑现奖品了？&lt;page&gt;当……当然！我看您自带工具袋，里面准是塞满了各种零碎小玩意！&lt;page&gt;我给您的工具袋上加个新口袋，能多装点工具。这奖品公道吧？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="LADY_BUG_REOFFER_3">
    <en>Ola, ola! We’ve devised a final challenge for you, my lady, if you’re interested.&lt;page&gt;Hit the target as many times as you can without missing. The more targets you hit, the more rosaries you’ll win from us! Care to try?</en>
    <zh>哎哎！我们给您准备了终极挑战，女士！&lt;page&gt;连续击中靶子次数越多，赢取的念珠越多！敢试试吗？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FORGE_DAUGHTER_WEAVERSHOT">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;Forge Daughter, within an old Weaver nest I discovered a weapon. Though much damaged by age, I believe your skills could see it restored.&lt;page&gt;Ho. An impressive tool that, and a fine challenge. We can reforge the weapon, if the price fits.</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;熔炉之女，我在一处古老织巢中发现了这件武器。虽年代久远损毁严重，但以你们的手艺应该能修复。&lt;page&gt;嚯，好东西！这活儿够意思，只要报酬合适，咱就帮你重铸。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FORGE_DAUGHTER_PURCHASED">
    <en>A fair exchange made, pointy bug. Now our work calls. Return again if you find need of our trade and talent.</en>
    <zh>交易愉快，小尖头虫。眼下我们的活儿还多着呢，有需要再来。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FORGE_DAUGHTER_ACT_3_REPEAT_BALLOW_LEFT">
    <en>We hope Ballow serves you well, pointy bug. In our long time serving these docks, he’s the finest assistant we’ve found.</en>
    <zh>希望巴洛能帮上忙，小尖头虫。在码头干了这么多年，他是咱见过最得力的助手。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="DIVING_BELL_TO_TRAVEL_INSPECT_ASCEND">
    <en>Ascend?</en>
    <zh>上浮？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FORGE_DAUGHTER_ACT_3_WHITE_FLOWER_REPAIR_AND_FORGE_UNSEEN">
    <en>Well. Well. Still about, pointy bug! You have proved yourself made of the hardiest stuff.&lt;page&gt;Ballow did tell, shamefully, of complications with your diving bell, and of your absence upon its first retrieval.&lt;page&gt;He had feared you lost to the flame, but we ourself had slight guessed otherwise.&lt;hpage&gt;To return from below proved as difficult a climb as ever I have faced, and yet I now need to descend again.&lt;page&gt;Then twice mad you are, bug! Or brave beyond measure.&lt;page&gt;Know we have heard from Ballow, who told of his repair efforts upon the diving bell below. By now that task is likely completed.&lt;page&gt;If you are hoping to put his work to the test, then we shall wish again on your survival. And if our own service can aid your critical task, know we will continue to provide it gladly.</en>
    <zh>啊哈！瞧瞧这是谁还生龙活虎的！小尖头虫，你可真是命硬。&lt;page&gt;巴洛支支吾吾地交代了潜钟的意外——打捞起来后，你已经不见了。&lt;page&gt;他以为你已经葬身火海了，但咱倒隐约觉得不然。&lt;hpage&gt;从底下爬回来确实是个不小的挑战，但很快我又得再下去一趟了。&lt;page&gt;哈！？你这虫子，不是疯到顶了就是勇到没边了！&lt;page&gt;听巴洛说，他底下那口老破钟修得差不多了。这会儿多半已经完工。&lt;page&gt;想试试那家伙的成果？那咱还得再一次祝你好运。要是咱这熔炉里的功夫能帮上忙，甭客气，照旧伺候着！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="LADY_BUG_CHALLENGE_FINAL_FAIL">
    <en>And not a single target was struck... a right shame, that! We can’t reward you with any rosaries, my lady, but we’d love to see you test your aim once more!</en>
    <zh>一次都没中……太可惜啦！我没法给您念珠，女士，但欢迎随时再来试试准头！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FORGE_SILSHOT_DESC">
    <en>A weapon from a long distant past. We can combine the Weaver components with our own mouldings to repair the tool.</en>
    <zh>远古时期遗留下来的武器。可以将织者的部件与我们自造的铸件结合，修复这件工具。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FORGE_DAUGHTER_DIVING_BELL_TALK">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;Forge Daughter, these black quakes that now wrack your lands, I am seeking to see them quelled at their source, below the lakes of flame.&lt;page&gt;You wish to descend so deep, pointy bug?... It is true these docks possess a craft capable.&lt;page&gt;Alas, we ourselves cannot help. Whether Pharloom’s health or fall, our charge ties us to this forge, always.&lt;page&gt;Ballow there’s the bug to ask, and if our fate is as dire as your action suggests, we are sure he is only needing of some quick convincing.</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;熔炉之女，如今黑灾震动大地，我想深入熔岩湖之底，将其从源头平息。&lt;page&gt; 小尖头虫，你想潜那么深？……码头那边倒是有法子能办到。&lt;page&gt;唉，可惜咱帮不上忙。不管纺络是死是活，咱都得守着这熔炉。&lt;page&gt; 去找码头那边的巴洛吧。若局势真如你所说那般危急，你随便吓唬两句他就会服软。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="FORGE_ITEM_TOOL_KIT_DESC">
    <en>Crafting by claw alone produces inferior results. With this kit, you can craft finer, sharper, and deadlier tools... if that is your wish.</en>
    <zh>单凭你的肢爪，只能造出粗劣的工具。有此匣相助，你便可打造更精、更利、更致命的器械……只要你想。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="DIVING_BELL_TO_TRAVEL_INSPECT">
    <en>Descend?</en>
    <zh>下潜？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="LADY_BUG_LEFT_IN_CHALLENGE">
    <en>My lady, you left our game in such a hurry! No doubt some task of great import pulled you away.&lt;page&gt;That’s an instant disqualification, of course. You understand. But we don’t hold it against you, not at all! Care to play again?</en>
    <zh>女士，您离开得很匆忙！肯定是有要事要忙吧。&lt;page&gt;这局只能直接判负，希望您理解。但我们不会计较这种小事！要不要再来一局？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BALLOW_DIVING_BELL_TO_BENCH">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;I need a moment, sir. Please unlock the bell that I may exit.&lt;page&gt;Seein’ some sense? Can’t blame ya if you’re thinkin’ on backin’ out. It’s a mad hope that old bell’d even survive the trip. </en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;先生，我还需要一点时间。打开钟门让我出来。&lt;page&gt;总算清醒了？打退堂鼓也不怪你。那破钟能撑到湖底本就是个疯念头。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="BALLOW_DIVING_BELL_ABYSS">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;Sir, if you can hear me, there has been an accident during the descent.&lt;hpage&gt;In this broken state, the bell is unfit for travel. Retrieve it if you may, but I shall not return within.&lt;page&gt;...iss...istake...erwhelm...retrie...a...ssible...</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;巴洛先生，能听见吗？下潜途中出了点故障。&lt;hpage&gt;钟体已损坏，无法继续下潜。你可试着把它打捞上岸，但我无法乘它返回。&lt;page&gt;……错……错误……过载……无法……打捞……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="LADY_BUG_DEPLETED_B">
    <en>Oh no... no, not at all. Wouldn’t do us any good, would it? No, it seems like this little frolic of ours is well and truly finished.&lt;page&gt;Oh, but what an honour it was to play with you, my lady! I hope you’ll think of us whenever you feel those rosaries rattling around in your pockets.</en>
    <zh>不不……不用。我们玩得起，也输得起。看来我们的游戏需要告一段落了。&lt;page&gt;但与您同乐实乃荣幸！希望您摸着兜里的念珠时能想起我们。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="LADY_BUG_CHALLENGE_WIN_2A">
    <en>Ola! That’s... that’s twenty-five times the target has been struck!&lt;page&gt;My lady... I thought perhaps you’d have a little more trouble with this round, but you’ve emerged victorious again.&lt;page&gt;I’ll have to speak to my associate. I don’t think he provided you with enough of a challenge, truth be told.&lt;hpage&gt;It was challenge enough. My prize, sir?&lt;page&gt;</en>
    <zh>哎！这……命中二十五次了！&lt;page&gt;女士……本以为这局能让您吃点苦头，结果您又赢了。&lt;page&gt;我得找我的伙计谈谈，说实话他给您设的挑战不够难。&lt;hpage&gt;我觉得够难了。那么奖品呢，先生？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="LADY_BUG_CHALLENGE_WIN_2B">
    <en>Urk! A prize, of course! My lady must have a prize!&lt;page&gt;Here then... a lovely necklace full with rosaries. I’d been hanging onto this for a while, but you’ve earned it fairly.&lt;page&gt;I just hope you think of me when you wear it, my lady!</en>
    <zh>啊！当然有！必须有！&lt;page&gt;给您……缀满念珠的漂亮项链。我私藏好久了，但您赢得实至名归。&lt;page&gt;希望您佩戴它时能想起我，女士！</zh>
  </entry>
</sheet>