<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<sheet name="Greymoor">
  <entry key="HH_BARTENDER_NECTAR_PROMPT">
    <en>Purchase Vintage Nectar?</en>
    <zh>购买陈年蜜露？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="HH_BARTENDER_GREET_ACT3">
    <en>Ho, traveller! With the lands outside fresh struck by fell events, it’s good to see someone still survivin’.&lt;hpage&gt;This new curse proves a threat even to my strengthened shell. For your own safety, barkeep, I strongly suggest you remain within your walls.&lt;page&gt;Aye, well, you’re welcome to do the same. Stay and wash the troubles away with a few bells of nectar... though, given the scale to them shakes, I’m thinkin’ it might take more’n just a few.</en>
    <zh>噢，旅行者！您没事吧？外头刚遭了灾，能见到还活着的虫子真让我宽心。&lt;hpage&gt;酒保先生，劝你最好待在屋内。这新的诅咒连我的甲壳都扛不住。&lt;page&gt;您说的对，您要乐意也可以留下。喝几盏蜜露压压惊……不过看这地动山摇的架势，怕得喝光我的存货才够压惊的。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="HH_BARTENDER_CURSED">
    <en>Phew. You’re lookin’ a bit raw there, miss. I’m thinkin’ it’ll take more than my nectar to fix you up.&lt;hpage&gt;A parasite of your land has twisted itself into my shell. Its writhing is causing some discomfort.&lt;hpage&gt;If not for my unique constitution, I suspect it would have already consumed me entirely.&lt;page&gt;Well, don’t be bringing such dangerous things in here! Head to the top of the moors. There’s an old doctor up there hiding in her bell.&lt;page&gt;Her remedies are said to often hurt more’n they help, but given your state, I’d say it’s worth the risk.</en>
    <zh>嚯，您看着不太对劲啊，小姐。光靠我的蜜露，可治不了您这毛病。&lt;hpage&gt;我的甲壳里钻入了寄生物，它的蠕动使我不太舒服。&lt;hpage&gt;若不是体质特殊，我可能早被啃噬干净了。&lt;page&gt;啊，别把这种危险的玩意带到我这来！赶紧去沼泽的顶部，那里有一位老医生！她躲在一口钟里。&lt;page&gt;虽说她开的药往往比疾病本身的危害还大，但您这状况值得赌一把。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="HH_BARTENDER_NECTAR_OFFER">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;Bartender, I’ve been tasked to acquire a nectar of significant age. Would you retain any such drink?&lt;page&gt;After the finer stuff, eh? Sure, I might have a few vessels left, but I can’t be selling ‘em cheap.&lt;page&gt;The shells in my cellar are the last left in Pharloom. Once they’re gone, no bug’ll ever taste such sweetness again.</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;酒保先生，我在找储存多年的蜜露。你这儿可有存货？&lt;page&gt;嘴巴越来越刁了，小姐？我这应该还剩几瓶，但价钱可不便宜。&lt;page&gt;我地窖里的存货可是纺络最后的陈酿。喝完之后，再也没有虫子能享受到此等蜜酿咯。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="HH_BARTENDER_DRINK_DECLINED">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;Another time, perhaps. Among the few gifts of my birth, I find rare need for sustenance.&lt;page&gt;S’at so? Well the nectar’s always on tap if you find yourself feelin’ different.</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;改日吧。我这副躯壳生来特殊，少有饥渴之时。&lt;page&gt;这样吗？蜜露随时管够，想来一盏就招呼我一声。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="HH_BARTENDER_NECTAR_REOFFER">
    <en>&lt;page&gt;Thinkin’ again on the Vintage Nectar?&lt;page&gt;My price might seem steep, but I assure you, the few finer bugs who passed used to pay a lot more.</en>
    <zh>&lt;page&gt;还惦记着陈年蜜露？&lt;page&gt;别看我现在出的价高，之前路过的阔绰顾客给得更多呢！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="HH_BARTENDER_OFFER_REPEAT">
    <en>Any chance you’d reconsider dealing with my blasted craw problem? I’d offer fair reward for your efforts.</en>
    <zh>真不打算帮我收拾房顶上的麻烦？酬劳保证让您满意。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="HH_BARTENDER_OFFER_QUEST">
    <en>Traveller, I’m not wanting to impose, but I’ve a wish that one of your able sort could likely grant.&lt;hpage&gt;I’ve my own task to attend, good sir, but I’ll hear you out.&lt;page&gt;It’s those blasted craws atop here. My roof is fast becoming their cosy nest! Now they’ve grown so bold they’re starting to attack pilgrims as they pass.&lt;hpage&gt;Would you simply have them slain? If so, your sturdy shell seems more than up to that task?&lt;page&gt;If only it were so simple. Kill the ones above, and more just keep coming. It’s the warmth of this home you see. Draws ‘em right in.&lt;page&gt;I’m looking for a long-term solution. A scarecraw! I’ll build the biggest there’s ever been, so fearsome it’ll keep those craws away for good!</en>
    <zh>旅行者，本不该劳烦您，但有件事非得您这样的利落角色才能办。&lt;hpage&gt;虽然我还有自己的事要去做，但请说吧，先生。&lt;page&gt;您看到房顶上那群腐囊虫了吗？它们快把我这儿当成自己的窝了！最近胆子越来越肥，已经开始攻击过路的朝圣者了。&lt;hpage&gt;你是想直接把它们杀光？看你这身强健的躯壳，办这事应该不费劲吧？&lt;page&gt;要这么简单就好了。杀完一茬又来一茬，全怪我这酒馆太暖和，招虫子。&lt;page&gt;得想个一劳永逸的办法——扎个巨型稻草人！保准吓得它们再不敢靠近！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="HH_PATRON_LEFT_TALK_1">
    <en>Tis a blessed bit of luck to find this place, eh, sister?&lt;page&gt;The climb’s proved harder than even my best guessin’, but there’s still some vigour left in these old limbs. Doubly so, now I have a belly full of nectar!</en>
    <zh>能找着这酒馆，真算撞大运了！&lt;page&gt;这段攀登比我预想的还要艰难，但我这副老甲壳里仍然残存着些许活力。如今，狠狠灌上几盏蜜露，更是精神倍增！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="HH_BARTENDER_REPEAT">
    <en>Care for a drink, traveller? My nectar’s got a kick that’ll warm your shell in these sodden climes.</en>
    <zh>旅行者，来盏蜜露暖暖身子？这地方湿气重，而我的蜜露最能驱寒。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="HH_PATRON_RIGHT_TALK_1">
    <en>Hoy... sister! I’m sat here all bent and bedraggled, but you look fresh as the day you was hatched!&lt;page&gt;How do you fare so well in these drenched and dangerous lands? Maybe you got a secret you could share?&lt;hpage&gt;None that would offer easy aid, good bug. Whatever luck or savvy brought you this far, may it continue on your journey.</en>
    <zh>嘿……小姐！我这破甲壳疼得我直不起腰，你的倒鲜亮得像是刚破卵而出！&lt;page&gt;在这种鬼地方你怎么保养的？有啥秘诀能透露不？&lt;hpage&gt;没有什么秘诀，在这种地方只能靠自己，无论靠的是运气还是智慧。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="HH_BARTENDER_NECTAR_DECLINE">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;For now, bartender, I cannot spare so many rosaries.&lt;page&gt;Suit yourself. Maybe you’d rather a pour of the cheap stuff? Give your shell a kick before you head out into our blighted lands.  </en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;酒保先生，眼下我拿不出这么多念珠。&lt;page&gt;没关系，那来盏便宜货？出发前给自己壮壮胆。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="HH_BARTENDER_BELLHARTHAUNTED">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;My travels took me through a town beside your moors, in a vein of old bells. Its residents are bound upon a vicious thread.&lt;page&gt;Ahh. So Pharloom’s curse has strung’em tight. A frightful thing. Word’d long gone silent from over their way.&lt;hpage&gt;I suggest you pass warning to your patrons, bartender. If they’re travelling the bellside paths, best they give that place wide berth.&lt;page&gt;Aye. I’ll let’em know, traveller, though in these cursed times, does any safe path still exist?</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;我路过了一个位于古老钟脉里的小镇，就在这片沼泽旁边，那里的居民全被凶恶的丝线缠绕着。&lt;page&gt;啊……纺络的诅咒把那儿的虫子紧紧束缚，可怕得很。那镇上很久就没有音讯传出来过了。&lt;hpage&gt;酒保先生，我建议你提醒客人们，若是要走钟脉边的小道，务必离那地方远点。&lt;page&gt;没问题，旅行者。不过话说回来，如今这世道哪还有安全的路哟。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="HH_BARTENDER_CURSED_REPEAT">
    <en>Best be visiting that doctor right quick, miss! She’s up there, at the top of the moors, over toward the bellvein.&lt;page&gt;Her methods might be suspect, but you’re lookin’ sorely in need of service.</en>
    <zh>小姐，您最好赶紧去看医生！就在沼泽顶部的钟脉附近。&lt;page&gt;虽然她的治疗方法很是邪乎，但您这身子骨可拖不起。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="HH_PATRON_LEFT_TALK_REPEAT">
    <en>Might have taken me a beat to build the courage, but I can feel it, closer now... the Citadel calling me up.</en>
    <zh>我可能得多喝点才能鼓足勇气，继续上路了。但我能感觉到，圣堡离我更近了……它在顶上呼唤我呢。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="HH_BARTENDER_QUEST_COMPLETE">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;Here is the Ragpelt, sir. I hope the amount is sufficient for your work.&lt;page&gt;Aye. This should be enough. Once I find a quiet moment, I’ll get straight to building that mighty scarecraw.&lt;page&gt;With a little luck, my roof should be clear of those pests when next you pass by. Thank you kindly, traveller!</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;酒保先生，这些是你要的破毛皮。希望足够帮你制作稻草人。&lt;page&gt;够了够了！等我腾出手就去扎稻草人。&lt;page&gt;运气好的话，待你下次路过时，房顶应该已经清静了。衷心感谢你，旅者！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="HH_BARTENDER_QUEST_ACTIVE">
    <en>If you’re collecting Ragpelt from the crawbugs, those young’ns above here’ll be slim pickings. It’s the mature craws you want, over by the watermound. They’ll drop the stuff a-plenty.&lt;page&gt;Course, you’ll need to do some pointed persuading if you’re planning to separate rag from bug...</en>
    <zh>要收集腐囊虫的破毛皮，房顶那些小崽子可不够用。去水丘旁边找成年腐囊虫，它们身上有更多的货。&lt;page&gt;当然，你得用点“尖锐”的手段，才能让它们乖乖交出毛皮……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="HH_BARTENDER_NECTAR_GOT">
    <en>You’re back, miss! Heard a little commotion below. I trust everything went... erm, smoothly?&lt;hpage&gt;&lt;hpage&gt;Sir, your cellar seems to have an ant problem. I assume, in sending me down, it merely slipped your mind to mention?&lt;page&gt;Ah... Oh yes! Well, with your weapon, and talent, and what... I’m sure they didn’t pose a problem? Ahem.&lt;page&gt;And why! I see you’ve collected your prize, so we’ve both come out well from the trade!&lt;page&gt;Enjoy your nectar, miss. No simple pilgrim will ever taste a drop so fine.</en>
    <zh>小姐，您回来啦！底下动静不小……没出什么岔子吧？&lt;hpage&gt;&lt;hpage&gt;先生，你家地窖闹蚂蚁，怎么不提前知会？&lt;page&gt;哎！您这身手……小小蚂蚁肯定不在话下嘛！是吧？&lt;page&gt;啊哈！我看您也得到了战利品，这笔交易对咱们双方都算得上圆满！&lt;page&gt;小姐，好好享受这瓶蜜露吧。这滋味普通的朝圣者可尝不着。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="HH_BARTENDER_DECLINE_QUEST">
    <en>Ahh. Fair enough, traveller. You’ve clearly got your own tasks to be on with. I’ll manage, no doubt.</en>
    <zh>唉，理解理解。你毕竟有要事在身，我再想想办法吧。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="HH_BARTENDER_QUEST_COMPLETE_2">
    <en>As payment goes, I’ve got something I think you’d make good use of. A spare crafting kit.&lt;page&gt;I’d been holding onto it for someone else, but they’ve been gone long enough now, I know they won’t be returning.</en>
    <zh>酬劳的话，我这有个东西，您应该能用得上——一个多余的制作匣。&lt;page&gt;本来这是要留给别人的，但那位怕是已经回不来了。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="HH_BARTENDER_QUEST_COMPLETE_3">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;Thank you sir. This is a worthy trade for my work. My tools shall attain an even sharper edge.</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;多谢先生。这东西对我很有帮助，我的工具将更加锋锐。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="HH_PATRON_RIGHT_TALK_REPEAT">
    <en>My sore shell will cease tormenting me once I reach the Citadel. It’s sung that all ails are healed just as soon as we step beyond the Grand Gate...</en>
    <zh>现在疼就疼点吧，等我到达圣堡，这一切都不是问题了。据说所有的痛苦都会在迈入巨扉圣门后烟消云散……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="HH_BARTENDER_NECTAR_ACCEPT">
    <en>Aye. A fair trade. The aged stuff’s down at the bottom of the cellar.&lt;page&gt;I’ll trust you to collect only the vessel you’re owed. I’d be grabbing it myself, but it’s become a hard climb for my stiffened shell.</en>
    <zh>好嘞，成交。陈酿在地窖最底层。&lt;page&gt;我这副甲壳现在僵硬了不少，不方便上上下下的。劳烦您自个儿去取。我相信您是不会多拿的，对吧？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="HH_BARTENDER_RUMOUR_1">
    <en>S’only those few stronger pilgrims that survive to reach my home now... Pharloom’s curse claims the rest. Poor sods, left to wander.&lt;page&gt;I do sometimes get to wondering... Is it the dregs of their own mind in there keepin’em walking, or something else entirely...?</en>
    <zh>如今能来到我这儿的，大多是足够强大的朝圣者……剩下的都被纺络的诅咒害成游魂了。&lt;page&gt;我有时候会想……是他们自己残存的意识在支撑行走呢，还是别的什么鬼东西在作祟……？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="HH_BARTENDER_RUMOUR_2">
    <en>Bellhart, over the moors, a great town I’ve heard it once was, heart of the path’n all, right smack in the middle of these midlands.&lt;page&gt;Now it’s all a’crumble... And that brittle vein of bells is crawling with nasties. Ain’t no place left in Pharloom that can fairly claim to offer safety. </en>
    <zh>这片沼泽上方的钟心镇，当年可是个了不得的地方。位于整个中部地区的腹地，被称为朝圣之路的“心脏”。&lt;page&gt;如今全垮了……那儿的钟脉里爬满脏东西。纺络早没安全地界啦。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="HH_BARTENDER_RUMOUR_3">
    <en>You visited them pens up above here, miss? Horrid place, once all about growing meat or some such. Meant to keep us moorbugs livin’, and working, its told...&lt;page&gt;That damned place’s long gone to the Haunting. And now the meat’s running feral and free.</en>
    <zh>小姐，去过上头那个养殖场没？可怕的地方。早先是搞正经蟑螂肉养殖的——为了喂饱我们这些沼泽虫，好让我们认真工作……&lt;page&gt;那鬼地方早被丝咒侵占了。现在，养的蟑螂全都跑出来撒野。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="HH_BARTENDER_QUEST_CANCOMPLETE">
    <en>Welcome back, traveller. How’d you get along with collecting the Ragpelt from those mangy crawbugs? Their squawking and crooing up there is starting to wear mightily on my patrons!</en>
    <zh>旅行者，你回来啦？破毛皮收集得怎么样？屋顶上叽叽喳喳吵个没完，我的老顾客们都要跑光了！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="HH_BARTENDER_DRINK_PROMPT">
    <en>Buy a drink?</en>
    <zh>要喝点什么吗？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="HH_BARTENDER_QUEST_DECLINEPELTS">
    <en>Hmm, holding on to them, eh? I won’t ask why, but I’d sure appreciate it if you reconsider.</en>
    <zh>嗯……不打算交给我？虽然不知道原因，但求您发发善心，再考虑考虑。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="HH_BARTENDER_NECTAR_PAID">
    <en>Planning to grab that Vintage Nectar? You passed a fair bundle of rosaries for the bottle, so I figured you’ll be eager to see it yours.&lt;page&gt;The old stuff’s down there, at the bottom of the cellar. I’ll keep the trap open for you, just be swift. </en>
    <zh>准备去取陈年蜜露了吗？您可为它付了不少念珠，我想您肯定也急着将它收入囊中。&lt;page&gt;陈酿在地窖的底层，地窖门给您开着，麻烦您手脚麻利点。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="HH_BARTENDER_GREET">
    <en>Harh! Well met, traveller. Lookin’ for a drink, or a rest, or both?&lt;hpage&gt;Fair greetings, good bug. The warmth of your hearth is welcome upon these wet plains.&lt;page&gt;Aye. It’s a damp climb through these parts. Used to be just pilgrims trekkin’ my way, but odd times these are, and you ain’t even the strangest shell wandering about.&lt;page&gt;A rowdy old warrior stopped through not long back, caused quite a scene, and now a young lass’s taken up lodging in my top room.&lt;page&gt;The lass mentioned she’s on the lookout for sharp types like yourself. Maybe pay her a visit, if you haven’t already?</en>
    <zh>哈！贵客临门。想来盏蜜露，还是歇个脚，或者两样都要？&lt;hpage&gt;这地方真是不错。这湿漉漉的平原上，最缺你这里暖烘烘的炉火。&lt;page&gt;是啊，这地界爬上来可不容易。早先只有朝圣者路过，如今世道古怪，连您这副稀罕甲壳都到处晃悠。&lt;page&gt;前阵子有个老战士在我这儿闹腾得欢，这几天顶层客房又住进个小姑娘。&lt;page&gt;那姑娘正想找您这样的利落角色，有空不妨上楼瞧瞧？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="HH_BARTENDER_ACCEPT_QUEST">
    <en>Excellent, excellent! Let’s give those mangy craws the fright of their lives! Hah!&lt;page&gt;All I need is some Ragpelt from the crawbugs themselves. Hunt ‘em down, collect their pelts, and bring me back a heap of the stuff. I’ll do the rest!</en>
    <zh>好极了！让那群臭腐囊虫见识见识，什么叫吓破胆！哈！&lt;page&gt;我需要腐囊虫身上的破毛皮作为材料。劳烦您宰些腐囊虫，取一些它们的破毛皮来。剩下的交给我！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="HH_BARTENDER_QUEST_ACTIVE_2">
    <en>The sooner you’ve collected that Ragpelt, the better. I can’t have those pests killing more potential guests.&lt;page&gt;Business is slow enough already, and clearing corpses ain’t no fun at all.</en>
    <zh>赶紧把破毛皮弄来吧，越快越好。不能再让它们杀害我的潜在客户们了。&lt;page&gt;本来生意就不算好，收拾虫尸还费劲！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="HH_BARTENDER_REPEAT_ACT3">
    <en>Wantin’ for a drink, traveller? Might soon be the end for all’o us, so no need to go easy on the nectar.</en>
    <zh>旅行者，要来喝一盏吗？反正大伙都快完蛋了，今朝有蜜今朝醉噢。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="HH_BARTENDER_OFFER_QUEST_WISHWALL">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;Barkeep, I have seen your request on the bell town’s wishwall. What assistance are you seeking?&lt;page&gt;Ah! Perfect! You’re the able sort that’ll make short work of the task.&lt;page&gt;The problem is those blasted craws atop here. My roof is fast becoming their cosy nest! Now they’ve grown so bold they’re starting to attack pilgrims as they pass.&lt;hpage&gt;Would you simply have me slay them? Your sturdy shell seems more than up to that task.&lt;page&gt;If only it were so simple. Kill the ones above and more just keep coming. It’s the warmth of this home you see. Draws ‘em right in.&lt;page&gt;I’m looking for a long-term solution. A scarecraw! I’ll build the biggest there’s ever been, so fearsome it’ll keep those craws away for good!&lt;page&gt;All I need is some Ragpelt from the crawbugs themselves. Hunt ‘em down, collect their pelts, and bring me back a heap of the stuff. I’ll do the rest!</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;酒保先生，我看见钟心镇祈愿墙上有你的委托。所为何事？&lt;page&gt;啊！太好了！可算找着行家了！&lt;page&gt;您看到房顶上那群腐囊虫了吗？它们快把我这儿当成自己的窝了！最近胆子越来越肥，已经开始攻击过路的朝圣者了。&lt;hpage&gt;你是想直接把它们杀光？看你这身强健的甲壳，办这事应该不费劲吧？&lt;page&gt;要这么简单就好了。杀完一茬又来一茬，全怪我这酒馆太暖和，招虫子。&lt;page&gt;得想个一劳永逸的办法——扎个巨型稻草人！保准吓得它们再不敢靠近！&lt;page&gt;我需要腐囊虫身上的破毛皮作为材料。劳烦您宰些腐囊虫，取一些它们的破毛皮来。剩下的交给我！</zh>
  </entry>
</sheet>