<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<sheet name="Peak">
  <entry key="MASK_MAKER_UNMASK_TALK_04">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;The bugs of your land, I have watched them, climbing towards their absolution without the flicker of a thought to what it means.&lt;page&gt;Aye. But isn’t it always such for those snared to serve your higher caste?&lt;page&gt;Our mortal mob did once act some defiance, unawares maybe, but successful in part, goaded towards it by Weavers’ will’n all.&lt;hpage&gt;You speak of the Citadel? Its former function has failed, but I can still sense its purpose, some. It is church and cage both.&lt;page&gt;Aye. Devised by your ancestors that monstrosity, and their wicked, clever minds. A system, or a web they’d likely call it, a way to keep their mother sealed in slumber, and themselves free to lavish in their false rule.</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;我观察了这片土地的虫。他们一心爬向救赎，却不懂这意味着什么。&lt;page&gt;是啊，但被你们高等族群使唤的不都这样。&lt;page&gt;我们凡虫不是没反抗过。当年被织者忽悠着，居然还真成了点事。&lt;hpage&gt;你说圣堡？虽然荒废了，还是能感觉到它的用途：既是教堂又是牢笼。&lt;page&gt;是啊。你祖辈造的这怪物，用狡猾心思织成网，让母亲陷入沉眠，自己却在外面称王。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="MASK_MAKER_UNMASK_DELIVERY">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;Maker, I bring a delivery from Bellhart below, lacquer for your long work.&lt;page&gt;Ahh. Know you distort the order of things, Old One. It is a rare want of your caste to serve us mortal bugs.&lt;hpage&gt;I am not my kin, Maker. I have seen enough pain born of their dominion. As much as I may, I choose to stand apart.&lt;page&gt;If your blood allows it so... And my thanks still for the lacquer. Pharloom’s fresh faces will welcome its sheen.</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;匠师，我从钟心镇送来漆料，够你用很久。&lt;page&gt;啊呀，古老者，这怎么合适。侍奉我们凡虫可不是你们族群的作风。&lt;hpage&gt;我和同族不一样。看够了他们统治下的苦难，自然不会同流合污。&lt;page&gt;不知您的同族会怎么想……但还是多谢漆料。纺络的新面孔会喜欢的。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="MASK_MAKER_REPEAT1_ACT3">
    <en>Until cavern’s collapse, the masks must be made! </en>
    <zh>直到洞窟崩塌，雕刻都不能停！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="MASK_MAKER_UNMASK_REPEAT_ACT3">
    <en>Enough talk, Old One. My contract remains. I’ll work till caverns’ collapse.&lt;hpage&gt;Very well, Maker. If it is within my power to do so, I shall see your lands saved.</en>
    <zh>聊够了吧，古老者。契约还在，我要继续刻面甲，直到大地崩塌。&lt;hpage&gt;好吧，匠师。要是有办法，我会保护好这片土地。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="MASK_MAKER_UNMASK_MEET">
    <en>Ahh. Old One. Your kind should know it’s rude to expose me such. Unmasked, the task becomes heavy. &lt;hpage&gt;I had the desire to hear you lucid, Maker, though you may protest.&lt;page&gt;Aye. Well its no great shock to have you visit. I’ve felt the stirrings of our monarch, even all the way out here, the tremors of her kin brought close.&lt;page&gt;You’re planning a confrontation with her then? The one atop? Our great, frayed god?&lt;hpage&gt;Our meeting seems inevitable, though first I seek the strength to ensure a favourable outcome.&lt;page&gt;Ha! As I’d have guessed! Your ancient kind aren’t told to abide one another peaceably.&lt;page&gt;Well, assuming you prevail, I’ll ask only that my labour may continue. No matter the state of these lands, you should well know the necessity of my service.</en>
    <zh>啊呀，古老者，你们这一族最清楚，不戴面甲交谈太失礼了。&lt;hpage&gt;我就是想和清醒的你聊聊，别见怪。&lt;page&gt;好吧。不过我倒是不奇怪你会来。连我这都能感觉到那位的躁动，想必就是因为你。&lt;page&gt;所以你打算要去她算账？找我们伟大却又衰败的女王？&lt;hpage&gt;迟早要见，但我得先积蓄力量。&lt;page&gt;哈！早猜到了！你们古族从来都是窝里斗。&lt;page&gt;要是你赢了，我只求能继续刻面甲。无论王国结局如何，我的活都不能停。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="MASK_MAKER_UNMASK_PREVIOUSLY_MET_ACT3">
    <en>Back again, Old One? The effects of your... altercation with the pale mother... those are plainly sensed. The fate for these caverns feels grim.&lt;page&gt;I’ll take it things have taken a turn more complicated? Or was this the aftermath anticipated all along?&lt;hpage&gt;In our meeting, a mortal blow was dealt, but the monarch’s desperate death throes now threaten to take this whole kingdom with her.&lt;page&gt;Ha! I’m not surprised! It’s always the way, aye? Your ancient kind, vying for dominion, and us mortal bugs squashed unseen underneath.&lt;hpage&gt;It was freedom I sought, Maker. Naive perhaps, but this is not the fate I wished to come.</en>
    <zh>又来了古老者？我感觉到了你和苍白女王争斗……不过看来情况不太妙。&lt;page&gt;我猜事情变得复杂了？还是说你早料到会这样？&lt;hpage&gt;我给了她致命一击，可她临死挣扎要让整个王国陪葬。&lt;page&gt;哈！一点都不意外！你们古族争权夺利，我们小虫子活该被碾碎。&lt;hpage&gt;我想要自由，匠师。既为了我也为了你们。或许是有些天真，但这不是我要的结局。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="MASK_MAKER_REPEAT1">
    <en>All deserve a face. A chance to be! Until I wither, for the faceless I shall provide. </en>
    <zh>所有生灵都该有张脸，有机会存在！只要我还没倒下，就会给无面者造脸。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="MASK_MAKER_REPEAT2_ACT3">
    <en>To exist, to die, a face is needed. It is the essential thing.</en>
    <zh>不论死活，都得有一张脸。这是根本。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="MASK_MAKER_DELIVERY">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;Maker, I bring a delivery from Bellhart below, lacquer for your long work. &lt;page&gt;Good! Good! To seal. To protect. May Pharloom’s fresh faces gleam bright.</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;匠师，我从钟心镇送来漆料，够你用很久。&lt;page&gt;好！好！用来封存，用来保护。让纺络的新面孔闪闪发亮。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="MASK_MAKER_POST">
    <en>Take reward for service made, visitor! Gift for you, to spend or treasure!</en>
    <zh>收下报酬吧客人！要用掉还是收着都行！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="MASK_MAKER_MEET">
    <en>A visitor! Grand you are. But you have already a mask. Already a face. It is for those without that I must carve. </en>
    <zh>欢迎！尊贵的客人。可你已经有面甲了，已经有脸了。我的刻刀只为无面者服务。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="MASK_MAKER_REPEAT3">
    <en>To work! To work! The masks must be carved.</en>
    <zh>雕刻！雕刻！必须继续雕刻面甲。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="MASK_MAKER_UNMASK_PEAK">
    <en>Did you treat with the creature upon the summit?&lt;page&gt;Your legged ancestors once found her company compelling, enough to build their chambers and their calling device at the height of this perilous peak.&lt;hpage&gt;I have paid my respects, and been granted her favour. Her down now fills my cloak, and does much to ward against the frost of these heights.&lt;page&gt;To pass something so precious... That’s a mighty gift you’ve been given. Seems she’s thrown her lot in with you.&lt;page&gt;I’d not have guessed her so opposed to our threaded monarch, but then she too must have sensed the wretched state of things, and the harsher change to come. </en>
    <zh>见过山顶上那位了吗？&lt;page&gt;你那些多足的先祖对她十分信服，甚至在这么险的山峰上修了屋子打造机器。&lt;hpage&gt;我去拜访过了，也受到了她的青睐，得了这身御寒的绒毛。&lt;page&gt;连这个都送你……真是下了血本。她把宝押在你身上了。&lt;page&gt;没想到她这么反对苍白之主，恐怕她也看出纺络情况不对，有大事要发生了。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="MASK_MAKER_UNMASK_MEET_ACT3">
    <en>Ahh. Old One. Your kind should know it’s rude to expose me such. Unmasked, the task becomes heavy. &lt;hpage&gt;I had the desire to hear you lucid, Maker, though you may protest.&lt;page&gt;Aye. Well its no great shock to have you visit. I’ve felt, and heard, the effects of your... altercation with the pale mother... The fate for these caverns seems grim.&lt;page&gt;I’ll take it things have taken a turn more complicated? Or was this the aftermath anticipated all along?&lt;hpage&gt;In our meeting, a mortal blow was dealt, but the monarch’s desperate death throes now threaten to take this whole kingdom with her.&lt;page&gt;Ha! I’m not surprised! It’s always the way, aye? Your ancient kind, vying for dominion, and us mortal bugs squashed unseen underneath.&lt;hpage&gt;It was freedom I sought, Maker, for myself and for you mortal few. Naive perhaps, but this is not the fate I wished to come.</en>
    <zh>啊呀，古老者，你们这一族最清楚，不戴面甲交谈太失礼了。&lt;hpage&gt;我就是想和清醒的你聊聊，别见怪。&lt;page&gt;好吧。不过我倒是不奇怪你会来。我感觉到、听到了你和苍白女王争斗……不过看来情况不太妙。&lt;page&gt;我猜事情变得复杂了？还是说你早料到会这样？&lt;hpage&gt;我给了她致命一击，可她临死挣扎要让整个王国陪葬。&lt;page&gt;哈！一点都不意外！你们古族争权夺利，我们小虫子活该被碾碎。&lt;hpage&gt;我想要自由，匠师。既为了我也为了你们。或许是有些天真，但这不是我要的结局。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="MASK_MAKER_MEET_ACT3">
    <en>Late! Late you are! And already a mask. Already a face. It is for those without that I must carve. </en>
    <zh>迟了！太迟了！你已经有面甲了，已经有脸了。我的刻刀只为无面者服务。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="MASK_MAKER_POST_UNMASK">
    <en>Have some small reward for your troubles, Old One. It’s no small thing to deliver that sloshing stuff safe, ‘specially all the way up here.</en>
    <zh>古老者，请收下这点酬劳。抱着晃荡的漆罐爬这么高不容易。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="MASK_MAKER_RELATIONSHIP">
    <en>A fine face, yours. Not of my work. Not of this kingdom’s craft. Not now at least.&lt;page&gt;But the deeper form. Distant relationship. Some form of Pharloom and our old, legged, stewards. &lt;page&gt;Now! To work. To work! The masks are needed.</en>
    <zh>你这张脸不错。不是我的手艺，也不是纺络的手艺。至少现在不是。&lt;page&gt;但更深处，有渊源。和古时候那些多足管事的一样。&lt;page&gt;好了！干活！干活！需要更多面甲！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="MASK_MAKER_UNMASK_TALK_03">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;You have the sight, Maker. Tell me what you see in me?&lt;page&gt;Your mask... It reads clear enough, Old One. Watcher, hunter, monarch even, though you may reject that station.&lt;page&gt;A complex visage, perhaps, yet still to my sight it looks unresolved.&lt;hpage&gt;If you see a transitional state, it is one I have accepted. My mask has remained defined through lifetimes uncounted.&lt;page&gt;Aye. Rigid I’m sure, but your kind rarely develop evenly, and the lifetime of bugs are poor measure for one like you.&lt;page&gt;Could be there’s more growth awaiting you yet...</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;匠师好眼力。在我身上看到什么了？&lt;page&gt;你的面甲……上面清清楚楚。守望者，猎手，甚至君主——就算你不认最后这个。&lt;page&gt;挺复杂的一张脸，但在我看来还没定型。&lt;hpage&gt;如果是过渡状态，那我早已接受。这面甲已陪我度过了不知多少辈子的时间。&lt;page&gt;是啊。不过你们古族生长发育不合常理，我们虫子的几辈子可没法衡量你的年纪。&lt;page&gt;说不定你还能再长大呢……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="MASK_MAKER_REPEAT3_ACT3">
    <en>Our world cries its end! But the masks must still be carved.</en>
    <zh>虽然世界在哀嚎！但面甲还得继续刻。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="MASK_MAKER_UNMASK_REPEAT">
    <en>Enough talk, Old One. Mine is a calling that scant allows rest.&lt;hpage&gt;Very well, Maker. I shall take my leave.</en>
    <zh>聊够了吧，古老者。我的使命可不让休息。&lt;hpage&gt;好吧，匠师。告辞了。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="MASK_MAKER_REPEAT2">
    <en>To exist, a face is needed. It is the essential thing.</en>
    <zh>要存在，就得有张脸。这是根本。</zh>
  </entry>
</sheet>