<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<sheet name="Pilgrims">
  <entry key="GATE_PILGRIM_REMEET_NO_SHRINES">
    <en>The Citadel is calling us, sister! We stand so close. We need only the blessing of those bells to see the Grand Gate open.&lt;hpage&gt;I will awaken the bells, pilgrim. With luck, you will not be waiting long.</en>
    <zh>圣堡在召唤，姊妹！我们只有一步之遥了。只需群钟赐福，巨扉圣门定将开启。&lt;hpage&gt;我会敲响那些巨钟。幸运的话，你们无需久候。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="GATE_PILGRIM_REPEAT_NO_SHRINES">
    <en>Only the holy bells of the great path shall open the way!&lt;page&gt;We beg you, traveller, see the bells awoken, that we may cross this final threshold.</en>
    <zh>只有朝圣途中的圣钟可开启此门！&lt;page&gt;恳求您，旅行者。令众钟苏醒，我们方可越过这最终的门槛。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="GATE_PILGRIM_REMEET_GOT_SHRINES">
    <en>Ahhh... the gate! The bells have awoken! All along the path. Now we need only music to see them attuned! &lt;hpage&gt;I have recently learnt the art of producing song by strumming Silk, though I confess it is a skill deserving of more practice.&lt;page&gt;Oh! Ohh! Have no doubt, sister! Play sincerely. Any music is sweet enough! Play for us, and surely the bells will resound! Play, and we will sing!</en>
    <zh>啊……巨门！圣钟皆已苏醒！眼下我们只需奏响音乐，使其共鸣！&lt;hpage&gt;我最近习得以灵丝拨弦成曲的技艺，但仍有些生疏。&lt;page&gt;噢！无需顾虑，姊妹！至诚则灵，凡乐皆美！为我们奏响音乐，圣钟必将回应！演奏吧，我们将为你歌唱！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="GATE_PILGRIM_REMEET_SHRINES">
    <en>Ahhh... the Grand Gate! The bells have awoken! &lt;page&gt;We beg you, sister. Play or sing, and we shall follow. Call out to the bells of the path and see the gate open!</en>
    <zh>啊……巨扉圣门！圣钟皆已苏醒！&lt;page&gt;恳求您，姊妹。奏乐咏唱，我们定将跟随你。呼唤圣途钟声，开启此门！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="GATE_PILGRIM_REPEAT_SHRINES">
    <en>We beg you, sister. Delay no further! Play for us. Call out to the bells of the path and see the Grand Gate open!</en>
    <zh>恳求您，姊妹。勿再拖延！为我们奏乐，呼唤圣途钟声，开启巨扉圣门！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="GATE_PILGRIM_MEET">
    <en>The gate... the gate! O, the Grand Gate to the Citadel stands before us!&lt;page&gt;We are so close! O mighty ones beyond the gate, we beg you! Open the way and let we poor, insignificant little pilgrims crawl into the light...&lt;hpage&gt;I see no gatekeepers to heed your plea, pilgrim, though I too seek entry to the Citadel. Have you heard of a means to open this gateway?&lt;page&gt;Ahh... Weapons blunt it not. No holes for keys. ‘Tis the bells, they say! The holy bells upon the path that open the way!</en>
    <zh>巨门啊……巨门！通往圣堡的巨扉圣门近在眼前！&lt;page&gt;咫尺之遥！门后的尊者啊，求您垂怜！开启通路，容我等卑微朝圣者遁入圣光……&lt;hpage&gt;看来没有守门者回应答你的祈愿。我也想进入圣堡，你可知道开门的办法？&lt;page&gt;唉……兵刃伤不了分毫，也不见锁孔。只有朝圣途中的圣钟可开启此门！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="GATE_PILGRIM_MEET_NO_SHRINES">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;I have passed several such bells, pilgrim. I know how to see them woken. Tell me what you know of their locations, and I shall seek those that still remain silent.&lt;page&gt;Sister? This is a mighty service you willingly perform! What a marvellous gift you would grant to your fellows. &lt;page&gt;Eagerly, I shall tell you of the shrines and their locations, as we have heard them spoken...</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;朝圣者，我途中遇到过多座此类巨钟，也知晓唤醒方法。请告知余下的位置，我这就去寻找未鸣之钟。&lt;page&gt;姊妹？这是何等伟大的侍奉！您对同伴的馈赠真是慷慨！&lt;page&gt;我会悉数告知神殿方位，将我们听闻的消息原封不动地告诉你……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="GATE_PILGRIM_MEET_ALT">
    <en>The gate... the gate! O, the Grand Gate to the Citadel stands before us!&lt;page&gt;We are so close! O mighty ones beyond the gate, we beg you! Open the way and let we poor, insignificant little pilgrims crawl into the light...&lt;hpage&gt;I see no gatekeepers to heed your plea, pilgrim, though I too would benefit from its opening. Have you heard of a means to pass through?&lt;page&gt;Ahh... Weapons blunt it not. No holes for keys. ‘Tis the bells, they say! The holy bells upon the path that open the way!</en>
    <zh>巨门啊……巨门！圣堡巨扉圣门近在眼前！&lt;page&gt;门后的尊者啊，求您垂怜！开启通路，容我等卑微朝圣者遁入圣光……&lt;hpage&gt;看来没有守门者回应你的祈愿。但开启这道门对我也有好处，你可知道开门的办法？&lt;page&gt;唉……兵刃伤不了分毫，也不见锁孔。只有朝圣途中的圣钟可开启此门！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="GATE_PILGRIM_MEET_SHRINES">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;On my journey up, I passed many large bells housed in old shrines. Each I have struck awake, yet still this gate stays closed. What other task must be done to see us pass beyond?&lt;page&gt;The bells are rung? Then this sacred threshold may now be crossed, for the final task is simple! Only music, played fair and true. Music shall attune the bells, and see the gate descend.&lt;page&gt;It must be you to lead us, sister! You, who brought this blessing! Play or sing, and we shall follow.</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;上行途中，我已敲响诸多钟殿内的巨钟，但此门仍然紧闭。还需要怎样的仪式吗？&lt;page&gt;巨钟皆已鸣响？那这神圣门槛便可跨越！最终仪式简单，唯有真诚演奏的音乐，方能使钟声共鸣，引导大门降下。&lt;page&gt;必须由你来引领我们，姊妹！是你带来了这份恩典。演奏或歌唱吧，我们定将跟随你。</zh>
  </entry>
</sheet>