<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<sheet name="Shellwood">
  <entry key="WOOD_WITCH_CURSE_ACCEPTED">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;Very well. This final rite... what would you have me do?&lt;page&gt;The time... of birth is close. Now give... its shell. Host... the final rite.&lt;page&gt;The time of birth... is near.</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;好吧。这最终仪式……需要我做什么？&lt;page&gt;诞生……之时。献出……甲壳。宿主……终仪。&lt;page&gt;诞辰……已至。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="SETH_GUARDIAN_TALK_REPEAT">
    <en>You may rest here in this sacred place, but know, if you choose to step further, you shall see my weapon raised.</en>
    <zh>你可以在此处休息，但记住，越界意味着面对我的兵刃。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="WOOD_WITCH_CURSE_OFFER">
    <en>The time... the time of birth approaches. The bud cries. Yearning. The final rite may begin.&lt;page&gt;White shell. Red cloak. Bug strong and old. The time of birth is near. Aid now the final rite.</en>
    <zh>时刻……诞生之时将至。花苞啼哭。终仪可启。&lt;page&gt;白面红袍。古老强虫。诞生之时已至，此刻助我终仪。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="WOOD_WITCH_FLOWER_QUEST_COMPLETE_1">
    <en>P... Pollip Hearts. Gathered. Gathered all. All that is needed, is given.</en>
    <zh>花……花芯。集齐。所需皆备。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="WOOD_WITCH_FLOWER_QUEST_DECLINE">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;I hear your request, but I must decline. My travels will take me far beyond this wood.&lt;page&gt;Decline. No. Decline, not. The time of birth approaches. The first rite must begin.</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;很遗憾，我有要事在身，没法帮忙。&lt;page&gt;拒绝。不可。诞生之时将至。仪式必启。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="WOOD_WITCH_FLOWER_QUEST_ACCEPT">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;If you have knowledge or power to grant, I will aid you. These Pollip Hearts you desire... they can be found about the wood?&lt;page&gt;P... Pollip Hearts. Found in the wood. Yes, bug.&lt;page&gt;Seek out the purple blooms. Inside... the hearts.&lt;page&gt;The time of birth approaches. Pollip Hearts are needed. Bring them, bug, and power will be shared.</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;若你能分享只是，我愿意帮忙。哪里能找到花芯？&lt;page&gt;花……花芯。树林间，对。&lt;page&gt;寻找紫花。芯……在其中。&lt;page&gt;诞生之时将至。带来花芯，共享力量。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="WOOD_WITCH_FLOWER_QUEST_COMPLETE_3">
    <en>Bug. Cloaked by red. The time of rebirth approaches.&lt;page&gt;First rite is completed. Prepared. For the time of birth.&lt;page&gt;Take... take. The refuse of the rite.</en>
    <zh>红袍虫。重生之时将至。&lt;page&gt;初仪完成。准备。迎接诞生。&lt;page&gt;收下……仪式残渣。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="WOOD_WITCH_FLOWER_QUEST_KEEPITEMS">
    <en>Rrrr... rite. The first rite must begin. Pollip Hearts are needed.</en>
    <zh>呃……仪式。初仪必启。需要花芯。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="WOOD_WITCH_CURSE_DECLINED">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;I am unable to help you. Not now. Perhaps another traveller will offer aid.&lt;page&gt;None... none come now. Once times, many bugs. Many. Now none. The final rite... the time of birth approaches...</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;我现在无法帮助你，或许会有其他旅者伸出援手。&lt;page&gt;无虫……曾有许多……如今无虫。终仪……诞生之时将至……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="WOOD_WITCH_MANDRAKE_ASK">
    <en>Bug. Red cloak. Far-travelled. Bring it here... the bud.&lt;page&gt;It calls. It cries for the rite. Offer it.</en>
    <zh>虫。红袍虫。远旅者。你带来了……花苞。&lt;page&gt;它在呼唤。呼唤仪式。献上吧。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="SETH_GUARDIAN_DECLINE">
    <en>Then go no further, that peace may remain between us.</en>
    <zh>那请就此止步，不必打破这份和平。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="WOOD_WITCH_MANDRAKE_ACCEPT">
    <en>The bud... weak. New. It must be nourished.&lt;page&gt;Nnn... nourished. It will be nourished.</en>
    <zh>花苞……孱弱。新生。需要滋养。&lt;page&gt;滋……滋养。得到滋养。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="WOOD_WITCH_FLOWER_QUEST_ACCEPTED">
    <en>Seek out the purple blooms. Inside... the precious hearts.&lt;page&gt;The time of birth approaches. Pollip Hearts are needed. Bring them, bug, and power will be shared.</en>
    <zh>寻找紫花。内有……珍贵花芯。&lt;page&gt;诞生之时将至。带来花芯，共享力量。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="WOOD_WITCH_FLOWER_QUEST_REOFFER">
    <en>Bug. Only you are left. None more tread here. None.&lt;page&gt;For the rite. The Pollip Hearts. They are needed. Bring them here, for the rite.</en>
    <zh>只剩你。无虫来此。&lt;page&gt; 仪式需要花芯。带来此处。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="SETH_GUARDIAN_OFFER">
    <en>Challenge the guardian?</en>
    <zh>挑战守卫者？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="WOOD_WITCH_FLOWER_QUEST_COMPLETE_2">
    <en>The first rite. Rite of the pollip. The first rite can begin.</en>
    <zh>初始仪式。花芯仪式。初仪可启。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="WOOD_WITCH_FLOWER_QUEST_CANCOMPLETE">
    <en>The precious hearts... Give them. For the time of birth, for the rite, they must bleed...</en>
    <zh>珍贵花芯……交付。为了诞生，为了仪式，它们必须流血……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="WOOD_WITCH_FLOWER_QUEST_OFFER">
    <en>The... the time of birth approaches. Now, the rite of the pollip.&lt;page&gt;Bug. Only you are left. None more tread here. None.&lt;page&gt;For the rite. The Pollip Hearts. They are needed. Bring them here, for the rite.</en>
    <zh>……诞生之时将至。现在，花芯仪式。&lt;page&gt;虫。只剩你。无虫来此。&lt;page&gt;仪式需要花芯。带来此处。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="WOOD_WITCH_MEET">
    <en>Shhhh... shell. White mask, red cloak.&lt;page&gt;Bug. A living bug.&lt;hpage&gt;A bug I am, at least in part, but you are something quite different. I apologise if I have roused you from some deep slumber.&lt;page&gt;Slumber. Long sleep. But now is the waking.&lt;page&gt;Growth. Time of birth. The time of birth approaches.&lt;page&gt;Heed, bug. The time of birth approaches.</en>
    <zh>嘘……甲壳。白面甲，红袍子。&lt;page&gt;虫。是活虫。&lt;hpage&gt;我算是半虫，但你倒是截然不同。若吵醒你的长眠，我道歉。&lt;page&gt;长眠。苏醒时分已至。&lt;page&gt;生长。诞生之时。诞生之时将至。&lt;page&gt;听着，诞生之时将至。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="WOOD_WITCH_MANDRAKE_DECLINE">
    <en>Th... the bud. It must be offered. It calls for it... for the rite.</en>
    <zh>花苞……必须献上。它在呼唤……呼唤仪式。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="WOOD_WITCH_REPEAT">
    <en>The time will come... Soon. The time of birth approaches.</en>
    <zh>时刻将至……诞生之时将至。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="SETH_GUARDIAN_MEET">
    <en>Halt, stranger. I am charged forever to guard the sacred shrine beyond.&lt;page&gt;Any who wish to pass must cross their weapon with my own.</en>
    <zh>止步，陌生的虫。我奉命永远守护后方圣所。&lt;page&gt;想要过去，先问过我的兵器。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="SETH_GUARDIAN_TALK1">
    <en>You may remain here and rest, if you choose. I am no enemy of yours. Only if you try to step beyond will I raise my weapon against you.&lt;hpage&gt;Then tell me, warrior, of the shrine you guard. These caves on wood’s edge seem long forgotten.&lt;page&gt;Some things may be hidden, but never forgotten. The shrine remains to remember the wood’s first seed, her that once was and always is.&lt;page&gt;I am the last bound to protect it. Sadly, in that service, many have fallen to my blade.</en>
    <zh>你可以在此处休息，只要不越界，我就不是你的敌人。&lt;hpage&gt;那就说说这处圣所吧。这深林边缘的洞窟似乎早已被遗忘。&lt;page&gt;事物或许会被被隐藏，但不会被遗忘。最初之种记得这处圣所，而她永恒存在。&lt;page&gt;我是最后一位守卫者。很遗憾，至今已有无数试图越界的亡魂。</zh>
  </entry>
</sheet>