<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<sheet name="Under">
  <entry key="ARCHITECT_AFTER_SHRINE">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;Master, I have communed with the shrine above. Your learnings are unique, techniques born of cogwork hearts. Their mastery will require some commitment on my part.&lt;page&gt;Bug-Red, you are the first organic shell to fuse our memories. S-s-s-such behaviour, my line would have believed improbable-impossible. &lt;page&gt;Still, your broad arsenal did suggest strong affinity with the m-m-m-mechanical craft, enough to allow access to our thought-store.&lt;hpage&gt;Yours is an impressive skill, Master. I am grateful for the insight.</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;大师，我已拜访上方圣像。你们的知识独特，源自机枢之心。需要我专注投入才能掌握。&lt;page&gt;红姑娘是首个融合我等记忆的血肉之躯。这种行为，按我族逻辑本应不-不-不可行。&lt;page&gt;不过您精通各式武具，确实与机械造诣契-契-合，因此决定开放思维秘藏。&lt;hpage&gt;你们的技艺令我叹服。对这份知识，我感激不尽。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CONFESSIONAL_START_BROKEN">
    <en>Speak... ... confession...</en>
    <zh>说……忏悔……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="ARCHITECT_WEAVER_SHOOT">
    <en>A fine artefact you carry there, Bug-Red. That broken tool, it is Weaver-make? &lt;hpage&gt;I believe so, Master. A relic of their old workshop, lost in fetid caves beyond this Citadel.&lt;hpage&gt;The parts suggest a weapon of thread, one I would attempt to repair myself, had I endless time.&lt;page&gt;An Architect’s work owes much to the art of the f-f-first children. They set expert standard for the tools and talents of Pharloom eternal.&lt;page&gt;If you desire-demand, I can remake the tool, though my own mind-directives may produce u-u-u-nique result.</en>
    <zh>红姑娘，你身上有件特殊遗物。这残器，是织者造物？&lt;hpage&gt;应该是。织者的旧工坊遗物，在圣堡外的腐臭洞窟里发现的。&lt;hpage&gt;看这构造应该是丝刃兵器。若不是时间有限，我倒想尝试修复。&lt;page&gt;建筑师技艺大多继承自初代织者子嗣。他们为永恒圣堡的器-器-具设下典范。&lt;page&gt;如果您有要求，我可以将它重铸，但成品恐怕会带有我的独-独-独特烙印。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="ARCHITECT_SHOP_DESC_SILKSHOT">
    <en>An intricate implement of Pharloom’s first children. I can restore-repair the w-w-weapon, though it will bear some trace of my identity-idiom.</en>
    <zh>初代子嗣的精巧造物。我可修-修-复此武具，但会留下我的工造印记。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="ARCHITECT_SHOP_TALK_REPEAT">
    <en>Bug-Red. Do you ask-need our service? We shall create, as is our d-d-directive. To serve, for Pharloom eternal.</en>
    <zh>红姑娘。需要服-服-服务？我将创造，如指-指-指令所示。为永恒圣堡。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CONFESSIONAL_START">
    <en>Speak now. Thy confession will be heard.</en>
    <zh>说吧。你的忏悔将被聆听。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="LARGE_COG_WORK_SONG">
    <en>Hrrr. Hrrrrrrr. Them sounds you make. Of holy sort. When me hear such sounds, me remember of home. Me remember of be little.&lt;page&gt;It make it painful hard to work, such remembers. Me must keep working. Please, friend. Do not make them sounds no more.</en>
    <zh>唔。唔唔唔唔。你弄的响动。像圣歌。让咱想起老家。想起小时候。&lt;page&gt;这些回忆让干活揪心。咱得继续干。朋友，求你别弄这些声了。&lt;page&gt;求你了……别再……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="ARCHITECT_WILL_LEAVE">
    <en>My s-s-service to you, Bug-Red... As it concludes, I must speak-confess. Long now I have felt my rotors slow their s-s-spin. My limbs lift weak. An ending is felt, coming, sudden-certain...welcome.&lt;hpage&gt;Whatever fading you feel has not shown in your craft, Master. You have provided tools of immaculate make.&lt;hpage&gt;What will follow if you pass? Would another take your place? &lt;page&gt;One cannot. The skill to construct an Architect... That was taken by t-t-time. I am the last-final. The core remains to sustain the song, but no more Architects to tend-toil or build anew. &lt;page&gt;S-s-strange... ‘For Pharloom eternal,’ states the d-d-directive-cage. But how can eternity sustain without an Architect to serve? This seems e-e-error. An end? An error... welcome?</en>
    <zh>为红姑娘效-效-力的时光……临别前必须坦-坦-白。我的齿轮渐-渐缓，臂膀无力。终结将至，突然但确-确-定……真好。&lt;hpage&gt;即便如此，大师的技艺也并未退步。您造的器具堪称完美。&lt;hpage&gt;您逝去后会怎么样，有后继者接任？&lt;page&gt;没有。锻造建筑师的技艺……早已失-失-失传。我是最后一位。核心尚能使圣歌存续，但再无工匠维缮新建。&lt;page&gt;荒-荒-谬……”为永恒圣堡”的指-指-令仍在。但无工匠何谈永恒？错-错-误？终局？错谬……真好？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="LARGE_COG_WORK_MEET">
    <en>Hrr. Hrrrrr. Who is there? Me can not... can not clear see....&lt;hpage&gt;At ease, large one. I am no danger to you.&lt;page&gt;Hrrrrr? Hrrrr! Me see you now! So clean, so lively... Surely you did come from above! Me time has come at last! Me work is done. You come to bring me up! Up, up! Hrrr!&lt;hpage&gt;You mistake me. I am no resident of the Citadel. I am a stranger here, though no foe to you.&lt;page&gt;Hrrr. Hrrrrrrrrr. S-stranger? Me grave mistaken. Forgive me, thems above, for me unworthy hope! Of course, me work is not done! Harder, harder! Me must work harder!</en>
    <zh>唔。唔唔唔。谁？咱看不清……看不清……&lt;hpage&gt;别慌，大块头。我不是你的敌人。&lt;page&gt;唔唔？唔唔！看清你了！这么干净鲜活……肯定是从上层来的！咱终于等到！咱完工了！你是来接咱上去的！上去！唔唔！&lt;hpage&gt;你误会了，我不是圣堡居民，只是旅者。但也不是你的敌人。&lt;page&gt;唔。唔唔唔唔。旅……旅者？咱大错特错。宽恕咱吧，上边的大人们！咱痴心妄想！咱当然还没完工！加把劲！咱得加把劲！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="ARCHITECT_SHOP_TALK_REPEAT_ACT3">
    <en>Bug-Red. Do you ask-need our services, even n-now? Our duty is l-l-long, but we shall create for you, if you require it...</en>
    <zh>红姑娘。此刻仍需要服-服-服务？职责已尽，但如果您需要，仍可制-制造……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="ARCHITECT_SHOP_DESC_KEY">
    <en>If Bug-Red could prove their aptitude with our implements, and others like, I would offer my key, to grant access to the chapel-store above. </en>
    <zh>如果红姑娘能证-证-明精通我等器械，我将献上钥匙，用以开启上方圣堂库房。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="ARCHITECT_MELODY">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;Master, I seek a melody held by your line, one part of a sequence and key to ascending above the Citadel. Can you teach it to me?&lt;page&gt;Our melody? I r-r-recall! Yes! There was melody, once, but its sound... that I possess no longer...&lt;page&gt;T-t-t-too long I have worked. From my mind-vault, the imprint has f-f-faded. With many things it is like this... remembrance, dimmed...&lt;page&gt;But you m-m-may hear it, still. At the height of our core, there is means-s-s-system, near complete... Constructs old-built to sound our song. They need only be set to functional form. </en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;大师，我想要你这一族保管的旋律，那是登顶圣堡的钥匙。你可愿意传授？&lt;page&gt;我们的旋律？确-确-曾存在！但是声纹……已遗失……&lt;page&gt;长-长-久劳役使我记忆缺损。许多往事……都已模糊……&lt;page&gt;但您仍可-可-可以聆听。核心顶端有一奏鸣构造，几近完成……启动即可重现圣歌。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="ARCHITECT_MELODY_RETURN">
    <en>Are you still to c-c-climb our grand core, Bug-Red? Within you may marvel at the work of Architects, my own, and all those passed b-b-before.&lt;hpage&gt;My path takes me in many directions, Master, but in due course, I will ascend the core and claim the melody atop it.</en>
    <zh>您仍要攀-攀-登伟大核心？路上可见历代建筑师的神工创造，包括我的拙作。&lt;hpage&gt;我有许多地方要去，但若是需要，我会登顶获取旋律。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="LARGE_COG_WORK_CITADEL">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;May I ask what you know of the Citadel above you, sir? You go to much effort to reach it.&lt;page&gt;Hrrrrrrrr! The Citadel! Most miracle of a place, bright and holy! Fresh water for all, much as can drink! Air so clean, can see the great rooves above! &lt;page&gt;When me thinks of Citadel above, me works hardest of all! Hrrrrrrrrr!</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;请问你对头顶的圣堡了解多少？为了上去这么煞费苦心。&lt;page&gt;唔唔唔唔！圣堡！神迹之地！亮堂圣洁！清水管够！空气清新能望见穹顶！&lt;page&gt;想着圣堡，咱就干得最卖力！唔唔唔唔！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CONFESSIONAL_END">
    <en>You have confessed a sin most grave and must by works cleanse yourself.&lt;page&gt;Return to your task and work off-cycle, neither eating nor supping until new-cycle begins.&lt;page&gt;By the grace of Pharloom eternal, may you never tire. Toil, and be forgiven.</en>
    <zh>你已供认重罪，须以苦役净化。&lt;page&gt;返回岗位持续劳作，禁食禁饮直至新周期始。&lt;page&gt;承永恒纺络之恩，愿你永不疲惫。劳作，方得救赎。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="LARGE_COG_WORK_TOGETHER">
    <en>Hrr. Hrrrrr! Good, me friend, good! When us works together, is more holy! Is more work done!&lt;page&gt;Together, lets us work raw hard ‘til thems above see how worthy us is!</en>
    <zh>唔。唔唔唔！好，朋友，好！咱一起干，更虔诚！活干得更快！&lt;page&gt;来！咱们一起拼命干，让上边看看咱多卖力！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="ARCHITECT_MELODY_GAINED">
    <en>&lt;page&gt;What’s this, Bug-Red? Even down here, I d-d-did detect its working... Have you climbed our c-c-core, and woken the voices of my l-l-line?&lt;hpage&gt;I have maker. Clearly it was a climb never intended for regular bugs, and fair fortune that the skills gifted within your lands allowed my ascent.&lt;hpage&gt;The melody, and the voices... both are fine things heard and witnessed. Even in this fading moment, their artistry shines through.&lt;page&gt;Impressive-industrious... eternal... You have seen a glimpse, Bug-Red, of us-s-s, how once we were. The minds of Architects inspired. What majesty we did create...</en>
    <zh>&lt;page&gt;怎么回事，红姑娘？即便身处此地，我也感-感-感知到它的运转……莫非你已攀上我们的核-核-核心，唤醒了我族先辈的歌声？  &lt;hpage&gt;正是如此，大师。这段攀登本非寻常虫类所能企及，所幸这片土地赋予的技艺助我登上了顶端。  &lt;hpage&gt;那旋律与歌声……皆是值得聆听见证的瑰宝。即便在此衰微之际，其中匠心仍熠熠生辉。  &lt;page&gt;勤勉卓绝……永垂不朽……红姑娘，你已见证我族-族-族昔日的荣光。建筑师们迸发的智慧，我们曾创造的伟业何等壮丽……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="ARCHITECT_MEET_ACT3">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;Master, you seem the lone maker left in this ruined Citadel. Are you my enemy? The other constructs of this place did object aggressively to my presence. &lt;page&gt;Bug-Red? I am a m-m-maker. Yes. Enemy. No. I am an Architect. Only an Architect. To build-automate, it is our nature-directive-c-c-c-cage.&lt;page&gt;Why are you here, Bug-Red? The time is late. Do you seek-need service of an Architect? You are weave-type, yes, a first child. Rare-e-e-extinct? Or not it does so seem.&lt;hpage&gt;You see it true, Master. I bear the lineage of Weaver, along with other strands, equally strange.&lt;page&gt;Then on your r-r-request, Bug-Red, as directive demands, for Pharloom’s first children, a-a-a-and our kingdom-eternal, I shall c-c-craft.</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;阁下，你似乎是圣堡最后的工匠，但是要与我为敌么？这里的构造体对我很有敌意。&lt;page&gt;红衣虫？我是制-制-造者。敌人。不是。建筑师。只是建筑师。建造-自动化，并非选择。是本性-指-指-指令牢笼。&lt;page&gt;您为何在此，是寻-寻求建筑师协助？您有织者血脉，是，初代子嗣。稀-稀-稀有种？但又似乎不是。&lt;hpage&gt;你眼光很独到，我确实有织者血脉，但只有一半。&lt;page&gt;那依红姑娘要-要-要求，遵循指令，为纺络初代子嗣，为永恒圣堡，我将效劳。为您制-制-造。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="ARCHITECT_MEET">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;Master, you seem the lone maker left in this Citadel. Are you my enemy? The other constructs of this place object aggressively to my presence. &lt;page&gt;Bug-Red? I am a m-m-maker. Yes. Enemy. No. I am an Architect. Only an Architect. To build-automate is not choice. It is our nature-directive-c-c-c-cage. &lt;page&gt;You are weave-type, yes, a first child. Rare-e-e-extinct? Or not it does so seem.&lt;hpage&gt;You see it true, Master. I bear the lineage of Weavers, along with other strands, equally strange.&lt;page&gt;Then on your r-r-request, Bug-Red, as directive demands, for Pharloom’s first children, a-a-a-and our kingdom-eternal, I shall serve. I shall c-c-craft.</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;阁下，你似乎是圣堡最后的工匠，但是要与我为敌么？这里的构造体对我很有敌意。&lt;page&gt;红衣虫？我是制-制-造者。敌人。不是。建筑师。只是建筑师。建造-自动化，并非选择。是本性-指-指-指令牢笼。&lt;page&gt;您有织者血脉，是，初代子嗣。稀-稀-稀有种？但又似乎不是。&lt;hpage&gt;你眼光很独到，我确实有织者血脉，但只有一半。&lt;page&gt;那依红姑娘要-要-要求，遵循指令，为纺络初代子嗣，为永恒圣堡，我将效劳。为您制-制-造。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="ARCHITECT_SHOP_TITLE">
    <en>Twelfth Architect</en>
    <zh>建筑师-13</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="LARGE_COG_WORK_WORK">
    <en>Hrrrrrrr. The harder me work, the sooner it come. Thems above, them watch us, always. Work hard, work hard, and us will go up. Hrrrr.&lt;hpage&gt;Sir, I fear you are long forgotten by your masters. Should you not rest? The burden this toil is placing on your shell is plain to see.&lt;page&gt;Hrrrrr? Hrrrrrr. You speaks strange. Me can not rest. Us works, and Citadel breathes, and thems above do sing, and all is right.&lt;page&gt;And when us works enough, thems see it... Hrrr... thems see it, and us gets us holy reward...</en>
    <zh>唔唔唔。越使劲干，就越早离开。上边的大人们看着咱呢。使劲干，使劲干，就能上去。唔唔。&lt;hpage&gt;先生，恐怕你早被主人遗忘了。为何不休息？这苦役正在摧残你的甲壳。&lt;page&gt;唔唔？唔唔唔。你说怪话。咱不能歇。咱干活，圣堡呼吸，上边唱歌，这才对劲。&lt;page&gt;等咱干够活，大人们会看见……唔唔……会看见，就给咱圣赐……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="ARCHITECT_SHOP_DESC_TOOL_KIT">
    <en>Tools of my craft. They could be used to improve your own. Make harder, sharper.</en>
    <zh>我的工具。可以用于改进您自己的。更硬，更利。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="ARCHITECT_SHOP_DESC_SCUTTLEBRACE">
    <en>A flexible shell-prosthetic. It would enhance a weave-type’s flexibility, allowing evasive options. </en>
    <zh>柔性甲壳义肢。能提升织者机动性，便于闪避。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CONFESSIONAL_END_BROKEN">
    <en>You... ... sin... ... cleanse....&lt;page&gt;Return... ... work... ... begins....&lt;page&gt;... Pharloom... ... never... ... forgiven.</en>
    <zh>你……罪……净化....&lt;page&gt;返回……劳作……周期始....&lt;page&gt;...纺络……永不……救赎。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="ARCHITECT_SHOP_DESC_COGWORK_SAW">
    <en>You have affinity for such radial blades? I can b-b-build upon the idea-knowledge. Make them retract. Make them force-store.</en>
    <zh>您偏爱这类机轮刃？我可基-基-据此改良。加回收装置。强化储能。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="ARCHITECT_SHOP_DESC_KEY_REQUIRE">
    <en>Acquire {0} more tools to prove aptitude.</en>
    <zh>再收集{0}件工具以证明资质。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="LARGE_COG_WORK_REPEAT">
    <en>Hrrrrrr. Me can not say much more, friend. Thems is watching. Us must keep working. </en>
    <zh>唔唔唔唔。咱不能多说了，朋友。上边看着呢。咱得接着干。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="AUTO_SHRINE_DOOR_INSPECT">
    <en>A locked gate bearing the symbol of an Architect.</en>
    <zh>一扇锁住的门，刻有建筑师徽记。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="ARCHITECT_SHOP_DESC_SHARDPOUCH">
    <en>Raw materials, for creation. Carry them with you always, that y-y-you may be prepared.</en>
    <zh>原材料，随身携带。有-有备无患。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="ARCHITECT_SHOP_DESC_KEY_REQUIRE_SINGLE">
    <en>Acquire 1 more tool to prove aptitude.</en>
    <zh>再收集1件工具以证明资质。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="ARCHITECT_COG_HEART">
    <en>Those pieces of a h-h-heart-core you carry upon you, how did you acquire-recover an artefact so rare?&lt;hpage&gt;They were scattered about the Citadel, each seemingly laid with purpose. Someone wished the thing dismantled, but showed respect enough to see it stored safe.&lt;page&gt;That heart is an inspired form, conceived by the first of my line for a knight of cog and blade.&lt;page&gt;In it, I see my predecessor’s talent, immense, now lost-forgotten. I could never create-copy a work s-s-so fine.&lt;hpage&gt;And the knight that once bore the heart? Tell me of them.&lt;page&gt;A gleaming order, cogwork sentinels, so impressive-majestic in function they were charged-b-b-bound to the highest holy duty.&lt;page&gt;Long before the c-c-creation of the core, the sentinels ventured, even beyond these walls, to see all bugs brought-forced safe to serve the Citadel.&lt;page&gt;If the h-h-h-heart were restored within the sentinel’s shell, would it give thanks for the awakening? Or would it grieve those lands now l-l-lost?&lt;hpage&gt;In time, maker, I may find out...</en>
    <zh>您携带的心-心-脏残片，您是怎么找到如此珍贵造物的？&lt;hpage&gt;它们散落在圣堡各处，似乎是被刻意安置。虽然被拆解，却有妥善保管。&lt;page&gt;这心脏构造精妙，出自我的先辈之手，为机枢骑士所铸造。&lt;page&gt;我能在其中看到先辈才华，如今却已失-失-传。我无法复刻这份神工。&lt;hpage&gt;那曾经承载这颗心的骑士？我想了解详情。&lt;page&gt;光辉教团，机枢戍卫。他们曾经威仪赫赫，掌管圣职。&lt;page&gt;远在核心铸-铸-造之前，戍卫就远征墙外，强掳众虫效忠圣堡。&lt;page&gt;如果将此心-心-脏重新装入戍卫甲中，它会为苏醒而感激？还是为圣堡衰颓哀伤？&lt;hpage&gt;假以时日，大师，或许我能知晓……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="ARCHITECT_SHOP_DESC_BROLLYSPIKE">
    <en>This band of metal teeth, sharp and light-fine. It could be woven within your red outer layer? A hidden weapon.</en>
    <zh>金属齿环，轻便锐利。可编入您的红色披风？作为暗器。</zh>
  </entry>
</sheet>