<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<sheet name="Weave">
  <entry key="CREST_UPGRADE_MEET_PT2">
    <en>&lt;page&gt;No. Not their enemy, and their prisoner not through malice. I am Eva, a thing... difficult to describe, a child of Weavers, yet not quite their kin...&lt;hpage&gt;How strange. That description could fit me as well as yourself. &lt;page&gt;Child of Weavers?... And not? I can detect your Weaver strain, yet you are different from them, and from me, a shifting, blended thing? What are you creature?&lt;page&gt;Step closer, lady, that my senses would better understand your nature.</en>
    <zh>&lt;page&gt;不是，也并非因为罪行囚禁。我叫伊娃，是……有点复杂，是织者后裔但又不完全是……&lt;hpage&gt;真奇妙。这番描述同样适用于我。&lt;page&gt;你也是织者后裔？……但又不是？我能感知你的织者血统，但你既不同于他们，也不同于我，一个流动的混合体？你究竟是什么？&lt;page&gt;请靠近些，女士，方便我感知你的本质。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CREST_UPGRADE_PRE_REPEAT_ADDITIONAL">
    <en>Lady, still my senses resound. You seem so far beyond the bounds of a bug.&lt;page&gt;Permit me to gaze again upon your nature, that I may offer clarity.</en>
    <zh>女士，我的感知再度震颤。您已远远超过凡虫界限。&lt;page&gt;请允许我再次深入感知，才好仔细说明</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CREST_UPGRADE_MEET_ACT3">
    <en>Lady? So you live, still. This is good... I had felt the conflict commence, pale hearts ablaze, and the sudden well of darkness after.&lt;hpage&gt;I am sorry, Eva. I had hoped to slay the monarch, and was near achieving that goal, but the situation has become... complicated. Now, all of Pharloom threatens to fall.&lt;page&gt;But I can sense it in you, lady. You have not yielded to despair, so some hope must still remain?&lt;hpage&gt;...Slim hope, I suspect. But true, there may yet be a way through this disaster. I shall pursue that goal with whatever strength remains.&lt;page&gt;Then allow me to continue to aid you as I can... Mine might be a small contribution, but I shall provide it eagerly.</en>
    <zh>女士？你还活着，真是太好了……我早已感受到冲突的爆发，苍白之心熊熊燃烧，而后是突如其来的黑暗深渊。&lt;hpage&gt;抱歉，伊娃。我本希望斩杀君主，几乎就要达成目标，但情况变得……复杂了。如今整个纺络都濒临倾覆。&lt;page&gt;但我能从你身上感受到，女士。你仍未屈服于绝望，是否意味着尚存一线希望？&lt;hpage&gt;……希望渺茫。但确实，或许仍有办法化解这场灾难。我将用残存之力追寻这个目标。&lt;page&gt;那么请允许我继续尽力协助你……虽只是微薄之力，但我必倾心奉献。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CREST_UPGRADE_POST_ADDITIONAL_AVAILABLE">
    <en>Incredible... Your nature is so unlike a mortal bug’s. Yours is malleable, transitory. It is a marvelous thing, worth my long life to behold.&lt;page&gt;With what power I possess, I may still be able to aid you further. </en>
    <zh>不可思议……你的本质异于凡虫。流动，嬗变，真是奇妙，是我前所未见的存在。&lt;page&gt;以我的力量，或许可以助你更上一层。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CREST_UPGRADE_TALK_SNARE">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;Eva, I am seeking a tool, told to be somewhere in this structure. It is a snare device of Weaver make. Do you know of it?&lt;page&gt;I may, lady. Search over from here, on side where the moss meets the nest. There, my mothers built their tools, all traps and bindings. Small things, but tests for larger forms.&lt;page&gt;I still remember their thoughts as they worked, their desperation, and their hunger. Another hopeless attempt to wrest their freedom. All ended in failure, of course.</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;伊娃，我在寻找织者制造的陷阱装置。你知道在哪么？&lt;page&gt;有点印象。您可以去青苔与巢穴交界处搜寻，母亲们曾在那制造工具。虽是些小玩意，却是为了更大的图谋。&lt;page&gt;我还记得她们制作时的思绪，那份绝望与饥渴，又一次争夺自由的徒劳尝试。当然，终归失败。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CARETAKER_SNARE_READY">
    <en>Ain’t you come a long way, bellringer! Granting wishes, saving bugs, even rousing my sullen family to act!&lt;page&gt;The snare is set above, our power bound along its thread. To your sight it may seem a crude thing, but there’s fair strength to it... enough to quell a god.&lt;hpage&gt;You and your family have done me well, sir. I shall prove your faith in the meeting ahead.&lt;page&gt;Aye. Bring your best, bellringer. Call forth our great pale god. Cut her weak, then drive the beast down atop the snare.&lt;page&gt;Contact made will stir the snare alight, but only your needle’s song will awaken the spell in full. When that moment arrives, you’ll see it clear.</en>
    <zh>敲钟者，你这一路可够折腾！祈愿、救虫，连我那些沉默的同族都让你说动了！&lt;page&gt;陷阱已在上方布好，我们的力量都缠在丝线上。看着简陋，但威力足够……连神都能制住。&lt;hpage&gt;你们一族对我多次相助，我必将不负所托。&lt;page&gt;那就好，敲钟者，拿出真本事。把那苍白之神引出来，先削弱她，再逼到陷阱上方。&lt;page&gt;触碰陷阱就会激活丝线，但只有你的织针之乐能彻底唤醒术式。时机一到，你自然明白。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CREST_UPGRADE_PRE_RETURNED">
    <en>&lt;page&gt;Lady, please. Permit me to look upon your nature, that I may offer clarity...</en>
    <zh>&lt;page&gt;女士，请允许我深入感知，才好仔细说明……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CREST_UPGRADE_POST">
    <en>Incredible... Your nature is so unlike a mortal bug’s. Yours is malleable, transitory. It is a marvelous thing, worth my long life to behold.&lt;page&gt;If in your travels you are able to further evolve, return to me. With what power I possess, I may be able to aid you further.&lt;hpage&gt;Thank you, Eva. If my nature expands as you say, I shall return. </en>
    <zh>不可思议……你的本质异于凡虫。流动，嬗变，真是奇妙，是我前所未见的存在。&lt;page&gt;如果旅途中你再度进化，请回来找我。以我的力量，或许可以助你更上一层。&lt;hpage&gt;多谢，伊娃。若我本质确实再度进化，我会回来找你。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CARETAKER_SNARE_TALK1">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;I have known your kind before, sir. Yours is a tribe that works and trades in power, and I am about to extinguish its prime source.&lt;hpage&gt;Once this is done, will you truly delight in a land so bereft?&lt;page&gt;Aye, well... My family’s marks are all over that trap. And we’ve spent a hard age avoiding the gaze of our god.&lt;page&gt;If we earned it now, after such open opposition... that’s a bleak conclusion none of us’d care for.&lt;page&gt;Now! My job’s done. S’time your grand business began! We’ll be wishin’ victory to you, bellringer, for all our sakes!</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;我曾见过你的同族。你们一族专门兜售力量，而我正要掐灭这力量的源头。&lt;hpage&gt;事成之后，这力量真空的世界真能让你们感到高兴？&lt;page&gt;哈……陷阱上现在全是家族徽记，我们也躲那苍白之神半辈子了。&lt;page&gt;要是现在因为公然反抗栽了……这种憋屈结局谁受得了？&lt;page&gt;好了！我活儿干完了。该你大显身手了！敲钟者，你可一定要赢啊，都指望着你呢！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CREST_UPGRADE_PRE">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;You see one’s nature, Eva? It is a skill far beyond bugs.&lt;page&gt;One not without cost. My sight perceives a bug only through the imprint upon their soul. &lt;hpage&gt;You speak of their crest? That signifier of a bug’s essence and their invisible yoke born through a lifetime.&lt;page&gt;Crest? Yes, the old Weaver term. A simple word to attempt description of something so profound.&lt;page&gt;But wait. Your own nature... Is it?...&lt;page&gt;Lady, permit me to look deeper still, that I may offer clarity...</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;伊娃，你能洞见本质？这等技艺远超虫类。&lt;page&gt;自然是有代价的。我需透过灵魂印记窥视生灵。&lt;hpage&gt;你是指纹章？那象征虫民全部存在与无形枷锁的标记？&lt;page&gt;纹章？对，织者用的古称，试图以简单词汇描述深邃之物。&lt;page&gt;等等，你的本质……莫非……&lt;page&gt;女士，请允许我深入感知，才好仔细说明……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CREST_UPGRADE_PROMPT">
    <en>Allow Insight?</en>
    <zh>允许洞察？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CREST_UPGRADE_REPEAT_ACT3">
    <en>Lady, Pharloom’s time grows short. If you are able to further expand your nature, I urge you return to me.&lt;page&gt;Any power I possess, I shall grant it for your aid.&lt;hpage&gt;My thanks, Eva. If my nature expands as you say, I shall return. </en>
    <zh>女士，纺络时日无多。若你能进一步突破自身极限，请务必回到我身边。&lt;page&gt;我拥有的任何力量，都将为你所用。&lt;hpage&gt;感激不尽，伊娃。若真如你所言突破极限，我定会回来。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CREST_UPGRADE_ACCEPT_DIALOGUE">
    <en>Bind Eva?</en>
    <zh>与伊娃联结？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CREST_UPGRADE_MEET_CURSED">
    <en>Stay back, twisted leech! Even lodged within another’s shell, your ravenous nature shines clear.&lt;page&gt;You shall not defoul this chamber, nor claim my soul. Begone!</en>
    <zh>退后，扭曲的寄生物！即便寄居他者躯壳也藏不住贪婪本性。&lt;page&gt;休想玷污此地，更别妄图吞噬我的灵魂。滚开！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CREST_UPGRADE_FIRST_ALL">
    <en>Lady... Incredible... Your nature is so unlike a mortal bugs. Yours is malleable, transitory. It is a marvelous thing. Worth my long life to behold.&lt;page&gt;Unbound one, though we know each other little, permit me to ask a selfish request.&lt;hpage&gt;Your talent has provided a great benefit, Eva. What is it you desire of me?&lt;page&gt;Only to have my own soul, my own memories, bound within your shell... As you have done with those others throughout these lands.&lt;page&gt;I would not define as a crest within you, but my small strength may still grant a final boon.&lt;hpage&gt;You ask to be subsumed? Know your mind would cease to be, in any independent sense.&lt;page&gt;To be united with one unbound... This is the kind of escape I once prayed for, though the weight of ages had almost made me forget.&lt;page&gt;Lady, would you grant me this request?</en>
    <zh>女士……不可思议……你的本质异于凡虫。流动，嬗变，真是奇妙，是我前所未见的存在。&lt;page&gt;无羁者啊，虽然相交尚浅，但我仍想提出一个自私请求。&lt;hpage&gt;你帮了我很多，伊娃。你想要什么？&lt;page&gt;请您将我的灵魂与记忆缚于您的壳中，就像您其他生物所做的那样。&lt;page&gt;虽然称不上是纹章，但或许能为您献上最后一份微薄馈赠。&lt;hpage&gt;你想被我吞噬？你要知道，那意味着独立意识将不复存在。&lt;page&gt;我明白，但自愿如此。能与无羁者合而为一……是我昔日渴求的解脱，尽管岁月让我几乎遗忘。&lt;page&gt;亲爱的女士，您愿意成全我吗？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CREST_UPGRADE_ALL">
    <en>Lady, you are a multitude within a single shell. A being truly unbound. To aid your growth has proved a grand task, even for one as limited as me.&lt;page&gt;As my last act, permit me to ask a final, selfish request.&lt;hpage&gt;Your talents have provided great benefit, Eva. What is it you desire of me?&lt;page&gt;Only to have my own soul, my own memories, bound within your shell... As you have done with those others throughout these lands.&lt;page&gt;I would not define as a crest within you, but my small strength may still grant a final boon.&lt;hpage&gt;You ask to be subsumed? Know your mind would cease to be, in any independent sense.&lt;page&gt;I know. And still I seek it, gladly. To be united with one unbound... This is the kind of escape I once prayed for, though the weight of ages had almost made me forget.&lt;page&gt;Dear Lady, would you grant me this request?</en>
    <zh>女士，您这具躯壳中存在万千可能，是真正无拘无束的存在。能助您成长，是我的荣幸。&lt;page&gt;最后，请允许我提出自私的请求。&lt;hpage&gt;你帮了我很多，伊娃。你想要什么？&lt;page&gt;请您将我的灵魂与记忆缚于您的壳中，就像您其他生物所做的那样。&lt;page&gt;虽然称不上是纹章，但或许能为您献上最后一份微薄馈赠。&lt;hpage&gt;你想被我吞噬？你要知道，那意味着独立意识将不复存在。&lt;page&gt;我明白，但自愿如此。能与无羁者合而为一……是我昔日渴求的解脱，尽管岁月让我几乎遗忘。&lt;page&gt;亲爱的女士，您愿意成全我吗？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CREST_UPGRADE_MEET">
    <en>Who’s there? Has someone come to free me? Or are you here to bring my end? &lt;hpage&gt;I am Hornet, prisoner, only a traveller and not here to slay you.&lt;hpage&gt;What cause sees you caged in these ruins of Weavers past? Were you their enemy?</en>
    <zh>谁在那儿？是来解救我的？还是来取我性命的？&lt;hpage&gt;我名为大黄蜂，只是一名旅者，无意取你性命。&lt;hpage&gt;你为何被囚于织者遗迹？你曾是他们的敌人？</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CREST_UPGRADE_PRE_REPEAT">
    <en>Lady, my senses resound. You have grown further beyond the bounds of a bug.&lt;page&gt;Permit me to gaze again upon your nature, that I may offer clarity.</en>
    <zh>女士，我的感知在震颤。你已远超凡虫界限。&lt;page&gt;请允许我再次深入感知，才好仔细说明……</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CREST_UPGRADE_TALK_PURPOSE">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;How did you come to be sealed here, Eva? &lt;page&gt;Lady, you mistake. What seems a cage is as much my shell as the form inside.&lt;page&gt;I was born within this space. To leave would be my death, an uninspired end, though one I’ve sometimes wished would come.&lt;page&gt;I am unique, you see. My mothers shared the curse of their tribe, to conceive a child is a painful, near impossible task. &lt;hpage&gt;I know the curse well, Eva, for I am also its victim, and spawn of one who managed to overcome its limits. &lt;hpage&gt;Are you too an attempt to defy that cruel constraint?&lt;page&gt;A flawed attempt. A life spun from rune and shell, sustained only by its cage. My thoughts may mimic a Weavers, but my senses are my own.&lt;page&gt;Over time, that difference brought only distance between us.</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;伊娃，你为何会被困在这里？&lt;page&gt;女士误会了。这囚笼也是我的躯壳，与其中的形体并无差异。&lt;page&gt;我诞生于这里，离开意味着消亡，虽然有时也渴求这平淡结局。&lt;page&gt;我很特殊，母亲们承受着族群诅咒，生育子嗣近乎不可能。&lt;hpage&gt;我很了解这诅咒，伊娃。因为我也是受害者，更是突破禁忌的产物。&lt;hpage&gt;想必你也是对抗这残酷枷锁的尝试？&lt;page&gt;是失败的尝试。符文与甲壳铸就的生命，只能靠囚笼维系。我虽能模仿织者，但终究不是织者。&lt;page&gt;久而久之，这份差异使我们渐行渐远。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CREST_UPGRADE_ACCEPT">
    <en>By your grace, I am at last broken from my fate.&lt;hpage&gt;Gladly I accept your union, Eva. No longer shall you suffer eternity alone.</en>
    <zh>蒙您恩典，我终于能挣脱宿命。&lt;hpage&gt;我欣然接受与你的联结，伊娃。你不必再承受永恒的孤寂。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CREST_UPGRADE_MEET_OVERBLUE">
    <en>Come no closer! I sense the forbidden blood coursing through you, that which grows and reshapes the world in its own vulgar image.&lt;page&gt;Whether it was imbibed willingly or not, none shall be allowed into this chamber while so afflicted. Begone!</en>
    <zh>站住！我能感知到你体内流淌的禁忌之血，那以粗鄙之形生长并重塑世界的秽物。&lt;page&gt;无论你是否自愿沾染此血，凡受其侵蚀者皆不得踏入这里。速速离开！</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CREST_UPGRADE_REPEAT">
    <en>Lady, if in your travels you are able to further expand your nature, return to me. With what power I possess, I may be able to aid you further.&lt;hpage&gt;If my nature expands as you say, Eva, I shall return. </en>
    <zh>女士，如果你的本质再度进化，请回来找我。以我的力量，或许能助你更上一层。&lt;hpage&gt;若我本质确实再度进化，我会回来找你。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CREST_UPGRADE_REOFFER">
    <en>Lady, would you think again upon my last request? To be bound amidst your shimmering soul?&lt;page&gt;I understand it is a selfish thing to ask, and I will hold no ill will if you reject.</en>
    <zh>女士，可愿重新考虑我的请求？让我融入你璀璨魂灵？&lt;page&gt;我明白这是个自私的请求，若您拒绝我也绝无怨言。</zh>
  </entry>
  <entry key="CREST_UPGRADE_DECLINE">
    <en>&lt;hpage&gt;I am sorry, Eva. I cannot grant you this. At least, not yet.&lt;hpage&gt;Yours is a mind strong and strange. That union could prove dangerous to my identity.&lt;page&gt;I understand, Lady. I will be here, if ever you reconsider.</en>
    <zh>&lt;hpage&gt;抱歉，伊娃。我不能答应你，至少现在不行。&lt;hpage&gt;你的心智强大而奇异，联结恐怕会危及我的存在。&lt;page&gt;我明白，女士。希望您能改变心意，我会永远在此等候。</zh>
  </entry>
</sheet>